// src/data/questions.js

export const quizData = [
    {
        set: 1,
        questions:[
  {
    "question": "A covert or overt trial of an aviation security measure which simulates an attempt to commit an unlawful act.",
    "options": [
      "a. Security survey",
      "b. Security investigation",
      "c. Security exercise",
      "d. Security Test"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Security Test"
  },
  {
    "question": "Safeguarding civil aviation against acts of unlawful interference. This objective is achieved by a ________ of measures and human and material resources.",
    "options": [
      "a. co-ordination",
      "b. combination",
      "c. compliance",
      "d. co-operation"
    ],
    "answer": "b. combination"
  },
  {
    "question": "Passengers departing from an airport on the same flight as that on which they arrived.",
    "options": [
      "a. Interline Passenger",
      "b. On-board Passenger",
      "c. Transit Passenger",
      "d. Deportee"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Transit Passenger"
  },
  {
    "question": "The first recorded aircraft hijack in world took place on:",
    "options": [
      "a. 21.Feb.31",
      "b. 12.Feb.31",
      "c. 02.Feb.31",
      "d. 13.Feb.32"
    ],
    "answer": "a. 21.Feb.31"
  },
  {
    "question": "Abbreviation of aircraft operator company materials, shipped within the company's network of stations",
    "options": [
      "a. Co-mail",
      "b. Courier service",
      "c. Co-mat",
      "d. Catering stores"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Co-mat"
  },
  {
    "question": "A formal evaluation and confirmation by or on behalf of the appropriate authority for aviation security that a person possesses the necessary competencies to perform assigned functions to an acceptable level as defined by the appropriate authority",
    "options": [
      "a. Facilitation",
      "b. Certification",
      "c. Permit",
      "d. Security Audit"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Certification"
  },
  {
    "question": "The airport permit system is a set of rules which controls the access of people and vehicles to ___ areas",
    "options": [
      "a. Airside",
      "b. Unrestricted",
      "c. SHA",
      "d. Restricted"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Restricted"
  },
  {
    "question": "'Examine a system or procedure' is the meaning of which radio telephony word",
    "options": [
      "a. MONITOR",
      "b. CHECK",
      "c. CLEARED",
      "d. CORRECT"
    ],
    "answer": "b. CHECK"
  },
  {
    "question": "'Pass me the following information…' is the meaning of which radio telephony word",
    "options": [
      "a. REQUEST",
      "b. SAY AGAIN",
      "c. REPORT",
      "d. READ BACK"
    ],
    "answer": "c. REPORT"
  },
  {
    "question": "An in-depth compliance examination of all aspects of the implementation of the national civil aviation security programme",
    "options": [
      "a. NCASP",
      "b. Security Audit",
      "c. Security programme",
      "d. Security Survey"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Security Audit"
  },
  {
    "question": "A general description applied to all hand held firearms",
    "options": [
      "a. Hijacking firearms",
      "b. Security firearms",
      "c. Handy firearms",
      "d. Small arms"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Small arms"
  },
  {
    "question": "Baggage that arrives at an airport and is not picked up or claimed by a passenger",
    "options": [
      "a. Unaccompanied baggage",
      "b. Unclaimed baggage",
      "c. Unidentified baggage",
      "d. Transfer baggage"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Unclaimed baggage"
  },
  {
    "question": "Full form of 'ANFO'",
    "options": [
      "a. Aluminum Nitro Fuel Oil",
      "b. Aluminum Nitrate Fuel Oxidant",
      "c. Ammonium Nitrate Fuel Oil",
      "d. Ammonium Nitrate Fuel Oxygen"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Ammonium Nitrate Fuel Oil"
  },
  {
    "question": "Full form of 'LEG's'",
    "options": [
      "a. Low Explosive Gels",
      "b. Low Effective Gels",
      "c. Liquid Explosives and Gels",
      "d. Limited Explosives and Gels"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Liquid Explosives and Gels"
  },
  {
    "question": "Full form of 'VA'",
    "options": [
      "a. Vulnerable Area",
      "b. Vehicle Assembly",
      "c. Vehicle Approach",
      "d. Vital Area"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Vital Area"
  },
  {
    "question": "Convene the Aerodrome Committee meetings is the responsibility of",
    "options": [
      "a. ASG/APSU",
      "b. Airport Operator",
      "c. Aircraft Operator",
      "d. MHA"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Aircraft Operator"
  },
  {
    "question": "Guarding of access control points to prevent unauthorized entry' is the responsibility of which unit of ASG",
    "options": [
      "a. Protection Unit",
      "b. Anti-hijacking Unit",
      "c. Support Unit",
      "d. Intelligence and Surveillance Unit"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Anti-hijacking Unit"
  },
  {
    "question": "Weapons that achieve their intended effects by infecting people with deliberate release of dangerous bacteria or viruses are",
    "options": [
      "a. Chemical Weapons",
      "b. Nuclear Weapons",
      "c. Biological Weapons",
      "d. Radiological Weapon"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Biological Weapons"
  },
  {
    "question": "1st Hijacking in India is done by which terrorist group",
    "options": [
      "a. LTTE",
      "b. JKLF",
      "c. Al-Qaeda",
      "d. Libyan agents"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Al-Qaeda"
  },
  {
    "question": "The 'Schiphol Incident' took place on",
    "options": [
      "a. 23rd Dec,2009",
      "b. 25th Dec, 2009",
      "c. 22nd Dec,2001",
      "d. 28th Nov, 2002"
    ],
    "answer": "b. 25th Dec, 2009"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which airlines was trageted for Ground to Air attack by missiles",
    "options": [
      "a. Air Lanka",
      "b. Arkia",
      "c. Air India",
      "d. North West"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Arkia"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which year maximum number of hijackings were recorded",
    "options": [
      "a. 1971",
      "b. 1985",
      "c. 1978",
      "d. 1969"
    ],
    "answer": "d. 1969"
  },
  {
    "question": "Bomb Threat Contingency Plan was implemented after which incident",
    "options": [
      "a. Kanishka Tragedy",
      "b. US Attack",
      "c. Chennai Airport Explosion",
      "d. Colombo Airport Attack"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Chennai Airport Explosion"
  },
  {
    "question": "Restrictions on carriage of morethan 100ml of liquid in cabin baggage was started after",
    "options": [
      "a. Moscow Airport attack",
      "b. Attempt attack at Heathrow Airport",
      "c. US Attack",
      "d. IC-814 hijack"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Attempt attack at Heathrow Airport"
  },
  {
    "question": "Random Screening at the entry gate of the terminal building started after which incident",
    "options": [
      "a. Moscow Airport attack",
      "b. US Attack",
      "c. Heathrow Airport Attack",
      "d. Colombo Airport Attack"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Moscow Airport attack"
  },
  {
    "question": "ACI' was founded in which year",
    "options": [
      "a. 1945",
      "b. 1991",
      "c. 1955",
      "d. 1987"
    ],
    "answer": "b. 1991"
  },
  {
    "question": "When moving at airport which safety rule to be followed",
    "options": [
      "a. Must not use vehicle hazard light",
      "b. Must not observe airport speed limits and comply with movement rules",
      "c. Must disobey ground control(or ATC) movement instructions during emergency",
      "d. Must not park any vehicle in a dangerous location"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Must not park any vehicle in a dangerous location"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pyro technic materials are often known as",
    "options": [
      "a. High Explosives",
      "b. Explosive Device",
      "c. Low Explosive",
      "d. Weapon"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Low Explosive"
  },
  {
    "question": "Baggage involuntarily, or inadvertently, separated from passengers or crew",
    "options": [
      "a. Interline baggage",
      "b. Transfer baggage",
      "c. Transit baggage",
      "d. Mishandled baggage"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Mishandled baggage"
  },
  {
    "question": "Perimeter guarding is the responsibility of:",
    "options": [
      "a. Airport Operator",
      "b. ASG",
      "c. Airline",
      "d. QRT"
    ],
    "answer": "b. ASG"
  },
  {
    "question": "Co-ordination in the event of any contingency at the airport is the responsibility of:",
    "options": [
      "a. Airline Operator",
      "b. Senior person from ASG",
      "c. Airport Operator",
      "d. Customs"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Airport Operator"
  },
  {
    "question": "The authority designated by a State within its administration to be responsible for the development, implementation and maintenance of the National Civil Aviation Security Program (NCASP)",
    "options": [
      "a. Appropriate authority for aviation security",
      "b. Civil Aviation",
      "c. General Aviation",
      "d. Corporate Aviation"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Appropriate authority for aviation security"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Anti Hijacking Act 1982 (amendment made in the year ___ )",
    "options": [
      "a. 1984",
      "b. 1994",
      "c. 1995",
      "d. 1985"
    ],
    "answer": "c. 1995"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pier is a corridor at, above or below ground level to _____ aircraft stands to a passenger building.",
    "options": [
      "a. Support",
      "b. Separate",
      "c. Connect",
      "d. Adjust"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Connect"
  },
  {
    "question": "Prohibition of intoxicated person boarding the aircraft",
    "options": [
      "a. Aircraft Rule 8A",
      "b. Aircraft Rule 13",
      "c. Aircraft Rule 19",
      "d. Aircraft Rule 24"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Aircraft Rule 24"
  },
  {
    "question": "Aviation security is a combination of measures, human and __________ , intended to safeguard civil aviation against acts of unlawful interference.",
    "options": [
      "a. SOP’s",
      "b. Procedures",
      "c. Material resources",
      "d. SARP's"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Material resources"
  },
  {
    "question": "All items, other than catering supplies, associated with passenger in-flight services, for example newspapers, magazines, headphones, audio and video tapes, pillows and blankets, amenity kits, etc.",
    "options": [
      "a. Dangerous goods",
      "b. Catering Stores",
      "c. Catering Supplies",
      "d. Cargo"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Catering Stores"
  },
  {
    "question": "A device worn by persons operating X-ray equipment to warn them of potential over exposure to radiation leakage from X-ray equipment",
    "options": [
      "a. Airport Entry Permit",
      "b. Fan beam geometry",
      "c. Dosimeter Batch",
      "d.  Lead Shielding"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Dosimeter Batch"
  },
  {
    "question": "Any baggage of the passenger other than checked baggage",
    "options": [
      "a. Registered baggage",
      "b. Carry-on baggage",
      "c. Unaccompanied baggage",
      "d. Cargo"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Carry-on baggage"
  },
  {
    "question": "A person, organization or enterprise engaged in or offering to engage in an aircraft operation.",
    "options": [
      "a. BCAS",
      "b. Operator",
      "c. Airport",
      "d. ICAO"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Operator"
  },
  {
    "question": "Recognizing the shapes displayed on X-ray units and being able to evaluate and classify them into the proper categories of NO THREAT, POSSIBLE THREAT, and OBVIOUS THREAT",
    "options": [
      "a. Explosive Trace detector",
      "b. Image Interpretation",
      "c. Physical Inspection",
      "d. Explosive vapor detector"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Image Interpretation"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft shall be deemed to be in service from the beginning of the pre – flight preparation of the aircraft by the ground staff or by the crew for a specific flight until twenty – four hours after any landing and the period of such service shall include _______.",
    "options": [
      "a. the entire period during which the aircraft is In flight",
      "b. the entire period during which the aircraft is In service",
      "c. the time till boarding is announced",
      "d. the time till aircraft is on ground"
    ],
    "answer": "a. the entire period during which the aircraft is In flight"
  },
  {
    "question": "The space between the check-in positions and the airside waiting area",
    "options": [
      "a. Airside",
      "b. Departure Concourse",
      "c. Aircraft Stand",
      "d. Sterile Area"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Departure Concourse"
  },
  {
    "question": "An originator of property for transportation by air for their own account and who has established business with a regulated agent or an airline on the basis of agreed criteria addressing the security of goods.",
    "options": [
      "a. Consignee",
      "b. Known Consignee",
      "c. Known Consignor",
      "d. Consignor"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Known Consignor"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft operation other than a commercial air transport operation or an aerial work operation",
    "options": [
      "a. Non commercial operation",
      "b. General aviation operation",
      "c. Corporate aviation",
      "d. Aircraft In flight"
    ],
    "answer": "b. General aviation operation"
  },
  {
    "question": "It means air transportation of passengers and their belongings, cargo, mail etc by civil aircraft.",
    "options": [
      "a. Aviation Security",
      "b. General Aviation",
      "c. Civil Aviation",
      "d. Corporate Aviation"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Civil Aviation"
  },
  {
    "question": "A person assigned by an operator to duty on an aircraft during flight time.",
    "options": [
      "a. Crew Member",
      "b. Disruptive passenger",
      "c. Regulated Agent",
      "d. Sky Marshal"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Crew Member"
  },
  {
    "question": "Passengers making direct connections between two different flights",
    "options": [
      "a. Transfer passenger",
      "b. Transit passenger",
      "c. Unaccompanied minor",
      "d. Disruptive passenger"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Transfer passenger"
  },
  {
    "question": "Baggage at an airport, with or without a baggage tag, which is not picked up by or identified with a passenger.",
    "options": [
      "a. Unidentified baggage",
      "b. Unaccompanied baggage",
      "c. Transit baggage",
      "d. Transit Passenger"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Unidentified baggage"
  },
  {
    "question": "The convention laid down foundation for International Civil Aviation Organization.",
    "options": [
      "a. Chicago Convention",
      "b. Montreal Convention",
      "c. Hague Convention",
      "d. Tokyo Convention"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Chicago Convention"
  }
]
    },
    {
        set: 2,
        questions:[
  {
    "question": "Convention on offences and certain other acts committed on board aircraft",
    "options": [
      "a. Chicago Convention",
      "b. Montreal Convention",
      "c. Hague Convention",
      "d. Tokyo Convention"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Tokyo Convention"
  },
  {
    "question": "The abbreviation CISF stands for",
    "options": [
      "a. Civil India Security Force",
      "b. Central India Security Force",
      "c. Central Indian Security Force",
      "d. Central Industrial Security Force"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Central Industrial Security Force"
  },
  {
    "question": "Security staff on duty can cross a runway",
    "options": [
      "a. At any time",
      "b. Only when runway appears clear",
      "c. Only after clearance from ground control or the ATC tower",
      "d. After aircraft lands"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Only after clearance from ground control or the ATC tower"
  },
  {
    "question": "When moving airside in a vehicle it is necessary to use hazard warning lights",
    "options": [
      "a. Only during conditions of poor visibility",
      "b. Only during darkness",
      "c. When crossing the runway",
      "d. At all times"
    ],
    "answer": "d. At all times"
  },
  {
    "question": "Airport movement rules apply to security staff",
    "options": [
      "a. At all times",
      "b. At all times except when they are on patrol",
      "c. At all times except in an emergency",
      "d. At all times except bad weather"
    ],
    "answer": "a. At all times"
  },
  {
    "question": "Red revolving light on top and below the aircraft if lit indicates",
    "options": [
      "a. You can align front step ladder",
      "b. You can open aircraft hold",
      "c. Engines are running",
      "d. You can drive close to aircraft"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Engines are running"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not the typical location/installation of the airport",
    "options": [
      "a. ATC",
      "b. Parking Area",
      "c. Operation Buildings",
      "d. Baggage Make up area"
    ],
    "answer": "a. ATC"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the vulnerable point of the airport",
    "options": [
      "a. Arrival",
      "b. Visitors area",
      "c. ATC",
      "d. Landside"
    ],
    "answer": "c. ATC"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the safety rule while moving at airport",
    "options": [
      "a. Know the ICAO definitions",
      "b. Must forget the boundary between land side and airside",
      "c. Do not use vehicle hazard light",
      "d. Must cross the runway even if you have not received clearance from Ground Control or ATC"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Know the ICAO definitions"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the right way to cross runway in emergency situation",
    "options": [
      "a. Look left and right then cross",
      "b. Runway should be crossed only after clearance from ATC",
      "c. Use a vehicle with hazard warning light to cross runway at any time",
      "d. Runway can never be crossed"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Use a vehicle with hazard warning light to cross runway at any time"
  },
  {
    "question": "While boarding the aircraft a passenger informs you that while in the coach he saw some smoke coming out of the left engine what action you will take.",
    "options": [
      "a. You will see left engine, since you do not see any smoke no further action required",
      "b. Smoke coming out of engine is not the unlawful interference hence no action required",
      "c. You will inform the passenger that it is none of his business",
      "d. You will immediately inform engineer about the same and tell him to inspect the engine"
    ],
    "answer": "d. You will immediately inform engineer about the same and tell him to inspect the engine"
  },
  {
    "question": "The main purpose of boundary fencing is",
    "options": [
      "a. To keep cattle and livestock off the runway",
      "b. To mark the boundary between land side and airside restricted areas",
      "c. To prevent people looking at aircraft",
      "d. To prevent capture of airport land"
    ],
    "answer": "b. To mark the boundary between land side and airside restricted areas"
  },
  {
    "question": "Access control points are located",
    "options": [
      "a. Within a building such as terminal and within airport boundary",
      "b. Only at the cargo complex",
      "c. Only at the vulnerable points",
      "d. Only at the catering premises"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Within a building such as terminal and within airport boundary"
  },
  {
    "question": "Access control points are",
    "options": [
      "a. Only manned during daylight hours",
      "b. Only manned at night",
      "c. Manned at all times",
      "d. Manned only during high threat"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Manned at all times"
  },
  {
    "question": "Airport workers are required to use access control points",
    "options": [
      "a. Whenever they enter restricted area",
      "b. Only when they are off duty",
      "c. Only if they do not have permit",
      "d. Only when they are accompanying relatives"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Whenever they enter restricted area"
  },
  {
    "question": "Airline employees are authorized to by-pass access control points",
    "options": [
      "a. Whenever they are in uniforms",
      "b. Whenever they are off duty",
      "c. Whenever they are on duty",
      "d. Never"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Never"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is not shown on the AEP",
    "options": [
      "a. Photograph of holder",
      "b. Employee code number",
      "c. Period of validity",
      "d. Permit serial number"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Period of validity"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which color pass is issued to those persons whose duty warrants them to visit all areas of civil airport/ civil enclaves in India",
    "options": [
      "a. Orange",
      "b. Brown",
      "c. Purple",
      "d. Navy Blue"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Orange"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which color pass is issued for crew members of Indian registered airlines whose duty warrants them to visit all areas of civil airports in India.",
    "options": [
      "a. Orange",
      "b. Orange-C",
      "c. Purple",
      "d. Navy blue"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Orange-C"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which color pass is issued for persons whose duty warrants them to visit all areas of a specific airports",
    "options": [
      "a. Orange C",
      "b. Purple",
      "c. Navy Blue",
      "d. White"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Purple"
  },
  {
    "question": "For persons whose duty warrants them to visit all areas of a specific airport except security hold area",
    "options": [
      "a. Purple",
      "b. Navy blue",
      "c. White",
      "d. Light Brown"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Navy blue"
  },
  {
    "question": "For persons whose duty warrants them to visit the operational area only, in a specific airport, excluding SHA and terminal building",
    "options": [
      "a. Navy blue",
      "b. White",
      "c. Light Brown",
      "d. Light Green"
    ],
    "answer": "b. White"
  },
  {
    "question": "For persons whose duty warrants them to visit only the arrival or departure halls of a specific airport, which color pass is issued",
    "options": [
      "a. Navy Blue",
      "b. White",
      "c. Light Brown",
      "d. Purple"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Light Brown"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which passes may be issued to persons whose duty warrants them to visit one specific airport for passenger facilitation up to check-in area of departure side and up to visitor areas on arrival side.",
    "options": [
      "a. Navy blue",
      "b. Light Green",
      "c. Transferable passes",
      "d. Purple – ‘G’"
    ],
    "answer":  "b. Light Green"
  },
  {
    "question": "For GHA persons whose duty warrants them to visit all areas of a specific airports which color pass is issued",
    "options": [
      "a. Purple ‘G’",
      "b. Purple ‘T’",
      "c. Light Green ‘G’",
      "d. Purple"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Purple ‘G’"
  },
  {
    "question": "For persons whose duty warrants them to visit only all areas of the terminal building of a specific airport which colour pass is issued",
    "options": [
      "a. Purple ‘G’",
      "b. Purple ‘T’",
      "c. Purple ‘P’",
      "d. Light Green ‘C’"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Purple ‘T’"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given to casual workers who are hired only on daily wages",
    "options": [
      "a. Purple P",
      "b. Casual labor token",
      "c. Light Green",
      "d. Orange C"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Casual labor token"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is not considered as biometrics?",
    "options": [
      "a. Hand Geometry",
      "b. Finger printing",
      "c. Frisking",
      "d. Iris Recognition"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Frisking"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which category of people need authorized access to airside",
    "options": [
      "a. Terrorist",
      "b. Saboteurs",
      "c. National government representative",
      "d. Employee without Permit"
    ],
    "answer": "c. National government representative"
  },
  {
    "question": "Passengers can be given access to airside on the basis of",
    "options": [
      "a. Pan card",
      "b. Id card",
      "c. Valid Ticket",
      "d. Passport"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Valid Ticket"
  },
  {
    "question": "Staff can be given access to airside on the basis of",
    "options": [
      "a. Pan card",
      "b. Airport Entry permit",
      "c. Company ID card",
      "d. Airside Driving Permit"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Airport Entry permit"
  },
  {
    "question": "Member of parliament can be given access to airside on the basis of",
    "options": [
      "a. Driving license",
      "b. ADP",
      "c. ID Card",
      "d. Ration Card"
    ],
    "answer": "c. ID Card"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following details will be checked in AEP",
    "options": [
      "a. Registered number",
      "b. Color indicating area",
      "c. Designated access gate to be used",
      "d. Safety status"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Color indicating area"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following details will be checked in AEP",
    "options": [
      "a. Registered number",
      "b. Photograph",
      "c. Designated access gate to be used",
      "d. Safety status"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Photograph"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following details will be checked in AEP",
    "options": [
      "a. Registered number",
      "b. Name and designation of person",
      "c. Designated access gate to be used",
      "d. Safety status"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Name and designation of person"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following details will be checked in AEP",
    "options": [
      "a. Registered number",
      "b. Organization",
      "c. Designated access gate to be used",
      "d. Safety status"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Organization"
  },
  {
    "question": "Purpose of access control",
    "options": [
      "a. To control movement of people from land side to airside",
      "b. To allow everyone to enter",
      "c. To allow non traveling people enter airside",
      "d. To control access of Employees only"
    ],
    "answer": "a. To control movement of people from land side to airside"
  },
  {
    "question": "Access control point cannot be located at",
    "options": [
      "a. Inside a building",
      "b. Along airport boundary",
      "c. At cargo warehouse",
      "d. Landside"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Landside"
  },
  {
    "question": "Access control points are located",
    "options": [
      "a. Within a building such as terminal and within airport boundary",
      "b. Only at the cargo complex",
      "c. Only at the vulnerable points",
      "d. Only at the catering premises"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Within a building such as terminal and within airport boundary"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following details should be maintained in access control point logbook",
    "options": [
      "a. Staff personal details",
      "b. Record of incident",
      "c. Shift Supervisors personal details",
      "d. AEP details"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Shift Supervisors personal details"
  },
  {
    "question": "Most of the terrorist prefer using IED because",
    "options": [
      "a. It is cheap",
      "b. The effect of explosion is less",
      "c. It is a home production",
      "d. Its components are not available easily"
    ],
    "answer": "c. It is a home production"
  },
  {
    "question": "IID is activated by",
    "options": [
      "a. Electrical detonator",
      "b. Spark",
      "c. Non electrical detonator",
      "d. Blasting cap"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Spark"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is not the component of IED.",
    "options": [
      "a. Explosives",
      "b. Detonator",
      "c. Switch",
      "d. Container"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Container"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is not the type of switch",
    "options": [
      "a. Anti handling",
      "b. Ambient",
      "c. Initiating",
      "d. Remote control"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Initiating"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following factor is not use in ambient condition bomb?",
    "options": [
      "a. Humidity",
      "b. Proximity",
      "c. Time",
      "d. Darkness"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Time"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sound sensitive switch is a type of ______________ switch.",
    "options": [
      "a. Ambient switch",
      "b. Delayed switch",
      "c. Anti-handling",
      "d. Remote control"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Ambient switch"
  },
  {
    "question": "Light sensitive is a type of _______________ switch",
    "options": [
      "a. Ambient switch",
      "b. Delayed switch",
      "c. Anti-handling",
      "d. Remote control"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Ambient switch"
  },
  {
    "question": "Barometric is a type of ____________ switch",
    "options": [
      "a. Delayed switch",
      "b. Anti-handling switch",
      "c. Ambient switch",
      "d. Remote control"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Ambient switch"
  },
  {
    "question": "Use of watch or timepiece in IED is a _______________ switch",
    "options": [
      "a. Ambient switch",
      "b. Time /Delay switch",
      "c. Anti- handling switch",
      "d. Remote control"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Time /Delay switch"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the color of the TNT explosive?",
    "options": [
      "a. Pale Yellow",
      "b. White",
      "c. Yellow",
      "d. Black"
    ],
    "answer":  "d. Black"
  }
]
    },
     {
        set: 3,
        questions:[
  {
    "question": "What is the physical form of the TNT explosive",
    "options": [
      "a. Block",
      "b. Crystalline",
      "c. Cartridge",
      "d. Slurry"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Block"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the color of the RDX.",
    "options": [
      "a. Pale Yellow",
      "b. White",
      "c. Yellow",
      "d. Black"
    ],
    "answer": "b. White"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the physical form of RDX.",
    "options": [
      "a. Block",
      "b. Crystalline",
      "c. Cartridge",
      "d. Flexible"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Crystalline"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the color of PETN",
    "options": [
      "a. White",
      "b. Pale Yellow",
      "c. Black",
      "d. Yellow"
    ],
    "answer": "a. White"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the physical form of PETN.",
    "options": [
      "a. Block",
      "b. Crystalline",
      "c. Cartridge",
      "d. Flexible"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Crystalline"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the color of PEK",
    "options": [
      "a. White",
      "b. Yellow",
      "c. Black",
      "d. Orange"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Yellow"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the physical form of PEK",
    "options": [
      "a. Cartridge",
      "b. Flexible",
      "c. Cord",
      "d. Granular"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Cartridge"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the color of Semtex",
    "options": [
      "a. Black",
      "b. Yellow",
      "c. White",
      "d. Chocolate"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Black"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the physical form of Semtex",
    "options": [
      "a. Flexible",
      "b. Slurry",
      "c. Granular",
      "d. Plastic"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Slurry"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the color of gun powder",
    "options": [
      "a. Chocolate",
      "b. Black",
      "c. Yellow",
      "d. White"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Black"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the physical form of gun powder",
    "options": [
      "a. Flexible",
      "b. Cord",
      "c. Granular",
      "d. Crystalline"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Granular"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the color of Dynamite",
    "options": [
      "a. Black",
      "b. Yellow",
      "c. Greenish",
      "d. White"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Yellow"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the physical form of Dynamite",
    "options": [
      "a. Cartridge wrapped in paper",
      "b. Slurry",
      "c. Granular",
      "d. Plastic"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Cartridge wrapped in paper"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is not the effect of explosion",
    "options": [
      "a. Translation",
      "b. Concussion",
      "c. Transmission",
      "d. Temperature rises"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Transmission"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the effect of explosion",
    "options": [
      "a. Transaction",
      "b. Translation",
      "c. Transeption",
      "d. Transmission"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Translation"
  },
  {
    "question": "Blast over pressure is the effect of explosion in which",
    "options": [
      "a. Temperature rises",
      "b. High Pressure is generated",
      "c. Human bodies lifted",
      "d. Vacuum is created"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Human bodies lifted"
  },
  {
    "question": "Thermal effect is the effect of explosion in which",
    "options": [
      "a. Temperature rises",
      "b. Pressure generated",
      "c. Human bodies lifted",
      "d. Vacuum is created"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Temperature rises"
  },
  {
    "question": "Concussion effect is the effect of explosion in which",
    "options": [
      "a. Temperature rises",
      "b. Earth and water shocks are caused",
      "c. Human bodies lifted",
      "d. Vacuum is created"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Vacuum is created"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the place of concealment of explosive",
    "options": [
      "a. Disguised",
      "b. On person",
      "c. Dismantled",
      "d. Camouflaged"
    ],
    "answer": "b. On person"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the place of concealment of explosive",
    "options": [
      "a. Disguised",
      "b. In hand bag",
      "c. Dismantled",
      "d. Camouflaged"
    ],
    "answer": "b. In hand bag"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the place of concealment of explosive",
    "options": [
      "a. Disguised",
      "b. Dismantled",
      "c. In registered bag",
      "d. Camouflaged"
    ],
    "answer": "c. In registered bag"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the place of concealment of explosive",
    "options": [
      "a. Disguised",
      "b. Dismantled",
      "c. Camouflaged",
      "d. In vehicle"
    ],
    "answer": "d. In vehicle"
  },
  {
    "question": "Those articles that must never be carried in the cabin of an aircraft or taken into the security restricted area of an airport",
    "options": [
      "a. Prohibited items",
      "b. Stores",
      "c. Company stores",
      "d. Company mail"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Prohibited items"
  },
  {
    "question": "A Hand Gun falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Weapons"
  },
  {
    "question": "A Flare Gun falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Weapons"
  },
  {
    "question": "A Blow Gun falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Explosives",
      "b. Dangerous Articles",
      "c. Dangerous Substances",
      "d. Weapons"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Weapons"
  },
  {
    "question": "A Dart falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Weapons"
  },
  {
    "question": "A Electrical Dart Gun falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Explosives",
      "b. Dangerous Articles",
      "c. Dangerous Substances",
      "d. Weapons"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Weapons"
  },
  {
    "question": "Rifle falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Weapons"
  },
  {
    "question": "Shot Gun falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Weapons"
  },
  {
    "question": "A Pallet Gun falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Weapons"
  },
  {
    "question": "A Spear Gun falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Weapons"
  },
  {
    "question": "A knife with blade of 12 cms falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Weapons"
  },
  {
    "question": "A knife with blade of 08 cms falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Dangerous Articles"
  },
  {
    "question": "A knife with blade of 5 inches falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Weapons"
  },
  {
    "question": "A knife with blade of 03 inches falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Dangerous Articles"
  },
  {
    "question": "A Mace falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Weapons"
  },
  {
    "question": "Tear Gas falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Weapons"
  },
  {
    "question": "A Nanchak used for Martial Arts falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Weapons"
  },
  {
    "question": "A Sword falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Explosives",
      "b. Dangerous Articles",
      "c. Dangerous Substances",
      "d. Weapons"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Weapons"
  },
  {
    "question": "A Starter Pistol falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Dangerous Articles"
  },
  {
    "question": "Toy Gun falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Dangerous Articles"
  },
  {
    "question": "A Pocket scissor falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Dangerous Articles"
  },
  {
    "question": "Screw driver falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Dangerous Articles"
  },
  {
    "question": "Knitting needles fall under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Substances",
      "d. Dangerous Articles"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Dangerous Articles"
  },
  {
    "question": "Dynamite falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Explosives"
  },
  {
    "question": "TNT falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Explosives"
  },
  {
    "question": "PEK falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Explosives"
  },
  {
    "question": "Flares fall under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Explosives"
  },
  {
    "question": "Fire crackers fall under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Explosives"
  }
]
    },
     {
        set: 4,
        questions:[
  {
    "question": "Hand grenade falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Explosives"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pipe bomb falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Dangerous Articles",
      "c. Explosives",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Explosives"
  },
  {
    "question": "Blasting cap falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Dangerous Articles",
      "c. Dangerous Substances",
      "d. Explosives"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Explosives"
  },
  {
    "question": "Acid falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Dangerous Substances"
  },
  {
    "question": "Corrosive liquid falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Dangerous Substances"
  },
  {
    "question": "Radioactive material falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Dangerous Substances"
  },
  {
    "question": "Umbrella with a pointed tip falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Dangerous Articles"
  },
  {
    "question": "Swiss knife falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Dangerous Articles"
  },
  {
    "question": "Zippo Lighter fluid falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Dangerous Substances"
  },
  {
    "question": "Kerosene falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Dangerous Substances"
  },
  {
    "question": "Gasoline falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Dangerous Substances"
  },
  {
    "question": "Corkscrew falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Dangerous Articles"
  },
  {
    "question": "Razor blade falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Dangerous Articles"
  },
  {
    "question": "Straight Razor falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substance"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Dangerous Articles"
  },
  {
    "question": "Bows and arrows falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Weapons"
  },
  {
    "question": "Hockey stick falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Dangerous Articles"
  },
  {
    "question": "Base ball bat falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Dangerous Articles",
      "b. Weapons",
      "c. Explosives",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Dangerous Articles"
  },
  {
    "question": "Cricket bat falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Dangerous Articles",
      "c. Explosives",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Dangerous Articles"
  },
  {
    "question": "Power drill falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Dangerous Articles"
  },
  {
    "question": "Box cutter falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Dangerous Articles"
  },
  {
    "question": "Hammer falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Dangerous Articles",
      "b. Weapons",
      "c. Explosives",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Dangerous Articles"
  },
  {
    "question": "TNT falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Explosives"
  },
  {
    "question": "RDX falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Explosives"
  },
  {
    "question": "Semtex falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Dangerous Articles",
      "c. Dangerous Substances",
      "d. Explosives"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Explosives"
  },
  {
    "question": "Gun powder falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Explosives"
  },
  {
    "question": "TATP falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Explosives",
      "b. Weapons",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Explosives"
  },
  {
    "question": "Dynamite falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Dangerous Articles",
      "c. Dangerous Substances",
      "d. Explosives"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Explosives"
  },
  {
    "question": "C-4 falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Dangerous substance",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Explosives"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Explosives"
  },
  {
    "question": "The main purpose of using IED is to",
    "options": [
      "a. Cause Explosion",
      "b. Burn items",
      "c. Create smoke",
      "d. Produce gas"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Cause Explosion"
  },
  {
    "question": "IID is designed to",
    "options": [
      "a. Explode",
      "b. Burn",
      "c. Burst",
      "d. Blast"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Burn"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following item is banned in hand bag.",
    "options": [
      "a. Gas lighter",
      "b. Walking stick",
      "c. Folding umbrella",
      "d. Medicines like asthma inhaler"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Gas lighter"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following item is banned in hand bag",
    "options": [
      "a. Cell phone",
      "b. Laptops",
      "c. Corkscrew",
      "d. Folding umbrella"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Corkscrew"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following item is banned in hand bag",
    "options": [
      "a. Thermometer",
      "b. Pool cues",
      "c. Folding Umbrella",
      "d. Liquids not more than 100 ml"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Pool cues"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following item is banned in hand bag",
    "options": [
      "a. Screw driver",
      "b. Cell phone",
      "c. Feeding bottle",
      "d. Thermometer"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Screw driver"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following item is allowed in hand bag",
    "options": [
      "a. Straight Razor",
      "b. Knitting needles",
      "c. Cell phone",
      "d. Hockey stick"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Cell phone"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following item is allowed in hand bag",
    "options": [
      "a. Ice pick",
      "b. Swiss knife",
      "c. Thermometer",
      "d. Box cutter"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Thermometer"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following item is banned in hand bag of passenger",
    "options": [
      "a. Medicines like asthma inhaler",
      "b. Feeding bottle",
      "c. Folding umbrella",
      "d. Cork screw"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Cork screw"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following item is banned in hand bag of passenger",
    "options": [
      "a. Medicines like asthma inhaler",
      "b. Feeding bottle",
      "c. Folding umbrella",
      "d. Screw driver"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Screw driver"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following item is banned in hand bag of passenger.",
    "options": [
      "a. Medicines like asthma inhaler",
      "b. Liquids more than 100 ml",
      "c. Feeding bottle",
      "d. Folding umbrella"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Liquids more than 100 ml"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following item is banned in hand bag of passenger.",
    "options": [
      "a. Replica of Gun",
      "b. Medicines like asthma inhaler",
      "c. Feeding bottle",
      "d. Folding umbrella"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Replica of Gun"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following item is banned in hand bag of passenger",
    "options": [
      "a. Medicines like asthma inhaler",
      "b. Feeding bottle",
      "c. Folding umbrella",
      "d. Replica of revolver"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Replica of revolver"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following item is banned in hand bag of passenger",
    "options": [
      "a. Ammunition",
      "b. Medicines like asthma inhaler",
      "c. Feeding bottle",
      "d. Folding umbrella"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Ammunition"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following item is banned in hand bag of passenger",
    "options": [
      "a. Medicines like asthma inhaler",
      "b. Bullets of any type",
      "c. Feeding bottle",
      "d. Folding umbrella"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Bullets of any type"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following item is banned in hand bag of passenger",
    "options": [
      "a. Medicines like asthma inhaler",
      "b. Feeding bottle",
      "c. Any sharp object",
      "d. Folding umbrella"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Any sharp object"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following item is banned in hand bag of passenger",
    "options": [
      "a. Medicines like asthma inhaler",
      "b. Feeding bottle",
      "c. Folding umbrella",
      "d. Brass knuckles"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Brass knuckles"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following item is banned in hand bag of passenger",
    "options": [
      "a. Disabling gases",
      "b. Medicines like asthma inhaler",
      "c. Feeding bottle",
      "d. Folding umbrella"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Disabling gases"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following item is banned in hand bag of passenger",
    "options": [
      "a. Medicines like asthma inhaler",
      "b. Feeding bottle",
      "c. Folding umbrella",
      "d. Chemicals"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Chemicals"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following item is banned in hand bag of passenger",
    "options": [
      "a. Medicines like asthma inhaler",
      "b. Feeding bottle",
      "c. Large heavy tools",
      "d. Folding umbrella"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Large heavy tools"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following item is banned in hand bag of passenger",
    "options": [
      "a. Wrenches",
      "b. Walking stick",
      "c. Feeding bottle",
      "d. Folding umbrella"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Wrenches"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following item is banned in hand bag of passenger.",
    "options": [
      "a. Medicines like asthma inhaler",
      "b. Feeding bottle",
      "c. Folding umbrella",
      "d. Pliers"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Pliers"
  }
]
    },
     {
        set: 5,
        questions: [
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following item is banned in hand bag of passenger",
    "options": [
      "a. Medicines like asthma inhaler",
      "b. Crow bar",
      "c. Walking stick",
      "d. Folding umbrella"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Crow bar"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following item is banned in hand bag of passenger",
    "options": [
      "a. Feeding bottle",
      "b. Medicines like asthma inhaler",
      "c. Folding umbrella",
      "d. Ice Pick"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Ice Pick"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following item is banned in hand bag of passenger",
    "options": [
      "a. Medicines like asthma inhaler",
      "b. Feeding bottle",
      "c. Folding umbrella",
      "d. Power Drill"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Power Drill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following item is banned in hand bag of passenger",
    "options": [
      "a. Medicines like asthma inhaler",
      "b. Feeding bottle",
      "c. Folding umbrella",
      "d. Saw"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Saw"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following item is banned in hand bag of passenger",
    "options": [
      "a. Medicines like asthma inhaler",
      "b. Feeding bottle",
      "c. Folding umbrella",
      "d. Fire extinguisher"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Fire extinguisher"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following item is banned in hand bag of passenger",
    "options": [
      "a. Box cutter",
      "b. Medicines like asthma inhaler",
      "c. Feeding bottle",
      "d. Folding umbrella"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Box cutter"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following item is banned in hand bag of passenger",
    "options": [
      "a. Medicines like asthma inhaler",
      "b. Screw driver",
      "c. Feeding bottle",
      "d. Folding umbrella"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Screw driver"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following item is banned in hand bag of passenger",
    "options": [
      "a. Dart",
      "b. Medicines like asthma inhaler",
      "c. Feeding bottle",
      "d. Folding umbrella"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Dart"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following item is banned in hand bag of passenger",
    "options": [
      "a. Medicines like asthma inhaler",
      "b. Feeding bottle",
      "c. Folding umbrella",
      "d. Bows and arrows"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Bows and arrows"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following item is banned in hand bag of passenger",
    "options": [
      "a. Medicines like asthma inhaler",
      "b. Feeding bottle",
      "c. Folding umbrella",
      "d. Mace"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Mace"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following item is banned in hand bag of passenger",
    "options": [
      "a. Medicines like asthma inhaler",
      "b. Feeding bottle",
      "c. Folding umbrella",
      "d. Martial art device"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Martial art device"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following item is banned in hand bag of passenger",
    "options": [
      "a. Walking stick",
      "b. Cell phone",
      "c. Pool cues",
      "d. Laptops"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Pool cues"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following item is banned in hand bag of passenger",
    "options": [
      "a. Walking stick",
      "b. Cell phone",
      "c. Hockey stick",
      "d. Asthma inhaler"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Hockey stick"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following item is banned in hand bag of passenger",
    "options": [
      "a. Walking stick",
      "b. Cell phone",
      "c. Base ball bat",
      "d. Folding umbrella"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Base ball bat"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following item is banned in hand bag of passenger",
    "options": [
      "a. Walking stick",
      "b. Cell phone",
      "c. Golf clubs",
      "d. Laptops"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Golf clubs"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following item is banned in hand bag of passenger",
    "options": [
      "a. Walking stick",
      "b. Cell phone",
      "c. Cricket bats",
      "d. Laptops"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Cricket bats"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following item is banned in hand bag of passenger",
    "options": [
      "a. Walking stick",
      "b. Cell phone",
      "c. Ski poles",
      "d. Laptops"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Ski poles"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following item is banned in hand bag of passenger",
    "options": [
      "a. Walking stick",
      "b. Cell phone",
      "c. Gas lighter",
      "d. Laptops"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Gas lighter"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following item is banned in hand bag of passenger",
    "options": [
      "a. Gasoline",
      "b. Walking stick",
      "c. Cell phone",
      "d. Laptops"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Gasoline"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following item is banned in hand bag of passenger",
    "options": [
      "a. Walking stick",
      "b. Cell phone",
      "c. Chilly powder",
      "d. Laptops"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Chilly powder"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following item is banned in hand bag of passenger",
    "options": [
      "a. Kerosene",
      "b. Cell phone",
      "c. Walking stick",
      "d. Laptops"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Kerosene"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following item is banned in hand bag of passenger",
    "options": [
      "a. Knitting needles",
      "b. Cell phone",
      "c. Walking stick",
      "d. Laptops"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Knitting needles"
  },
  {
    "question": "Detonators can be _______________ or ___________",
    "options": [
      "a. Burning and non burning",
      "b. Exploding and non exploding",
      "c. Electric and non electric",
      "d. Commercial and military"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Electric and non electric"
  },
  {
    "question": "Articles primarily designed to kill, injure, immobilize or incapacitate are known as",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous articles",
      "d. Dangerous substances"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Weapons"
  },
  {
    "question": "Any item that can be used to threaten the safety of passenger and aircraft is",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous articles",
      "d. Dangerous substances"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Dangerous articles"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is a dangerous article",
    "options": [
      "a. Grenade",
      "b. Tear Gas",
      "c. Hammer",
      "d. Gasoline"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Hammer"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which are the places of concealment of explosives on person",
    "options": [
      "a. In hand bag",
      "b. In birthday cake",
      "c. Between the legs",
      "d. In false bottom of bag"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Between the legs"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which are the places of concealment of explosives on person",
    "options": [
      "a. In hand bag",
      "b. In birthday cake",
      "c. Under the armpit",
      "d. In false bottom of bag"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Under the armpit"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which are the places of concealment of explosives on person",
    "options": [
      "a. In hand bag",
      "b. In birthday cake",
      "c. In the small of the back",
      "d. In false bottom of bag"
    ],
    "answer": "c. In the small of the back"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which are the places of concealment of explosives on person",
    "options": [
      "a. In hand bag",
      "b. Seam of trouser",
      "c. In birthday cake",
      "d. In false bottom of bag"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Seam of trouser"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which are the places of concealment of explosives on person",
    "options": [
      "a. In hand bag",
      "b. In between the breasts",
      "c. In birthday cake",
      "d. In false bottom of bag"
    ],
    "answer": "b. In between the breasts"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is true for a delay bomb",
    "options": [
      "a. The maximum delay can be for 12 hours",
      "b. The maximum delay can be for 24 hours",
      "c. The delay can be for few minutes to several days",
      "d. The maximum delay can be for 2 hours"
    ],
    "answer": "c. The delay can be for few minutes to several days"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is minimum safe distance from package containing IED",
    "options": [
      "a. 200 m",
      "b. 1 km",
      "c. 100 m",
      "d. 10 m"
    ],
    "answer": "c. 100 m"
  },
  {
    "question": "Improvised explosive cannot be manufactured from",
    "options": [
      "a. Urine",
      "b. Aspirin tablets",
      "c. Weed killer",
      "d. Wheat"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Wheat"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explosives are of two types",
    "options": [
      "a. Low explosive and high explosive",
      "b. Small explosive and big explosive",
      "c. Electrical and non electrical explosive",
      "d. Traditional and Modern explosive"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Low explosive and high explosive"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is not the type of switch used in an IED",
    "options": [
      "a. Cloth peg",
      "b. Anti lift mechanism",
      "c. Wire",
      "d. Booby trap"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Wire"
  },
  {
    "question": "Anti handling bomb in the bag cannot be activated by",
    "options": [
      "a. Lifting",
      "b. Pulling",
      "c. Opening",
      "d. Change in temperature"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Change in temperature"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the color of LTPE",
    "options": [
      "a. Yellow",
      "b. Black",
      "c. White",
      "d. Pale yellow"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Black"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the physical form of LTPE",
    "options": [
      "a. Cartridge",
      "b. Flexible",
      "c. Slurry",
      "d. Cord"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Flexible"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the color of Tetryl",
    "options": [
      "a. Black",
      "b. Yellow",
      "c. White",
      "d. Chocolate"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Yellow"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the physical form of Tetryl",
    "options": [
      "a. Slurry",
      "b. Granular",
      "c. Flexible",
      "d. Plastic"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Granular"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the color of sheet explosive",
    "options": [
      "a. Yellow",
      "b. White",
      "c. Chocolate",
      "d. Black"
    ],
    "answer": "b. White"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the physical form of sheet explosive",
    "options": [
      "a. Granular",
      "b. Block",
      "c. Cord",
      "d. Flexible"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Flexible"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the color of C-4 explosive",
    "options": [
      "a. Black",
      "b. White",
      "c. Chocolate",
      "d. Pale Yellow"
    ],
    "answer": "b. White"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the physical form of C-4 explosive",
    "options": [
      "a. Flexible",
      "b. Plastic",
      "c. Cord",
      "d. Granular"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Plastic"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is color of cordtex explosive",
    "options": [
      "a. Yellow",
      "b. Chocolate",
      "c. Black",
      "d. Orange"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Chocolate"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the physical form of cordtex explosive",
    "options": [
      "a. Plastic",
      "b. Cord",
      "c. Granular",
      "d. Flexible"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Cord"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the color of the safety fuse",
    "options": [
      "a. Yellow",
      "b. Dirty black",
      "c. White",
      "d. Chocolate"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Dirty black"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the color of gelatin",
    "options": [
      "a. Greenish",
      "b. Yellow",
      "c. Black",
      "d. White"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Yellow"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the color of ANFO",
    "options": [
      "a. Yellow",
      "b. White",
      "c. Greenish",
      "d. Black"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Greenish"
  }
]
    },
     {
        set: 6,
        questions: [
  {
    "question": "Due to explosion pressure may be generated up to __________PSI.",
    "options": [
      "a. 4,00,000 PSI",
      "b. 40,000 PSI",
      "c. 25,000 PSI",
      "d. 40,00,000 PSI"
    ],
    "answer": "d. 40,00,000 PSI"
  },
  {
    "question": "Velocity of detonation of TNT is",
    "options": [
      "a. 6,000 KMPH",
      "b. 30,000 KMPH",
      "c. 25,000 KMPH",
      "d. 40,000 KMPH"
    ],
    "answer": "c. 25,000 KMPH"
  },
  {
    "question": "Speed of fragmentation due to explosion may be up to ___________",
    "options": [
      "a. 6,000 KMPH",
      "b. 3,000 KMPH",
      "c. 25,000 KMPH",
      "d. 4,000 KMPH"
    ],
    "answer": "a. 6,000 KMPH"
  },
  {
    "question": "Due to translation effect of explosion human bodies are lifted ____________ feet high",
    "options": [
      "a. 30 to 60",
      "b. 100 to 120",
      "c. 100 to 200",
      "d. 80 to 100"
    ],
    "answer": "a. 30 to 60"
  },
  {
    "question": "A scissor with 11cms blade falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Weapons"
  },
  {
    "question": "Chisels falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Dangerous Articles"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ice picks falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Dangerous Articles"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ammunition falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Explosives"
  },
  {
    "question": "Loaded magazine of a gun falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Explosives"
  },
  {
    "question": "Safety fuse falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substances"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Explosives"
  },
  {
    "question": "Chilly powder falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substance"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Dangerous Articles"
  },
  {
    "question": "Martial art device falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substance"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Weapons"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pool cues fall under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substance"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Dangerous Articles"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ski poles falls under which category of prohibited article",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous Articles",
      "d. Dangerous Substance"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Dangerous Articles"
  },
  {
    "question": "IID is designed to",
    "options": [
      "a. Explode",
      "b. Burn",
      "c. Burst",
      "d. Blast"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Burst"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is incendiary material",
    "options": [
      "a. TNT",
      "b. RDX",
      "c. Semtex",
      "d. Gun Powder"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Gun Powder"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following item can be carried in checked in luggage without license",
    "options": [
      "a. Pistol",
      "b. Revolver",
      "c. Machine gun",
      "d. Starter pistol"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Starter pistol"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following item can be carried in checked in luggage without license",
    "options": [
      "a. Air gun",
      "b. Pistol",
      "c. Revolver",
      "d. Machine gun"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Air gun"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is true for an IED",
    "options": [
      "a. Requires incendiary device",
      "b. Explodes",
      "c. Burns",
      "d. Requires gun powder"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Explodes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is true for an IED",
    "options": [
      "a. Requires incendiary device",
      "b. Burns",
      "c. Requires initiating mechanism",
      "d. Does not require detonator"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Requires initiating mechanism"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is not applicable for an IID ?",
    "options": [
      "a. Requires incendiary device",
      "b. Burns",
      "c. Requires a high explosive",
      "d. Does not require detonator"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Requires a high explosive"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explosives are of two types. The two types are",
    "options": [
      "a. High explosive and Low Explosive",
      "b. Traditional explosive and Modern explosive",
      "c. Heavy explosives and Light explosives",
      "d. Commercial explosives and military explosives"
    ],
    "answer": "a. High explosive and Low Explosive"
  },
  {
    "question": "_________ includes acids, corrosives and radioactive material",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapons",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Dangerous articles",
      "d. Dangerous substances"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Dangerous substances"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is not an explosive",
    "options": [
      "a. TNT",
      "b. RDX",
      "c. Sulphur powder",
      "d. Semtex"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Sulphur powder"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is not a weapon",
    "options": [
      "a. Hammer",
      "b. Mace",
      "c. AK 47",
      "d. Baton"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Hammer"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is a dangerous substance",
    "options": [
      "a. TNT",
      "b. RDX",
      "c. Kerosene",
      "d. Baton"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Kerosene"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is a weapon",
    "options": [
      "a. Grenade",
      "b. Mace",
      "c. TNT",
      "d. Hammer"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Mace"
  },
  {
    "question": "Detonator is also known as",
    "options": [
      "a. Switch",
      "b. Initiator",
      "c. Explosive",
      "d. Mechanism"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Initiator"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following falls under concealment of explosives on person",
    "options": [
      "a. Concealing explosive in handbag",
      "b. Concealing explosive in a box carried in handbag",
      "c. Concealing explosive in the sole of shoe",
      "d. Concealing explosive in false bottom of bag"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Concealing explosive in the sole of shoe"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not true for IED ?",
    "options": [
      "a. It is easy to conceal",
      "b. It does not require detonator",
      "c. It can take any shape",
      "d. It can be of any size"
    ],
    "answer": "b. It does not require detonator"
  },
  {
    "question": "A __________ is the explosive device designed, fabricated, placed and activated to create panic and chaos among public",
    "options": [
      "a. Incendiary Explosive Device",
      "b. Inert Explosive Device",
      "c. Impact Exploding Device",
      "d. Improvised Explosive Device"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Improvised Explosive Device"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is applicable for explosive material used in an IED",
    "options": [
      "a. It will always be stolen from military camp",
      "b. It can be manufactured from material easily available in market",
      "c. It will always be acquired from international terrorist organizations which are specialized in manufacturing it",
      "d. It requires only explosive material and switch"
    ],
    "answer": "b. It can be manufactured from material easily available in market"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is true for IED ?",
    "options": [
      "a. IED can be of any shape, size or color",
      "b. IED is always of specific shape",
      "c. IED is another name for bomb",
      "d. IED device always uses incendiary material for explosion"
    ],
    "answer": "a. IED can be of any shape, size or color"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IED which may explode if you tilt the package, has ____________ mechanism",
    "options": [
      "a. Anti handling mechanism",
      "b. Ambient mechanism",
      "c. Delayed mechanism",
      "d. Remote control mechanism"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Anti handling mechanism"
  },
  {
    "question": "Remote control bombs can be activated by",
    "options": [
      "a. Transmission of electric current",
      "b. Transmission of light",
      "c. Transmission of sound waves",
      "d. Transmission of electromagnetic waves"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Transmission of electromagnetic waves"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is an example of plastic explosive",
    "options": [
      "a. Semtex",
      "b. RDX",
      "c. TNT",
      "d. ANFO"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Semtex"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is an example of plastic explosive",
    "options": [
      "a. PEK",
      "b. RDX",
      "c. TNT",
      "d. ANFO"
    ],
    "answer": "a. PEK"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following battery can be used for letter bomb",
    "options": [
      "a. 6V",
      "b. 9V",
      "c. Polaroid battery",
      "d. Pencil cells"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Polaroid battery"
  },
  {
    "question": "Remote control bomb cannot be activated by",
    "options": [
      "a. Transmission of electromagnetic waves",
      "b. Command wire bomb",
      "c. Infrared",
      "d. Humidity"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Humidity"
  },
  {
    "question": "Remote control bomb can be activated by",
    "options": [
      "a. Time",
      "b. Change in temperature",
      "c. Infrared",
      "d. Humidity"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Infrared"
  },
  {
    "question": "Remote control bomb can be activated by",
    "options": [
      "a. Sound",
      "b. Change in temperature",
      "c. Transmission of electromagnetic waves",
      "d. Humidity"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Transmission of electromagnetic waves"
  },
  {
    "question": "The abbreviation of POD stands for",
    "options": [
      "a. Proof of departure",
      "b. Point of detonation",
      "c. Power of detonator",
      "d. Postal order"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Point of detonation"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is an example of weapon",
    "options": [
      "a. Kirpan",
      "b. Pocket knife",
      "c. Box cutter",
      "d. Hockey stick"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Kirpan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is an example of improvised detonator",
    "options": [
      "a. Cloth peg",
      "b. Party popper",
      "c. Safety fuse",
      "d. Polaroid battery"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Party popper"
  },
  {
    "question": "_________________ PSI of pressure created by explosion can cause eardrums to rupture",
    "options": [
      "a. 10 PSI",
      "b. 50 PSI",
      "c. 05 PSI",
      "d. 20 PSI"
    ],
    "answer": "b. 50 PSI"
  },
  {
    "question": "The name ‘Improvised Explosive Device’ signifies that",
    "options": [
      "a. The explosive is a improved version of a bomb",
      "b. It is the best explosive available in the market",
      "c. It is a explosive invented by the terrorist using his own imagination",
      "d. It is made from explosive material stolen from a military camp"
    ],
    "answer": "c. It is a explosive invented by the terrorist using his own imagination"
  },
  {
    "question": "__________ volts of current is the minimum requirement for a power source used in IED",
    "options": [
      "a. 3 volts",
      "b. 9 volts",
      "c. 1.5 volts",
      "d. 15 volts"
    ],
    "answer": "c. 1.5 volts"
  },
  {
    "question": "_______________ type of IED is activated by the victim",
    "options": [
      "a. IED with Ambient mechanism",
      "b. IED with Delayed mechanism",
      "c. IED with Anti handling mechanism",
      "d. IED with Remote control mechanism"
    ],
    "answer": "c. IED with Anti handling mechanism"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following method of concealment of IED would be difficult to identify in XBIS ?",
    "options": [
      "a. IED concealed in a book",
      "b. IED concealed in a wooden box",
      "c. IED concealed in a plastic bottle",
      "d. IED concealed in a laptop"
    ],
    "answer": "d. IED concealed in a laptop"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following type of IED is most dangerous to handle",
    "options": [
      "a. IED with Ambient mechanism",
      "b. IED with Delayed mechanism",
      "c. IED with Anti handling mechanism",
      "d. IED with Remote control mechanism"
    ],
    "answer": "c. IED with Anti handling mechanism"
  }
]
    }, 
    {
        set: 7,
        questions: [
  {
    "question": "A micro switch with a pressure release mechanism is _______________ type of switch",
    "options": [
      "a. Ambient mechanism",
      "b. Delayed mechanism",
      "c. Anti handling mechanism",
      "d. Remote control mechanism"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Anti handling mechanism"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IED which may explode once atmospheric pressure changes, uses ____________",
    "options": [
      "a. Barometer",
      "b. Altimeter",
      "c. Thermometer",
      "d. Micro switch"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Barometer"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IED which would explode once aircraft reaches exactly 35000 feet, uses ____________ to activate the device",
    "options": [
      "a. Ambient mechanism",
      "b. Delayed mechanism",
      "c. Anti handling mechanism",
      "d. Remote control mechanism"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Ambient mechanism"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IED planted at night automatically explodes on sunrise, uses ___________ as a switch",
    "options": [
      "a. Watch",
      "b. Micro switch",
      "c. Remote control",
      "d. Light sensor"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Light sensor"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following property of mercury enables terrorist to use it as a switch in anti handling device",
    "options": [
      "a. Mercury is a liquid",
      "b. Mercury is a good conductor of electricity",
      "c. Mercury is very dense",
      "d. Mercury is a metal"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Mercury is a good conductor of electricity"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is true for time / delay mechanism in IED",
    "options": [
      "a. Only digital clock can be used",
      "b. Only mechanical clock can be used",
      "c. Chemicals can also be used to cause a delay",
      "d. Maximum delay can be for 24 hours"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Chemicals can also be used to cause a delay"
  },
  {
    "question": "IED with a command wire mechanism is activated by",
    "options": [
      "a. Electromagnetic waves",
      "b. By means of a wire connecting from bomber to the intended target",
      "c. Loud sound",
      "d. Handling it any way such as lifting, tilting"
    ],
    "answer": "b. By means of a wire connecting from bomber to the intended target"
  },
  {
    "question": "________________ can be cast into shapes such as dolls heads, animals, wall plaques",
    "options": [
      "a. RDX",
      "b. TNT",
      "c. Cortex",
      "d. Sheet explosive"
    ],
    "answer": "b. TNT"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is an example of high explosive",
    "options": [
      "a. ANFO",
      "b. Gunpowder",
      "c. Flares",
      "d. Fireworks"
    ],
    "answer": "a. ANFO"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is an example of high explosive",
    "options": [
      "a. Semtex",
      "b. Gunpowder",
      "c. Flares",
      "d. Fireworks"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Semtex"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is an example of low explosive",
    "options": [
      "a. ANFO",
      "b. Gunpowder",
      "c. Semtex",
      "d. C4"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Gunpowder"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is an example of low explosive",
    "options": [
      "a. Fireworks",
      "b. PETN",
      "c. Semtex",
      "d. C4"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Fireworks"
  },
  {
    "question": "In EVD presence of explosives is detected by collection of",
    "options": [
      "a. Vapors",
      "b. Traces",
      "c. Smell",
      "d. Information"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Vapors"
  },
  {
    "question": "In ETD presence of explosives is detected by collection of",
    "options": [
      "a. Vapors",
      "b. Traces",
      "c. Smell",
      "d. Information"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Traces"
  },
  {
    "question": "The abbreviation LTPE stands for?",
    "options": [
      "a. Limited Threat Plastic Explosive",
      "b. Low Time Plastic Explosive",
      "c. Low Temperature Plastic Explosive",
      "d. Limited Temperature Plastic Explosive"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Low Temperature Plastic Explosive"
  },
  {
    "question": "Access control system can be",
    "options": [
      "a. Only automatic",
      "b. Only manual",
      "c. Automatic and manual",
      "d. Only Physical"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Automatic and manual"
  },
  {
    "question": "Physical access control system can be controlled by",
    "options": [
      "a. Drop arm barrier",
      "b. Turnstile",
      "c. Frisking",
      "d. Both 'a' & 'b'"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Both 'a' & 'b'"
  },
  {
    "question": "Background checks are conducted",
    "options": [
      "a. To see staff is medically fit",
      "b. To check his police record",
      "c. To check his qualifications",
      "d. To check his residence address"
    ],
    "answer": "b. To check his police record"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a part of Physical access control system",
    "options": [
      "a. Drop arm barrier",
      "b. Turnstile",
      "c. Gates",
      "d. Frisking"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Frisking"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a part of Physical access control system",
    "options": [
      "a. Drop arm barrier",
      "b. Turnstile",
      "c. Person manning entry gate",
      "d. Gates"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Person manning entry gate"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following details will be checked in vehicle permit.",
    "options": [
      "a. Photo",
      "b. Color indicating area",
      "c. Registered number",
      "d. BCAS stamp"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Registered number"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following details will be checked in vehicle permit.",
    "options": [
      "a. Photo",
      "b. Color indicating area",
      "c. Designated access gate to be used",
      "d. BCAS stamp"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Designated access gate to be used"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following details will be checked in vehicle permit.",
    "options": [
      "a. Photo",
      "b. Color indicating area",
      "c. Airside safety status of vehicle",
      "d. BCAS stamp"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Airside safety status of vehicle"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following details will not be checked in vehicle permit.",
    "options": [
      "a. Registered number of vehicle",
      "b. Name of organization",
      "c. Area of validity",
      "d. Color of permit"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Color of permit"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is not mentioned in vehicle permit.",
    "options": [
      "a. Photo",
      "b. Registered number of vehicle",
      "c. Area of validity",
      "d. Period of validity"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Photo"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is not mentioned in vehicle permit",
    "options": [
      "a. Color indicating area",
      "b. Registered number of vehicle",
      "c. Area of validity",
      "d. Period of validity"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Color indicating area"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is not mentioned in vehicle permit",
    "options": [
      "a. Registered number of vehicle",
      "b. BCAS stamp",
      "c. Area of validity",
      "d. Period of validity"
    ],
    "answer": "b. BCAS stamp"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following equipment is used at vehicle check point?",
    "options": [
      "a. Iris recognition",
      "b. Finger printing",
      "c. Drop arm barrier",
      "d. Hand Geometry"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Drop arm barrier"
  },
  {
    "question": "Drivers driving at airside are issued with",
    "options": [
      "a. APD",
      "b. ADP",
      "c. ID",
      "d. Passport"
    ],
    "answer": "b. ADP"
  },
  {
    "question": "Vehicle permit is issued by",
    "options": [
      "a. Airport Operators",
      "b. Airline",
      "c. BCAS",
      "d. DGCA"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Airport Operators"
  },
  {
    "question": "ADP is issued by",
    "options": [
      "a. Airport Operators",
      "b. Airline",
      "c. BCAS",
      "d. DGCA"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Airport Operators"
  },
  {
    "question": "What immediate action you will take on the discovery of IED in vehicle",
    "options": [
      "a. Do not allow vehicle to enter airside",
      "b. Throw water",
      "c. Restrain driver",
      "d. Immediately move out of place"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Do not allow vehicle to enter airside"
  },
  {
    "question": "Suspicious object is something",
    "options": [
      "a. Which is not out of place",
      "b. Which should not be there",
      "c. Which can be accounted for",
      "d. Which is claimed by passenger"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Which should not be there"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the coordinator of BTAC",
    "options": [
      "a. Station Manager of airline",
      "b. Air Worthiness Officer",
      "c. Airport Director",
      "d. In charge of BDDS"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Airport Director"
  },
  {
    "question": "List out the AGENCY whose representative is involved to cordon off an aircraft in case of a specific call",
    "options": [
      "a. DGCA",
      "b. ASG/APSU",
      "c. Airline",
      "d. BDDS"
    ],
    "answer": "b. ASG/APSU"
  },
  {
    "question": "A warning where the threat permits identification of a specific target, or where the caller has positively identified himself or the organization involved is",
    "options": [
      "a. Non- specific threat",
      "b. Specific threat",
      "c. Hoax call",
      "d. Bomb Alert"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Specific threat"
  },
  {
    "question": "What time is the bomb set to explode’ is the question asked to the caller of bomb threat to know",
    "options": [
      "a. What type of device is it",
      "b. How much time is available in hand before the bomb explodes",
      "c. Whether the bomb was placed in the day or at night",
      "d. Who must have placed the bomb"
    ],
    "answer": "b. How much time is available in hand before the bomb explodes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where is the bomb placed?’ is the question asked to caller of bomb threat to know",
    "options": [
      "a. What type of device is it",
      "b. What is the time left",
      "c. Who placed the device",
      "d. Exact location of the bomb"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Exact location of the bomb"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of device is it ?’ is the question asked to the caller of the bomb threat to know",
    "options": [
      "a. What type of switch and explosive is used",
      "b. What is the time left for the bomb to explode",
      "c. Who must have placed the device",
      "d. Where it is placed"
    ],
    "answer": "a. What type of switch and explosive is used"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does it look like?’ is the question asked to the caller of Bomb threat to",
    "options": [
      "a. Help know how much time is left for explosion",
      "b. Help searches in Identification of the device",
      "c. Know who must have placed it",
      "d. Know what kind of mechanism it uses"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Help searches in Identification of the device"
  },
  {
    "question": "What information must be reported by the recipient of a bomb threat call to the authorities",
    "options": [
      "a. Background noise",
      "b. Brief discussion verbally",
      "c. Actual word",
      "d. Both 'a' & 'c'"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Both 'a' & 'c'"
  },
  {
    "question": "What information must be reported by the recipient of a bomb threat call to the authorities",
    "options": [
      "a. Any time of call",
      "b. Average age",
      "c. No need of actual word",
      "d. Any place of call"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Any time of call"
  },
  {
    "question": "A warning that can be related to one or more targets but where there is doubt about its credibility or about the effectiveness of existing countermeasures",
    "options": [
      "a. Specific Threat",
      "b. Non specific Threat",
      "c. Amber Threat",
      "d. Both 'b' & 'c'"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Both 'b' & 'c'"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is not the member of BTAC",
    "options": [
      "a. APD",
      "b. Commandant of ASG",
      "c. Local police",
      "d. BDDS"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Local police"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is not the member of BTAC",
    "options": [
      "a. APD",
      "b. Commandant of ASG",
      "c. Emergency service people",
      "d. BDDS"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Emergency service people"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is not the member of BTAC",
    "options": [
      "a. APD",
      "b. Commandant of ASG",
      "c. Diplomatic representative",
      "d. DGCA"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Diplomatic representative"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is not the member of BTAC",
    "options": [
      "a. APD",
      "b. Commandant of ASG",
      "c. BDDS",
      "d. Cargo manager"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Cargo manager"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following action will be taken in case of specific bomb threat call",
    "options": [
      "a. Aircraft to be taken to isolated bay",
      "b. Inform passenger to remain seated in the aircraft",
      "c. Passengers to deplane without hand baggage",
      "d. Do not offload catering"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Aircraft to be taken to isolated bay"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following action will be taken in case of specific bomb threat call",
    "options": [
      "a. Aircraft will stay at normal parking bay",
      "b. Inform passenger to remain seated in the aircraft",
      "c. Aircraft will be taken to isolated parking bay and cordoned off",
      "d. Do not offload registered baggage"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Aircraft will be taken to isolated parking bay and cordoned off"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following action will be taken in case of specific bomb threat call",
    "options": [
      "a. Aircraft will stay at normal parking bay",
      "b. Cargo, mail, registered bag to be offloaded and checked",
      "c. Cargo, mail, registered bag will not be offloaded",
      "d. Catering will be checked inside the aircraft by security"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Cargo, mail, registered bag to be offloaded and checked"
  }
]
    },
     {
        set: 8,
        questions:[
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following action will be taken in case of specific bomb threat",
    "options": [
      "a. All registered baggage will be offloaded and taken to BMA",
      "b. All registered baggage will be offloaded and taken to terminal building for re screening",
      "c. Registered bags will not be offloaded",
      "d. Registered bags will be offloaded and kept 100mtr away from aircraft"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Registered bags will be offloaded and kept 100mtr away from aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "In case of specific threat agencies carrying out search will sign a completion certificate and forward it to __________ to get clearance for aircraft to take off",
    "options": [
      "a. CASO",
      "b. COSCA",
      "c. ATC",
      "d. BDDS"
    ],
    "answer": "c. ATC"
  },
  {
    "question": "In case of non specific call",
    "options": [
      "a. Aircraft to be taken to isolated bay",
      "b. Aircraft to remain at its normal parking bay",
      "c. Aircraft to be taken to taxiways",
      "d. Aircraft to be taken to runway"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Aircraft to remain at its normal parking bay"
  },
  {
    "question": "In case of non specific call",
    "options": [
      "a. Aircraft to be checked by BDDS",
      "b. Aircraft to be checked by dog squad",
      "c. Aircraft to be checked by airlines security, airlines engineer",
      "d. Aircraft to be checked by CISF and airline security"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Aircraft to be checked by airlines security, airlines engineer"
  },
  {
    "question": "Open windows on the discovery of suspicious object, to reduce the impact of explosion",
    "options": [
      "a. ensure passengers can evacuate through windows as well",
      "b. allow BDDS to enter through any window",
      "c. throw the package out of the window or door",
      "d. to reduce the impact of explosion"
    ],
    "answer": "d. to reduce the impact of explosion"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following you will follow on the identification of suspicious object",
    "options": [
      "a. Submerge package in the water",
      "b. Close all windows and doors",
      "c. Place sand bags around the package",
      "d. Open package"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Place sand bags around the package"
  },
  {
    "question": "In case of specific threat to terminal building which one of the following is not correct",
    "options": [
      "a. Coordinator to make announcement on PA system to evacuate",
      "b. Passengers will remain in terminal building",
      "c. Coordinator will ensure to switch off ac",
      "d. Coordinator will ensure to open emergency door"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Passengers will remain in terminal building"
  },
  {
    "question": "In case of specific threat to terminal building which one of the following is correct",
    "options": [
      "a. Staff and passengers both will evacuate terminal building",
      "b. Passengers to evacuate terminal building but not staff",
      "c. Passengers in SHA will not evacuate terminal building",
      "d. All Passengers from the terminal building will be taken to the apron"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Staff and passengers both will evacuate terminal building"
  },
  {
    "question": "In case of specific threat to terminal building which one of the following is not correct",
    "options": [
      "a. All the staff will evacuate terminal building",
      "b. Passengers will evacuate terminal building along with their hand bags",
      "c. While evacuating passengers will not carry their belonging",
      "d. The air conditioning units of your offices should be switched off"
    ],
    "answer": "c. While evacuating passengers will not carry their belonging"
  },
  {
    "question": "In case of specific threat to terminal building which one of the following is not correct",
    "options": [
      "a. The air conditioning units of your offices should be switched off",
      "b. Passengers will evacuate terminal building along with their hand bags",
      "c. Coordinator will ensure to open emergency door",
      "d. Staff will not carry their belonging while evacuating"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Staff will not carry their belonging while evacuating"
  },
  {
    "question": "In case of non specific threat to terminal building which of the following is true",
    "options": [
      "a. Evacuation of building is not required",
      "b. Evacuation of building is required",
      "c. All passengers except ones in SHA should be evacuated",
      "d. Evacuation of only passenger is required, staff will not leave office"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Evacuation of building is not required"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a counter measure to reduce hoax bomb call incidents at airport",
    "options": [
      "a. Pre-embarkation security check",
      "b. Perimeter wall around the airport",
      "c. Installation of caller ID",
      "d. QRT’s"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Installation of caller ID"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a counter measure to reduce bomb incidents at the airport",
    "options": [
      "a. Pre-embarkation security check",
      "b. Perimeter wall around the airport",
      "c. Give wide publicity in local newspaper if caller is identified",
      "d. QRT’s"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Give wide publicity in local newspaper if caller is identified"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a counter measure for bomb threat incidents at the airport",
    "options": [
      "a. Using sniffer dogs to identify explosive in the baggage",
      "b. Access control of the aircraft",
      "c. QRT's",
      "d. Prompt evaluation of call with the help of BWAF"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Prompt evaluation of call with the help of BWAF"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a counter measure for bomb threat incidents at the airport",
    "options": [
      "a. Introduction of Sky marshals on the aircraft",
      "b. Access control of the aircraft",
      "c. QRT’s",
      "d. Effective training of staff"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Effective training of staff"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is true for a Non specific threat call where all passengers had boarded the aircraft",
    "options": [
      "a. All passengers and their hand baggage have to undergo security checks again at SHA",
      "b. No additional checks will be carried out on passengers",
      "c. Only hand bags of passengers will be rechecked",
      "d. Only registered bags of passengers will be rechecked"
    ],
    "answer": "a. All passengers and their hand baggage have to undergo security checks again at SHA"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a counter measures to tackle bomb threat incidents at airport",
    "options": [
      "a. Introduction of Sky marshals on the aircraft",
      "b. Conduct periodical mock up exercise",
      "c. Installing watch towers around the perimeter",
      "d. Patrolling around the perimeter"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Conduct periodical mock up exercise"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a counter measures to tackle bomb threat incidents at airport",
    "options": [
      "a. Introduction of Sky marshals on the aircraft",
      "b. Up gradation of EDS and EDDS",
      "c. Installing watch towers around the perimeter",
      "d. Patrolling around the perimeter"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Up gradation of EDS and EDDS"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is not a counter measures for bomb incidents taken at airport",
    "options": [
      "a. CCTV",
      "b. Installation of EVD / ETD",
      "c. Conducting periodic mock up exercise",
      "d. Catering Security"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Catering Security"
  },
  {
    "question": "In case of a specific bomb call search of aircraft will be conducted by",
    "options": [
      "a. Bomb squad",
      "b. Airline engineer",
      "c. Airline security",
      "d. NSG"
    ],
    "answer": "d. NSG"
  },
  {
    "question": "In case of a specific bomb call which agency which one of the following will not be involved in search of aircraft",
    "options": [
      "a. Bomb squad",
      "b. Representative from CISF",
      "c. Security Officer of airline",
      "d. Watch Supervisory Officer"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Watch Supervisory Officer"
  },
  {
    "question": "The recipient of bomb threat call should try and hear background sounds because it will help",
    "options": [
      "a. To get an idea of age of the caller",
      "b. in recognizing the caller",
      "c. in getting an idea of the location from where call was made",
      "d. in understanding the motive of the caller"
    ],
    "answer": "c. in getting an idea of the location from where call was made"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is applicable while searching for a Suspect article",
    "options": [
      "a. Use minimum 2 searchers per room of size 250 sq ft",
      "b. Use maximum 2 searchers per room of size 250 sq ft",
      "c. Use maximum 3 searchers per room",
      "d. Use maximum searchers per room"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Use maximum 2 searchers per room of size 250 sq ft"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Basic Search Rule specifies",
    "options": [
      "a. Searchers should be used in alternate rooms",
      "b. Searchers should be used in adjacent rooms",
      "c. Use at least 04 searchers per room",
      "d. Suspect device should be immediately moved to safe location"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Searchers should be used in alternate rooms"
  },
  {
    "question": "Search area should be divided into which three levels while searching for a suspect device",
    "options": [
      "a. Floor to head, head to waist, waist to celing",
      "b. Ceiling to waist, waist to head, head to floor",
      "c. Waist to floor, floor to head, head to ceiling",
      "d. Floor to waist, waist to head, head to ceiling"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Floor to waist, waist to head, head to ceiling"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not applicable for unclaimed article",
    "options": [
      "a. It is treated as a potential bomb",
      "b. It will not be touched",
      "c. It will be immediately taken to the local police station",
      "d. It should not be opened"
    ],
    "answer": "c. It will be immediately taken to the local police station"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not the correct way to handle an unclaimed article",
    "options": [
      "a. It is treated as a potential bomb",
      "b. It will not be touched",
      "c. A safe distance should be maintained from it",
      "d. It should be opened to check if owner can be traced"
    ],
    "answer": "d. It should be opened to check if owner can be traced"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following action is implemented immediately after a bomb threat call is received for an aircraft where boarding has completed but BTAC decision is awaited ?",
    "options": [
      "a. Immediately disembark all passengers who have boarded along with their hand baggage and shift aircraft to isolated bay",
      "b. Immediately disembark all passengers who have boarded along with their hand baggage and keep aircraft ready to be shifted to isolated bay",
      "c. Immediately disembark all passengers who have boarded but leave hand bags in the aircraft itself",
      "d. Do not take any action till BTAC decision is communicated"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Immediately disembark all passengers who have boarded along with their hand baggage and keep aircraft ready to be shifted to isolated bay"
  },
  {
    "question": "The recipient of bomb threat call should try to prolong the call because it will",
    "options": [
      "a. Help to get an idea of age of the caller",
      "b. Be useful in recognizing the caller",
      "c. Help in tracing the call",
      "d. Useful for Identification"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Help in tracing the call"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is true in case of a bomb threat",
    "options": [
      "a. Most bomb threats are preceded by warnings",
      "b. Most of the bomb threats are declared as specific threats",
      "c. Most of the bomb threats are hoax in nature",
      "d. Bomb threats should not be taken too seriously"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Most of the bomb threats are hoax in nature"
  },
  {
    "question": "A passenger who reports for check in after bomb threat call has been received for the flight on which he is travelling, is immediately referred to the APSU/ASG because",
    "options": [
      "a. This passenger could have been responsible for making the threat call",
      "b. All passengers traveling on that flight have to be handed over to APSU/ASG, hence he should also be referred",
      "c. He could have checked in the bag containing the bomb",
      "d. This passenger could be a VIP as he has reported at the last minute"
    ],
    "answer": "a. This passenger could have been responsible for making the threat call"
  },
  {
    "question": "You are allocated at remote bay guarding grounded aircraft and you received news that bomb exploded in terminal building, what action you will take.",
    "options": [
      "a. Immediately run out of airport",
      "b. Immediately rush to terminal building to see the damage and check if your help is required",
      "c. You will be extra alert and vigilant at the aircraft and conduct periodical checks of aircraft",
      "d. As airport targeted, you will call security in charge to send CISF to man the aircraft and to relieve you at the earliest"
    ],
    "answer": "c. You will be extra alert and vigilant at the aircraft and conduct periodical checks of aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "Principles of airport protection is based on",
    "options": [
      "a. Not Controlling movement of people and vehicle",
      "b. Divide airport into restricted and non restricted area",
      "c. Not Protecting airport with physical barrier",
      "d. Not preventing Airport boundary"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Divide airport into restricted and non restricted area"
  },
  {
    "question": "Principles of airport protection is based on",
    "options": [
      "a. Preventing penetration of airport boundary",
      "b. No division of airport into restricted and non restricted area",
      "c. Not protecting airport with physical barrier",
      "d. Not Controlling movement of people and vehicle"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Preventing penetration of airport boundary"
  },
  {
    "question": "Restricted and non- restricted area separation is achieved by",
    "options": [
      "a. Guards",
      "b. Use of building",
      "c. Watch Tower",
      "d. Patrols"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Use of building"
  },
  {
    "question": "Security integrity of barriers at airport is maintained by",
    "options": [
      "a. Security guards not protecting access control point",
      "b. Security personnel carrying out foot patrol",
      "c. Surveillance",
      "d. Both 'b' & 'c'"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Both 'b' & 'c'"
  },
  {
    "question": "Outer ring of airport is protected by",
    "options": [
      "a. Fencing",
      "b. Lighting",
      "c. Guarding aircraft",
      "d. Both 'a' & 'b'"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Both 'a' & 'b'"
  },
  {
    "question": "Outer ring of airport is protected by",
    "options": [
      "a. Pre embarkation checks",
      "b. Lighting",
      "c. Secondary checks",
      "d. Anti sabotage check of aircraft"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Lighting"
  },
  {
    "question": "Outer ring of airport is protected by",
    "options": [
      "a. Pre embarkation checks",
      "b. Fencing",
      "c. Secondary checks",
      "d. Apron Guarding"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Fencing"
  },
  {
    "question": "Outer ring of airport is protected by",
    "options": [
      "a. Pre embarkation checks",
      "b. Alarms",
      "c. Secondary checks",
      "d. Securing SHA"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Alarms"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which facilities or locations will be protected by outer ring",
    "options": [
      "a. Perimeter",
      "b. ATC",
      "c. SHA",
      "d. Aircraft"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Perimeter"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which facilities or locations will be protected by outer ring",
    "options": [
      "a. Access gate of terminal building",
      "b. Aircraft",
      "c. SHA",
      "d. ATC"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Access gate of terminal building"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which facilities or locations will be protected by outer ring",
    "options": [
      "a. ATC",
      "b. Aircraft",
      "c. SHA",
      "d. Access gate for vehicle"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Access gate for vehicle"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which facilities or locations will be protected by middle ring",
    "options": [
      "a. Exterior of building",
      "b. ATC",
      "c. Access gate",
      "d. Aircraft"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Exterior of building"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which facilities or locations will be protected by middle ring",
    "options": [
      "a. Apron",
      "b. ATC",
      "c. Access gate",
      "d. Aircraft"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Apron"
  },
  {
    "question": "Objective of physical barrier is to",
    "options": [
      "a. Stop unlawful seizure of aircraft",
      "b. Control crowding of people in an area",
      "c. Protect defined area",
      "d. Hold a deportee till the time his flight boarding is announced"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Protect defined area"
  },
  {
    "question": "Objective of physical barrier",
    "options": [
      "a. Stop unlawful seizure of aircraft",
      "b. Control crowding of people in an area",
      "c. Hold a deportee till the time his flight boarding is announced",
      "d. Create physical and psychological deterrent"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Create physical and psychological deterrent"
  },
  {
    "question": "Objective of physical barrier",
    "options": [
      "a. Stop unlawful seizure of aircraft",
      "b. Control crowding of people in an area",
      "c. Hold a deportee till the time his flight boarding is announced",
      "d. Delay intrusion and assist detection"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Delay intrusion and assist detection"
  },
  {
    "question": "Objective of security guarding is to",
    "options": [
      "a. Protect vulnerable areas",
      "b. Have free movement of people/ vehicle",
      "c. Deter and prevent attack",
      "d. Both 'a' & 'c'"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Both 'a' & 'c'"
  },
  {
    "question": "Objective of security patrolling is to",
    "options": [
      "a. Deter and prevent unauthorized access",
      "b. Detect unauthorized access",
      "c. Prevent lawful activity",
      "d. Both 'a' & 'b'"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Both 'a' & 'b'"
  }
]
    },
     {
        set: 9,
        questions:[
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the sign of interference or attempted unauthorized access",
    "options": [
      "a. False alarm given by security equipment",
      "b. Power failure at airport",
      "c. Broken doors",
      "d. False alarm given by HHMD"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Broken doors"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the sign of interference or attempted unauthorized access",
    "options": [
      "a. False alarm given by security equipment",
      "b. Power failure at airport",
      "c. Broken boundary",
      "d. False alarm given by HHMD"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Broken boundary"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the sign of interference or attempted unauthorized access",
    "options": [
      "a. False alarm given by security equipment",
      "b. Power failure at airport",
      "c. Broken window",
      "d. False alarm given by HHMD"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Broken window"
  },
  {
    "question": "Patrolling can be by __________",
    "options": [
      "a. Watch tower",
      "b. Foot",
      "c. Control room",
      "d. Using CCTV cameras"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Foot"
  },
  {
    "question": "Patrolling can be by __________",
    "options": [
      "a. Watch tower",
      "b. Foot",
      "c. Control room",
      "d. Access Control"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Foot"
  },
  {
    "question": "Patrolling can be by __________",
    "options": [
      "a. Watch tower",
      "b. Using vehicle",
      "c. Control room",
      "d. Using CCTV cameras"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Using vehicle"
  },
  {
    "question": "The abbreviation HHMD stands for?",
    "options": [
      "a. Hand Held Man Detector",
      "b. Hand Held Metal Detector",
      "c. Hand Held Metal Detection",
      "d. Hand Held Man Detection"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Hand Held Metal Detector"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following equipment is used to screen bags",
    "options": [
      "a. Body scanners",
      "b. HHMD",
      "c. X-BIS",
      "d. DFMD"
    ],
    "answer": "c. X-BIS"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following equipment is used to screen bags",
    "options": [
      "a. Body scanners",
      "b. HHMD",
      "c. EVD",
      "d. DFMD"
    ],
    "answer": "c. EVD"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following equipment is used to screen bags",
    "options": [
      "a. Body scanners",
      "b. HHMD",
      "c. ETD",
      "d. DFMD"
    ],
    "answer": "c. ETD"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statement is incorrect",
    "options": [
      "a. Do not place HHMD on wet surface",
      "b. Do not hold or swing HHMD by the head",
      "c. Do not use HHMD it as a hammer",
      "d. Do not hold HHMD away from body, it should always touch the area to be checked"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Do not hold HHMD away from body, it should always touch the area to be checked"
  },
  {
    "question": "Check that the battery is fully charged is applicable to which equipment",
    "options": [
      "a. DFMD",
      "b. HHMD",
      "c. X-BIS",
      "d. OTP"
    ],
    "answer": "b. HHMD"
  },
  {
    "question": "Before checking passenger with HHMD",
    "options": [
      "a. He should remove all metallic objects except cell phone",
      "b. He has to remove all metallic objects",
      "c. He should remove all metallic objects except coins",
      "d. He should remove his shoes"
    ],
    "answer": "b. He has to remove all metallic objects"
  },
  {
    "question": "Hold HHMD at the distance of ___________ from passenger body",
    "options": [
      "a. 2.5cm",
      "b. 2.5 inches",
      "c. 5 cm",
      "d. 5 cm"
    ],
    "answer": "a. 2.5cm"
  },
  {
    "question": "HHMD cannot detect",
    "options": [
      "a. Metal of 10gms",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Steel pens",
      "d. Coins"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Explosives"
  },
  {
    "question": "HHMD cannot detect",
    "options": [
      "a. Metal of 10gms",
      "b. Guns made of non metallic material",
      "c. Steel pens",
      "d. Coins"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Guns made of non metallic material"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is portable",
    "options": [
      "a. DFMD",
      "b. X-BIS",
      "c. HHMD",
      "d. CTX"
    ],
    "answer": "c. HHMD"
  },
  {
    "question": "The size of OTP is",
    "options": [
      "a. 10X10 cm",
      "b. 20X20 cm",
      "c. 05X05 cm",
      "d. 10X10 inches"
    ],
    "answer": "a. 10X10 cm"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the part of DFMD",
    "options": [
      "a. Receptor",
      "b. Inverse panel",
      "c. Receiver panel",
      "d. Sampling unit"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Receiver panel"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the part of DFMD",
    "options": [
      "a. Cross Piece",
      "b. Generator",
      "c. Sampling unit",
      "d. Inverter"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Cross Piece"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the part of DFMD",
    "options": [
      "a. Electronics unit",
      "b. Sampling unit",
      "c. Analysis unit",
      "d. Generator"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Electronics unit"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the part of DFMD",
    "options": [
      "a. Electronic unit",
      "b. Cross Piece",
      "c. Sampling unit",
      "d. Both 'a' & 'b'"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Both 'a' & 'b'"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following will be screened at passenger screening station",
    "options": [
      "a. Physically challenged person",
      "b. Vehicles",
      "c. Pregnant lady",
      "d. Both 'a' & 'c'"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Both 'a' & 'c'"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the passenger is not ready to get frisked then",
    "options": [
      "a. Only allow him to pass through DFMD",
      "b. If he is frequent flier allow him without checks",
      "c. Deny boarding",
      "d. Ask questions and allow to board the aircraft"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Deny boarding"
  },
  {
    "question": "While checking passenger, HHMD alarms it indicates",
    "options": [
      "a. Faulty equipment",
      "b. Passenger is clear",
      "c. He is carrying metal",
      "d. He is carrying explosive material"
    ],
    "answer": "d. He is carrying explosive material"
  },
  {
    "question": "The abbreviation DFMD stands for?",
    "options": [
      "a. Door Frame Man Detector",
      "b. Door Frame Main Detector",
      "c. Door Frame Metal Detector",
      "d. Door Frame Material Detector"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Door Frame Metal Detector"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which is the equipment used for screening for Bags?",
    "options": [
      "a. HHMD",
      "b. DFMD",
      "c. X-BIS",
      "d. WTMD"
    ],
    "answer": "c. X-BIS"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which is the equipment used for screening for Bags?",
    "options": [
      "a. AMD",
      "b. DFMD",
      "c. EVD",
      "d. WTMD"
    ],
    "answer": "c. EVD"
  },
  {
    "question": "HHMD is used to detect?",
    "options": [
      "a. Non-metallic material",
      "b. Metallic items on a person’s body",
      "c. Replicas of weapons made of non-metallic material",
      "d. Drugs"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Metallic items on a person’s body"
  },
  {
    "question": "The HHMD should be capable of detecting a minimum of …….. metals ?",
    "options": [
      "a. 2.5gms",
      "b. 5gms",
      "c. 0.5gms",
      "d. 50gms"
    ],
    "answer": "c. 0.5gms"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of these is not a pre operational check of HHMD?",
    "options": [
      "a. The metal detector should be tested before use",
      "b. Frisk the passenger with the HHMD by keeping it 2.5 cm away from his body",
      "c. Check that the battery is fully charged",
      "d. Adjust the audio control knob as necessary"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Frisk the passenger with the HHMD by keeping it 2.5 cm away from his body"
  },
  {
    "question": "HHMD is safe for ……….. And ………..?",
    "options": [
      "a. Metals, Pacemakers",
      "b. Pacemakers, non-metallic material",
      "c. Pacemakers, Pregnant Women",
      "d. Weapons, Drugs"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Pacemakers, Pregnant Women"
  },
  {
    "question": "DFMD is safe for ……….. And ………..?",
    "options": [
      "a. Metals, Pacemakers",
      "b. Pacemakers, non-metallic material",
      "c. Pacemakers, Pregnant Woman's",
      "d. Weapons, Drugs"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Pacemakers, Pregnant Woman's"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of these is not an advantage of HHMD",
    "options": [
      "a. It may malfunction",
      "b. Easy to use",
      "c. Touch free checks for passengers",
      "d. Low Cost"
    ],
    "answer": "a. It may malfunction"
  },
  {
    "question": "The dimension of DFMD is?",
    "options": [
      "a. 2meters x 0.75 to 0.85 meters",
      "b. 3meters x 0.70 to 0.80 meters",
      "c. 2meters x 0.7 to 0.8 meters",
      "d. 3meters x 0.75 to 0.85 meters"
    ],
    "answer": "a. 2meters x 0.75 to 0.85 meters"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of these is a part of DFMD?",
    "options": [
      "a. Transmitter Unit",
      "b. Transmitter Piece",
      "c. Transmitter Control",
      "d. Transmitter Panel"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Transmitter Panel"
  },
  {
    "question": "DFMD is used to detect metallic items on person’s body which is of ?",
    "options": [
      "a. 30gms and below",
      "b. 0.30gms",
      "c. 30gms and above",
      "d. .5gms"
    ],
    "answer": "c. 30gms and above"
  },
  {
    "question": "Distance between 02 passengers passing through DFMD should be?",
    "options": [
      "a. 3 meters",
      "b. 3 feet",
      "c. 30cms",
      "d. 30 feet"
    ],
    "answer": "b. 3 feet"
  },
  {
    "question": "DFMD has ______ overlapping zones?",
    "options": [
      "a. 6",
      "b. 8",
      "c. 10",
      "d. 12"
    ],
    "answer": "b. 8"
  },
  {
    "question": "DFMD gives ______ and _____ alarm",
    "options": [
      "a. Video, audio",
      "b. Visual, LED",
      "c. Audio, visual",
      "d. Audio, beep"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Audio, visual"
  },
  {
    "question": "DFMD and HHMD gives an ______ and _____ alarm",
    "options": [
      "a. Video, audio",
      "b. Visual, LED",
      "c. Audio, visual",
      "d. Audio, beep"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Audio, visual"
  },
  {
    "question": "Distance between two passengers while passing through DFMD is",
    "options": [
      "a. 3mtr",
      "b. 3 ft",
      "c. 3 cm",
      "d. 3 mm"
    ],
    "answer": "b. 3 ft"
  },
  {
    "question": "With OTP staff should pass _______ times through DFMD for pre operational checks",
    "options": [
      "a. 10 Time",
      "b. 20 Time",
      "c. 05 Time",
      "d. 8 Time"
    ],
    "answer": "a. 10 Time"
  },
  {
    "question": "DFMD works on which principle",
    "options": [
      "a. Infrared",
      "b. Radio transmission",
      "c. Electromagnetic",
      "d. Audio visual"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Electromagnetic"
  },
  {
    "question": "HHMD works on which principle",
    "options": [
      "a. Infrared",
      "b. Radio transmission",
      "c. Electromagnetic",
      "d. Audio visual"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Electromagnetic"
  },
  {
    "question": "DFMD cannot detect",
    "options": [
      "a. Metal of 40gms",
      "b. Explosives",
      "c. Steel",
      "d. Mobile phone"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Explosives"
  },
  {
    "question": "In normal situation not more than ___________ LED’s should be illuminating when nobody is passing through the DFMD",
    "options": [
      "a. 02.Jan",
      "b. 05.Apr",
      "c. 06.Mai",
      "d. 07.Jun"
    ],
    "answer": "a. 02.Jan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Red light illuminates on the control panel of DFMD, indicates passenger is carrying",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapon",
      "b. Explosive",
      "c. Alarming quantity of metal",
      "d. Dangerous article"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Alarming quantity of metal"
  },
  {
    "question": "Everyone will be screened at screening station except",
    "options": [
      "a. Staff",
      "b. Women",
      "c. Children",
      "d. Person under Exempted category"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Person under Exempted category"
  },
  {
    "question": "The different colours that we see on the X-ray monitor are due to",
    "options": [
      "a. Atomic number",
      "b. Weight",
      "c. Density",
      "d. Both 'a' & 'c'"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Both 'a' & 'c'"
  }
]
    },
     {
        set: 10,
        questions: [
  {
    "question": "Emergency switch off button of x-ray is used during which of the following emergency",
    "options": [
      "a. Discovery of Prohibited article",
      "b. Fire",
      "c. Discovery of Gun",
      "d. Discovery of Knife"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Fire"
  },
  {
    "question": "Brightness and contrast control buttons of X-ray is located on",
    "options": [
      "a. Key board of x-ray",
      "b. Monitor",
      "c. Tunnel",
      "d. External Panels"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Monitor"
  },
  {
    "question": "On the discovery of undeclared weapon at x-ray what question will be asked to passenger by screener",
    "options": [
      "a. Are you carrying any prohibited article",
      "b. Is there any metal in your bag",
      "c. What are the contents of your bag",
      "d. Are you carrying any weapon"
    ],
    "answer": "c. What are the contents of your bag"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a CTX machine which of the following true for the generator",
    "options": [
      "a. Moves around the bag",
      "b. Position is fixed",
      "c. Four generators are available which are fixed",
      "d. Six generators ar available which are fixed"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Moves around the bag"
  },
  {
    "question": "While screening bag if liquid is spilled on conveyor belt",
    "options": [
      "a. Stop conveyor belt",
      "b. Use emergency stop button",
      "c. Stop conveyor and wipe liquid",
      "d. Immediately try to pull container out of tunnel"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Stop conveyor and wipe liquid"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is true for a Top Down Beamer as compared to Down Top Beamer or Side beamer ?",
    "options": [
      "a. High Conveyor belt",
      "b. Difficult to handle bulky bags",
      "c. Machine requires huge amount of space",
      "d. Low conveyor belt"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Low conveyor belt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is true for a Top Down Beamer as compared to Down Top Beamer or Side beamer",
    "options": [
      "a. High Conveyor belt",
      "b. Difficult to handle bulky bags",
      "c. Space saving design",
      "d. Machine requires huge amount of space"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Space saving design"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is true for a Top Down Beamer as compared to Down Top Beamer or Side beamer",
    "options": [
      "a. High Conveyor belt",
      "b. Difficult to handle bulky bags",
      "c. Machine requires huge amount of space",
      "d. Easy to handle bulky bags"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Easy to handle bulky bags"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is true for a Top Down Beamer as compared to Down Top Beamer or Side beamer",
    "options": [
      "a. High Conveyor belt",
      "b. Difficult to handle bulky bags",
      "c. Machine requires huge amount of space",
      "d. Performance limitation"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Performance limitation"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is true for a Top Down Beamer as compared to Down Top Beamer or Side beamer",
    "options": [
      "a. High Conveyor belt",
      "b. Easy to handle bulky bags",
      "c. Machine requires huge amount of space",
      "d. Performance limitation"
    ],
    "answer": "a. High Conveyor belt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is true for a Top Down Beamer as compared to Down Top Beamer or Side beamer",
    "options": [
      "a. Difficult to handle bulky bags",
      "b. Easy to handle bulky bags",
      "c. Machine requires huge amount of space",
      "d. Performance limitation"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Difficult to handle bulky bags"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is true for a Top Down Beamer as compared to Down Top Beamer or Side beamer",
    "options": [
      "a. High Performance machine",
      "b. Easy to handle bulky bags",
      "c. Machine requires huge amount of space",
      "d. Performance limitation"
    ],
    "answer": "a. High Performance machine"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is true for a Top Down Beamer as compared to Down Top Beamer or Side beamer",
    "options": [
      "a. Space saving design",
      "b. Easy to handle bulky bags",
      "c. Machine requires huge amount of space",
      "d. Performance limitation"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Space saving design"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is true for a Top Down Beamer as compared to Down Top Beamer or Side beamer",
    "options": [
      "a. Magnification of objects",
      "b. Machine requires huge amount of space",
      "c. Easy to handle bulky bags",
      "d. Performance limitation"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Magnification of objects"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is true for a Top Down Beamer as compared to Down Top Beamer or Side beamer",
    "options": [
      "a. Low conveyor belt",
      "b. Difficult to handle bulky bags",
      "c. Space saving design",
      "d. Low Performance"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Low conveyor belt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is true for a Top Down Beamer as compared to Down Top Beamer or Side beamer",
    "options": [
      "a. Bags may topple and fall while conveyor moves",
      "b. Difficult to handle bulky bags",
      "c. Space saving design",
      "d. Low Performance"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Bags may topple and fall while conveyor moves"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is true for a Top Down Beamer as compared to Down Top Beamer or Side beamer",
    "options": [
      "a. Low conveyor belt",
      "b. Difficult to handle bulky bags",
      "c. Space saving design",
      "d. Low Performance"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Low conveyor belt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is true for a Top Down Beamer as compared to Down Top Beamer or Side beamer",
    "options": [
      "a. High performance",
      "b. Difficult to handle bulky bags",
      "c. Space saving design",
      "d. Low Performance"
    ],
    "answer": "a. High performance"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is true for a Top Down Beamer as compared to Down Top Beamer or Side beamer",
    "options": [
      "a. Machine occupies large amount of space",
      "b. Difficult to handle bulky bags",
      "c. Space saving design",
      "d. Low Performance"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Machine occupies large amount of space"
  },
  {
    "question": "One of the reasons why X-ray BIS is film safe is",
    "options": [
      "a. Interlocks",
      "b. Integrated image device",
      "c. Fan beam X-ray geometry",
      "d. High detection rate"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Fan beam X-ray geometry"
  },
  {
    "question": "One of the reasons why X-ray BIS is film safe is",
    "options": [
      "a. Interlocks",
      "b. Integrated image device",
      "c. Low false alarm rate",
      "d. Conveyor belt is constantly moving"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Conveyor belt is constantly moving"
  },
  {
    "question": "One of the reasons why X-ray BIS is film safe is",
    "options": [
      "a. Integrated image device",
      "b. X-ray dosage is low",
      "c. Interlocks",
      "d. High detection rate"
    ],
    "answer": "b. X-ray dosage is low"
  },
  {
    "question": "Lead is seen in Black colour because",
    "options": [
      "a. X-rays fully penetrate through lead",
      "b. All X-rays are absorbed by lead",
      "c. X-rays have partly penetrated lead",
      "d. X-rays are deflected by lead"
    ],
    "answer": "b. All X-rays are absorbed by lead"
  },
  {
    "question": "Gun is mostly seen in Black colour because",
    "options": [
      "a. X-rays fully penetrate through gun",
      "b. Most X-rays are absorbed by the gun",
      "c. X-rays have partly penetrated gun",
      "d. X-rays are deflected by gun"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Most X-rays are absorbed by the gun"
  },
  {
    "question": "An element with atomic number 6 will be seen in ______ colour on XBIS monitor ?",
    "options": [
      "a. Orange",
      "b. Green",
      "c. Blue",
      "d. Black"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Orange"
  },
  {
    "question": "An element with atomic number 9 will be seen in ______ colour on XBIS monitor ?",
    "options": [
      "a. Orange",
      "b. Green",
      "c. Blue",
      "d. Black"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Orange"
  },
  {
    "question": "An element with atomic number 12 will be seen in ______ colour on XBIS monitor ?",
    "options": [
      "a. Orange",
      "b. Green",
      "c. Black",
      "d. Blue"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Green"
  },
  {
    "question": "An element with atomic number 16 will be seen in ______ colour on XBIS monitor ?",
    "options": [
      "a. Orange",
      "b. Green",
      "c. Black",
      "d. Blue"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Green"
  },
  {
    "question": "An element with atomic number 33 will be seen in ______ colour on XBIS monitor ?",
    "options": [
      "a. Orange",
      "b. Green",
      "c. Blue",
      "d. Black"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Blue"
  },
  {
    "question": "An element with atomic number 45 will be seen in ______ colour on XBIS monitor ?",
    "options": [
      "a. Orange",
      "b. Green",
      "c. Blue",
      "d. Black"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Blue"
  },
  {
    "question": "An element with atomic number 74 will be seen in ______ colour on XBIS monitor ?",
    "options": [
      "a. Orange",
      "b. Green",
      "c. Blue",
      "d. Black"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Blue"
  },
  {
    "question": "An element with atomic number 80 will be seen in ______ colour on XBIS monitor ?",
    "options": [
      "a. Orange",
      "b. Black",
      "c. Green",
      "d. Blue"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Black"
  },
  {
    "question": "An element with atomic number 92 will be seen in ______ colour on XBIS monitor ?",
    "options": [
      "a. Orange",
      "b. Black",
      "c. Green",
      "d. Blue"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Black"
  },
  {
    "question": "An element with atomic number 100 will be seen in ______ colour on XBIS monitor ?",
    "options": [
      "a. Orange",
      "b. Black",
      "c. Green",
      "d. Blue"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Black"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which one of the following colors will Lead appear on the X-ray monitor?",
    "options": [
      "a. Green",
      "b. Blue",
      "c. Orange",
      "d. Opaque"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Opaque"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which one of the following colors will Tin appear on the X-ray monitor?",
    "options": [
      "a. Orange",
      "b. Blue",
      "c. Green",
      "d. Opaque"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Blue"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which one of the following colors will copper detonator appear on the X-ray monitor?",
    "options": [
      "a. Blue",
      "b. Orange",
      "c. Opaque",
      "d. Green"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Blue"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which one of the following colors will aluminum detonator appear on the X-ray monitor?",
    "options": [
      "a. Green",
      "b. Opaque",
      "c. Orange",
      "d. Green"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Green"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which one of the following colors will Zinc appear on the X-ray monitor?",
    "options": [
      "a. Green",
      "b. Blue",
      "c. Opaque",
      "d. Orange"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Blue"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following items will appear in Green color on the X-ray monitor?",
    "options": [
      "a. Copper, Silver",
      "b. Glass, Salt",
      "c. Glass, Sugar",
      "d. Copper, Gold"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Glass, Salt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following items will appear in Opaque color on the X-ray monitor?",
    "options": [
      "a. Silver, Lead",
      "b. Gold, Gun",
      "c. Tin, Gold",
      "d. Plastic, Copper"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Gold, Gun"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which one of the following colors will copper detonator appear on the X-ray monitor?",
    "options": [
      "a. Mechanism, Salt",
      "b. Iron, Zinc",
      "c. Glass, Iron",
      "d. Gun, Gold"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Iron, Zinc"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which one of the following colors will copper detonator appear on the X-ray monitor?",
    "options": [
      "a. Gold, Silver",
      "b. Knife, Salt",
      "c. Copper, Tin",
      "d. Wood, Glass"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Copper, Tin"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which one of the following colors will copper detonator appear on the X-ray monitor?",
    "options": [
      "a. Silver, Mechanism used in IED",
      "b. Knife, Wood",
      "c. Gold, Silver",
      "d. Explosive, Iron"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Silver, Mechanism used in IED"
  },
  {
    "question": "Only trained staff can operate x-ray which is the disadvantage of x-ray means",
    "options": [
      "a. Staff who knows how to operate x-ray can operate it",
      "b. Only certified screeners can operate it",
      "c. Staff who has been trained on X-ray simulator can operate it",
      "d. Basic AVSEC qualified staff can operate it"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Only certified screeners can operate it"
  },
  {
    "question": "The requirement of Single wire resolution test is to display 40 SWG wire because",
    "options": [
      "a. X-RAY machine cannot detect more thinner wire than that",
      "b. That is the minimum thickness of wire that would work effectively in an IED",
      "c. This is the thinnest wire",
      "d. This is the thickest wire"
    ],
    "answer": "b. That is the minimum thickness of wire that would work effectively in an IED"
  },
  {
    "question": "In useful penetration wire should be seen under second step of thickness",
    "options": [
      "a. 5/16”",
      "b. 3/16”",
      "c. 7/16”",
      "d. 9/16”"
    ],
    "answer": "a. 5/16”"
  },
  {
    "question": "__________ test defines what thickness of steel the machine should be able to penetrate?",
    "options": [
      "a. Single wire resolution",
      "b. Useful penetration",
      "c. Simple penetration",
      "d. Spatial resolution"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Simple penetration"
  },
  {
    "question": "The requirement of spatial resolution test is that vertical and horizontal grating to be seen which defines",
    "options": [
      "a. The ability of the system to distinguish between closely placed items in a bag",
      "b. Minute wires to be seen",
      "c. XBIS is able to distinguish between items based on atomic numbers",
      "d. The penetrating capacity of XBIS"
    ],
    "answer": "a. The ability of the system to distinguish between closely placed items in a bag"
  },
  {
    "question": "One of the CTP test is not giving correct result, what action you will take",
    "options": [
      "a. It is OK to continue screening bags as the other five tests have given correct results",
      "b. Details should be recorded in log book so that technician can check the machine next time he comes for maintenance work",
      "c. Inform technician and do not use machine for baggage inspection",
      "d. Inform supervisor and screen the bags"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Inform technician and do not use machine for baggage inspection"
  }
]
    },
     {
        set: 11,
        questions:[
  {
    "question": "While screening you discovered human bones in passenger bag, what immediate action you will take",
    "options": [
      "a. Put sticker on bag as it is not prohibited article.",
      "b. Stop x-ray machine using emergency stop button",
      "c. Question guest about the content of the bag and inform supervisor",
      "d. Hand over passenger to police"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Question guest about the content of the bag and inform supervisor"
  },
  {
    "question": "Individual tailored training is the benefit of TIP which means",
    "options": [
      "a. screener receive increased exposure to image of threat items",
      "b. Immediate feedback is received by the individual",
      "c. Training can be provided to staff through identification of his strengths and weakness in detecting prohibited items",
      "d. Supervisor can get feedback of each individual using XBIS"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Training can be provided to staff through identification of his strengths and weakness in detecting prohibited items"
  },
  {
    "question": "On the discovery of drugs in the bag while screening what action will be taken by screener",
    "options": [
      "a. Use emergency stop button",
      "b. Take bag in your custody and inform ASG",
      "c. Put sticker on the bag as it is not prohibited article",
      "d. Ask the passenger to dispose off the drugs and then clear his bag"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Take bag in your custody and inform ASG"
  },
  {
    "question": "In inline X-ray machine Level 1 screening is undertaken by",
    "options": [
      "a. Heimann XBIS",
      "b. Standalone X-ray machine",
      "c. High speed Multi view x-ray machine",
      "d. One dimensional XBIS"
    ],
    "answer": "c. High speed Multi view x-ray machine"
  },
  {
    "question": "In inline X-ray machine Level 2 comprises of",
    "options": [
      "a. Screenwriters",
      "b. Standalone X-ray machine",
      "c. High speed Multi view X-ray machine",
      "d. Explosive detectors"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Screenwriters"
  },
  {
    "question": "Passenger is not ready to open bag for physical search at X-ray machine, what action you will take",
    "options": [
      "a. Inform ASG / APSU",
      "b. Put sticker and allow as bag has passed through XBIS",
      "c. Inform him it is a procedure or else you will offload bag",
      "d. Consider the bag as threat bag and follow SOP"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Inform him it is a procedure or else you will offload bag"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is applicable while conducting physical search of a bag ?",
    "options": [
      "a. Bag is placed in between the passenger and the searcher and no any other passenger should see the contents",
      "b. Only searcher should be able to see the bag",
      "c. In between the passenger and the searcher, it view of other passengers",
      "d. Bag should not be searched in presence of passenger"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Bag is placed in between the passenger and the searcher and no any other passenger should see the contents"
  },
  {
    "question": "Denser the object _________ the image",
    "options": [
      "a. Darker",
      "b. Lighter",
      "c. Thicker",
      "d. Brighter"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Darker"
  },
  {
    "question": "‘XBIS should have a high detection rate’ is _________ Requirement of XBIS",
    "options": [
      "a. Requirement of XBIS",
      "b. Detection Requirement of XBIS",
      "c. Property of X-ray",
      "d. Safety measure of XBIS"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Requirement of XBIS"
  },
  {
    "question": "‘XBIS should be able to distinguish between hazardous and non hazardous item’ is specified under _________",
    "options": [
      "a. Requirement of XBIS",
      "b. Property of X-ray",
      "c. Detection Requirement of XBIS",
      "d. Safety measure of XBIS"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Property of X-ray"
  },
  {
    "question": "‘XBIS should have a low false alarm rate’ is specified under _________",
    "options": [
      "a. Requirement of XBIS",
      "b. Property of X-ray",
      "c. Detection Requirement of XBIS",
      "d. Safety measure of XBIS"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Property of X-ray"
  },
  {
    "question": "‘XBIS should be able to inspect entire bag as well as partial bag areas’ is specified under _________",
    "options": [
      "a. Detection Requirement of XBIS",
      "b. Safety measure of XBIS",
      "c. Property of X-ray",
      "d. Requirement of XBIS"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Requirement of XBIS"
  },
  {
    "question": "‘XBIS should have throughput of 300 bags per hour’ is specified under _________",
    "options": [
      "a. Requirement of XBIS",
      "b. Property of X-ray",
      "c. Detection Requirement of XBIS",
      "d. Safety measure of XBIS"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Requirement of XBIS"
  },
  {
    "question": "‘XBIS should be able detect firearms both metallic and non-metallic’ is specified under _________",
    "options": [
      "a. Requirement of XBIS",
      "b. Property of X-ray",
      "c. Safety measure of XBIS",
      "d. Detection Requirement of XBIS"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Detection Requirement of XBIS"
  },
  {
    "question": "‘XBIS should be able detect firearm components’ is specified under _________",
    "options": [
      "a. Detection Requirement of XBIS",
      "b. Property of X-ray",
      "c. Safety measure of XBIS",
      "d. Requirement of XBIS"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Detection Requirement of XBIS"
  },
  {
    "question": "‘XBIS should be able detect ammunition of all calibers’ is specified under _________",
    "options": [
      "a. Property of X-ray",
      "b. Requirement of XBIS",
      "c. Detection Requirement of XBIS",
      "d. Safety measure of XBIS"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Detection Requirement of XBIS"
  },
  {
    "question": "‘XBIS should be able detect grenades and other fragmentation devices’ is specified under _________",
    "options": [
      "a. Requirement of XBIS",
      "b. Property of X-ray",
      "c. Safety measure of XBIS",
      "d. Detection Requirement of XBIS"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Detection Requirement of XBIS"
  },
  {
    "question": "‘XBIS should be able detect knives, batons, swords’ is specified under _________",
    "options": [
      "a. Property of X-ray",
      "b. Requirement of XBIS",
      "c. Safety measure of XBIS",
      "d. Detection Requirement of XBIS"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Detection Requirement of XBIS"
  },
  {
    "question": "‘XBIS should be able detect detonators’ is specified under _________",
    "options": [
      "a. Requirement of XBIS",
      "b. Property of X-ray",
      "c. Detection Requirement of XBIS",
      "d. Safety measure of XBIS"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Detection Requirement of XBIS"
  },
  {
    "question": "‘XBIS should be able detect timing devices’ is specified under _________",
    "options": [
      "a. Requirement of XBIS",
      "b. Detection Requirement of XBIS",
      "c. Property of X-ray",
      "d. Safety measure of XBIS"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Detection Requirement of XBIS"
  },
  {
    "question": "‘XBIS should be able detect electronic items’ is specified under _________",
    "options": [
      "a. Requirement of XBIS",
      "b. Property of X-ray",
      "c. Detection Requirement of XBIS",
      "d. Safety measure of XBIS"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Detection Requirement of XBIS"
  },
  {
    "question": "‘XBIS should be able detect power sources’ is specified under _________",
    "options": [
      "a. Detection Requirement of XBIS",
      "b. Property of X-ray",
      "c. Requirement of XBIS",
      "d. Safety measure of XBIS"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Detection Requirement of XBIS"
  },
  {
    "question": "Passenger is carrying 10 boxes of undeveloped film which is sealed. He insists X-ray screening will damage film. He is a frequent flyer. What action you will take.",
    "options": [
      "a. Ask passenger to send film by Cargo",
      "b. If possible conduct physical search or else convince him that XBIS will not damage the film and screen it",
      "c. Take undertaking from him that it is not containing any restricted article and accept it.",
      "d. If he is not ready to break seal and conduct physical search then offload"
    ],
    "answer": "b. If possible conduct physical search or else convince him that XBIS will not damage the film and screen it"
  },
  {
    "question": "Passenger is carrying chemicals in his bag, what action you will take",
    "options": [
      "a. Offload bag",
      "b. Ask for documents and check that it is does not fall in category of dangerous goods",
      "c. Re screen the bag",
      "d. Immediately hand over passenger to ASG/APSU"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Ask for documents and check that it is does not fall in category of dangerous goods"
  },
  {
    "question": "The staff who is allocated for physical search of baggage at X-ray machine must be",
    "options": [
      "a. Basic AVSEC qualified",
      "b. Certified screener",
      "c. An experienced staff",
      "d. Expert staff"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Certified screener"
  },
  {
    "question": "After screening of registered bag you saw passenger is moving towards a book shop instead of check-in counter what action you will take",
    "options": [
      "a. You will follow him wherever he goes",
      "b. You will brief passenger to first check-in and then go to book shop",
      "c. Once passenger comes out of book shop you will brief him he should have first done check in",
      "d. Passenger can go anywhere he wishes, you cannot stop him"
    ],
    "answer": "b. You will brief passenger to first check-in and then go to book shop"
  },
  {
    "question": "While searching bag physically you have discovered an electronic equipment which you have never seen before, how you will check",
    "options": [
      "a. Offload the item and dispose it off to avoid confusion",
      "b. Profile the passenger and allow the item to be taken",
      "c. Ask passenger to operate and show. If you are satisfied clear the bag",
      "d. Hand over passenger to CISF"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Ask passenger to operate and show. If you are satisfied clear the bag"
  },
  {
    "question": "In CTX machine bag is x-rayed from over __________ different angles",
    "options": [
      "a. 2",
      "b. 4",
      "c. 500",
      "d. 100"
    ],
    "answer": "c. 500"
  },
  {
    "question": "Denser objects absorb ________ X-rays",
    "options": [
      "a. Less",
      "b. More",
      "c. Very few",
      "d. No Xrays are absorbed"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Very few"
  },
  {
    "question": "The main aim of segregating 10% of screened baggage should be at randomly marked for physical search",
    "options": [
      "a. To keep physical searcher alert",
      "b. It acts as a deterrent",
      "c. Because BCAS circular says so",
      "d. Searcher gets some practice"
    ],
    "answer": "b. It acts as a deterrent"
  },
  {
    "question": "The function of NEG key in Heiman machine is same as ________ key of Rapiscan",
    "options": [
      "a. IM",
      "b. OM",
      "c. INV",
      "d. CC"
    ],
    "answer": "c. INV"
  },
  {
    "question": "The function of O2 key in Heimann machine is same as ______ key of Rapiscan",
    "options": [
      "a. IM",
      "b. OM",
      "c. INV",
      "d. CC"
    ],
    "answer": "b. OM"
  },
  {
    "question": "The function of OS key in Heimann machine is same as ____ key of Rapiscan",
    "options": [
      "a. IM",
      "b. INV",
      "c. CC",
      "d. OM"
    ],
    "answer": "a. IM"
  },
  {
    "question": "The function of SEN key in Heimann machine is same as ___ key of Rapiscan.",
    "options": [
      "a. IM",
      "b. INV",
      "c. OM",
      "d. CC"
    ],
    "answer": "d. CC"
  },
  {
    "question": "The function of HI key in Heimann machine is same as ___ key of Rapiscan",
    "options": [
      "a. High",
      "b. IM",
      "c. INV",
      "d. CC"
    ],
    "answer": "a. High"
  },
  {
    "question": "Low false alarm rate which is one of the property of X-ray which indicates",
    "options": [
      "a. Physical check ratio is less",
      "b. There are only few explosives X-BIS cannot identify",
      "c. X-ray should alarm screener on the discovery of prohibited article",
      "d. Wrong indication rate is less"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Wrong indication rate is less"
  },
  {
    "question": "Atomic number of an element signifies the number of _________ moving around the nucleus of the atom of that element",
    "options": [
      "a. electrons",
      "b. protons",
      "c. neutrons",
      "d. atoms"
    ],
    "answer": "a. electrons"
  },
  {
    "question": "Zoom facility for new X-ray machine is",
    "options": [
      "a. 4X",
      "b. 8X",
      "c. 12X",
      "d. 16X"
    ],
    "answer": "b. 8X"
  },
  {
    "question": "Zoom facility for existing x-ray machine is",
    "options": [
      "a. 4X",
      "b. 8X",
      "c. 12X",
      "d. 16X"
    ],
    "answer": "a. 4X"
  },
  {
    "question": "When ____ key is pressed the conveyor belt will travel in the reverse direction",
    "options": [
      "a. FWD",
      "b. STOP",
      "c. REV",
      "d. ZOOM"
    ],
    "answer": "c. REV"
  },
  {
    "question": "When _____ key is pressed any area of monitor can be selected and magnified",
    "options": [
      "a. FWD",
      "b. STOP",
      "c. REV",
      "d. ZOOM"
    ],
    "answer": "d. ZOOM"
  },
  {
    "question": "_______ key gives a more through description of the functions available in the image processing section of the keyboard",
    "options": [
      "a. Menu key",
      "b. Inorganic material key",
      "c. Black and white key",
      "d. Inverse key"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Menu key"
  },
  {
    "question": "______key is pressed all colours are removed except for blue",
    "options": [
      "a. Menu key",
      "b. Inorganic material key",
      "c. Inverse key",
      "d. Black and white key"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Inorganic material key"
  },
  {
    "question": "______key is pressed all colour information from the image is removed and black and white image is displayed",
    "options": [
      "a. Menu key",
      "b. Inorganic material key",
      "c. Black and white key",
      "d. Inverse key"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Black and white key"
  },
  {
    "question": "_______ key is pressed the image is displayed in reverse i.e. black becomes white and vice versa",
    "options": [
      "a. Menu key",
      "b. Inverse key",
      "c. Inorganic material key",
      "d. Inverse key"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Inverse key"
  },
  {
    "question": "_______ key is pressed all colours are removed except for orange",
    "options": [
      "a. Organic Material",
      "b. Crystal Clear",
      "c. Low density key",
      "d. High density key"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Organic Material"
  },
  {
    "question": "_______ key is pressed it brings out the details in both light and dark areas simultaneously.",
    "options": [
      "a. Organic Material",
      "b. Crystal Clear",
      "c. Low density key",
      "d. High density key"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Crystal Clear"
  },
  {
    "question": "_______key is pressed the presentation of less dense objects in enhanced.",
    "options": [
      "a. Crystal Clear",
      "b. Organic Material",
      "c. Low density key",
      "d. High density key"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Low density key"
  },
  {
    "question": "_______ key is pressed the presentation of high density objects is enhanced",
    "options": [
      "a. Low density key",
      "b. Crystal Clear",
      "c. Organic Material",
      "d. High density key"
    ],
    "answer": "d. High density key"
  },
  {
    "question": "_______ key is pressed square box will appear on the screen and the area can be marked to check presence of Explosive material",
    "options": [
      "a. High Density Key",
      "b. EPX key",
      "c. Search Key",
      "d. Mode Key"
    ],
    "answer": "b. EPX key"
  }
]
    },
     {
        set: 12,
        questions:[
  {
    "question": "When _______ key is pressed in a Rapiscan machine search lamp will illuminate, and a buzzer will sound",
    "options": [
      "a. High Density Key",
      "b. EPX key",
      "c. Search Key",
      "d. Mode Key"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Search Key"
  },
  {
    "question": "A set of un insulated copper wires of different sizes are used in",
    "options": [
      "a. Single wire resolution test",
      "b. Simple penetration",
      "c. Useful penetration",
      "d. Material discrimination"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Single wire resolution test"
  },
  {
    "question": "________ test has different gauges of wire behind varying thickness of aluminium is",
    "options": [
      "a. Single wire resolution",
      "b. Simple penetration",
      "c. Useful penetration",
      "d. Material discrimination"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Useful penetration"
  },
  {
    "question": "The requirement salt and sugar should be seen in different colours is a specification of ______________ test",
    "options": [
      "a. Single wire resolution",
      "b. Simple penetration",
      "c. Useful penetration",
      "d. Material discrimination"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Material discrimination"
  },
  {
    "question": "The requirement salt and sugar should be seen in different colours is a specification of ______________ test",
    "options": [
      "a. Single wire resolution",
      "b. Simple penetration",
      "c. Useful penetration",
      "d. Material discrimination"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Material discrimination"
  },
  {
    "question": "The requirement that lead be visible beneath 26mm of steel is a specification of ______________ test",
    "options": [
      "a. Single wire resolution test",
      "b. Simple penetration",
      "c. Useful penetration",
      "d. Material discrimination"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Simple penetration"
  },
  {
    "question": "The requirement that vertical and horizontal grating to be seen is a specification of ______________ test",
    "options": [
      "a. Single wire resolution test",
      "b. Simple penetration",
      "c. Spatial resolution",
      "d. Material discrimination"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Spatial resolution"
  },
  {
    "question": "The requirement of single wire resolution is",
    "options": [
      "a. Display of 40 SWG wire not covered by step wedge",
      "b. 26SWG wire is seen under second step wedge",
      "c. Salt should be seen in green colour and sugar in orange colour",
      "d. Lead be visible beneath 26mm of steel"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Display of 40 SWG wire not covered by step wedge"
  },
  {
    "question": "The requirement of Useful penetration is",
    "options": [
      "a. Display of 40 SWG wire not covered by step wedge",
      "b. 26SWG wire is seen under second step wedge",
      "c. Salt should be seen in green colour and sugar in orange colour",
      "d. Lead be visible beneath 26mm of steel"
    ],
    "answer": "b. 26SWG wire is seen under second step wedge"
  },
  {
    "question": "The requirement of material discrimination test is",
    "options": [
      "a. Display of 40 SWG wire not covered by step wedge",
      "b. 26SWG wire is seen under second step wedge",
      "c. Salt should be seen in green colour and sugar in orange colour",
      "d. Lead be visible beneath 26mm of steel"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Salt should be seen in green colour and sugar in orange colour"
  },
  {
    "question": "The requirement of Simple penetration is",
    "options": [
      "a. Display of 40 SWG wire not covered by step wedge",
      "b. 26SWG wire is seen under second step wedge",
      "c. Salt should be seen in green colour and sugar in orange colour",
      "d. Lead be visible beneath 26mm of steel"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Display of 40 SWG wire not covered by step wedge"
  },
  {
    "question": "The requirement of spatial resolution is",
    "options": [
      "a. Vertical and horizontal gratings to be seen",
      "b. To see 0.1mm if thick steel",
      "c. Salt should be seen in green colour and sugar in orange colour",
      "d. Lead be visible beneath 26mm of steel"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Vertical and horizontal gratings to be seen"
  },
  {
    "question": "The requirement of thin metal imaging is",
    "options": [
      "a. Vertical and horizontal gratings to be seen",
      "b. to see 0.1mm thickness of steel",
      "c. Salt should be seen in green colour and sugar in orange colour",
      "d. Lead be visible beneath 26mm of steel"
    ],
    "answer": "b. to see 0.1mm thickness of steel"
  },
  {
    "question": "CTP test to be carried out",
    "options": [
      "a. Once every day",
      "b. When there is breakdown of x-ray machine",
      "c. Once in week",
      "d. Once every 8 hours"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Once every day"
  },
  {
    "question": "The software programme that projects fictional images of threat articles within the X-ray image of a real bag under examination is",
    "options": [
      "a. CTP",
      "b. TIP",
      "c. PIDS",
      "d. OTP"
    ],
    "answer": "b. TIP"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the benefit of TIP",
    "options": [
      "a. Individual tailored training",
      "b. Decrease motivation of the operator",
      "c. Supervisor feedback",
      "d. Both 'a' & 'c'"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Both 'a' & 'c'"
  },
  {
    "question": "While screening passenger baggage you have noticed one electronic which you have never seen before, how you will check the same.",
    "options": [
      "a. Ask passenger if any battery is attached, if not accept it.",
      "b. Ask passenger for what purpose it is used and ask him to switch it on and operate.",
      "c. Check passengers identity and ticket and allow the item",
      "d. Offload the item"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Ask passenger for what purpose it is used and ask him to switch it on and operate."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following can create difficulty for screener while screening",
    "options": [
      "a. Clothes",
      "b. Gun",
      "c. Liquids",
      "d. Dangerous article"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Liquids"
  },
  {
    "question": "The abbreviation CTX stands for?",
    "options": [
      "a. Controlled Tomography X-ray",
      "b. Computed Telegraphic X-ray",
      "c. Computed Tomography X-ray",
      "d. Computer Transmitted X-ray"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Computed Tomography X-ray"
  },
  {
    "question": "The abbreviation IM stands for?",
    "options": [
      "a. Inverse Material",
      "b. Inorganic Metal",
      "c. Inorganic Material",
      "d. Intense Material"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Inorganic Material"
  },
  {
    "question": "The abbreviation OM stands for ?",
    "options": [
      "a. Only Metal",
      "b. Organic Material",
      "c. Organic Metal",
      "d. Orange Material"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Organic Material"
  },
  {
    "question": "The abbreviation RCB stands for ?",
    "options": [
      "a. Result of Current Bag",
      "b. Resume Current Bag",
      "c. Re-search Current Bag",
      "d. Revise Current Bag"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Resume Current Bag"
  },
  {
    "question": "The abbreviation RTVS stands for ?",
    "options": [
      "a. Red Time Viewing System",
      "b. Real Time Viewing System",
      "c. Real Threat Viewing System",
      "d. Real Time Viewing Standard"
    ],
    "answer":"c. Real Threat Viewing System"
  },
  {
    "question": "The abbreviation STP stands for ?",
    "options": [
      "a. Standard Testing Plan",
      "b. Standard Training Process",
      "c. Standardized Training Package",
      "d. Standard Time Package"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Standardized Training Package"
  },
  {
    "question": "The abbreviation SWG stands for ?",
    "options": [
      "a. Standard Wire Gauge",
      "b. Standard Wireless Gauge",
      "c. Secured Wire Gauge",
      "d. Step Wire Gauge"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Standard Wire Gauge"
  },
  {
    "question": "The abbreviation VDU stands for ?",
    "options": [
      "a. Vision Display Unit",
      "b. Visual Density Unit",
      "c. Visual Display Unit",
      "d. Visual Direction Unit"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Visual Display Unit"
  },
  {
    "question": "The abbreviation VDZ stands for ?",
    "options": [
      "a. Variable Display Zoom",
      "b. Variable Density Zoom",
      "c. Vision Density Zoom",
      "d. Vision Display Zoom"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Variable Density Zoom"
  },
  {
    "question": "The abbreviation VEH stands for ?",
    "options": [
      "a. Variable Edge Enhancement",
      "b. View Edge Enhancement",
      "c. Variable Enhancement Edge",
      "d. Vertical Edge Enhancement"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Variable Edge Enhancement"
  },
  {
    "question": "The abbreviation VPB stands for ?",
    "options": [
      "a. View Previous Bag",
      "b. Variable Previous Bag",
      "c. Visual Previous Bag",
      "d. View Previous Bank"
    ],
    "answer": "a. View Previous Bag"
  },
  {
    "question": "The abbreviation VZM stands for ?",
    "options": [
      "a. Variable Zoom Metal",
      "b. Vision Zoom Mode",
      "c. Variable Zoom Mode",
      "d. View Zoom Mode"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Variable Zoom Mode"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the method for screening passenger bag",
    "options": [
      "a. Cooling off",
      "b. Cooling pit",
      "c. X-ray screening",
      "d. Use of DFMD"
    ],
    "answer": "c. X-ray screening"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which are the following is the method for screening passenger bag",
    "options": [
      "a. Cooling off",
      "b. Cooling pit",
      "c. Physical inspection of baggage",
      "d. Use of DFMD"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Physical inspection of baggage"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the method for screening passenger bag",
    "options": [
      "a. Cooling off",
      "b. Cooling pit",
      "c. Use of explosive detectors",
      "d. Use of DFMD"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Use of explosive detectors"
  },
  {
    "question": "Each X-BIS requires to be manned by ____ trained personnel",
    "options": [
      "a. 4",
      "b. 2",
      "c. 3",
      "d. 1"
    ],
    "answer": "a. 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Physical inspection of baggage is done",
    "options": [
      "a. When you have sufficient manpower",
      "b. At the discretion of APM",
      "c. When image on the monitor is not clear",
      "d. Whenever there is very light flight load"
    ],
    "answer": "c. When image on the monitor is not clear"
  },
  {
    "question": "Physical inspection of baggage is done",
    "options": [
      "a. When you have sufficient manpower",
      "b. At the discretion of APM",
      "c. Prescribed percentage baggage is required to be checked manually",
      "d. Very light flight load"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Prescribed percentage baggage is required to be checked manually"
  },
  {
    "question": "Physical inspection of baggage is done",
    "options": [
      "a. When you have sufficient manpower",
      "b. At the discretion of APM",
      "c. In the event of breakdown of x-ray machine",
      "d. Very light flight load"
    ],
    "answer": "c. In the event of breakdown of x-ray machine"
  },
  {
    "question": "Physical inspection of baggage is done",
    "options": [
      "a. When you have sufficient manpower",
      "b. At the discretion of APM",
      "c. Higher level of threat exists",
      "d. Very light flight load"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Higher level of threat exists"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is one the category in which X-ray screened bags are divided into",
    "options": [
      "a. Safe bag",
      "b. Oversize bag",
      "c. Open bag",
      "d. Small bag"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Safe bag"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is one the category in which X-ray screened bags are divided into",
    "options": [
      "a. Suspect bag",
      "b. Oversize bag",
      "c. Mishandled bag",
      "d. Small bag"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Suspect bag"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is one the category in which X-ray screened bags are divided into",
    "options": [
      "a. Unsafe bag",
      "b. Oversize bag",
      "c. Open bag",
      "d. Small bag"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Unsafe bag"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following action will be taken for the safe bag at X-ray machine",
    "options": [
      "a. Affix a security sticker or seal and bag can be send for check-in",
      "b. Send for physical search",
      "c. Inform supervisor and take action as per SOP",
      "d. Use Explosive detector to check for presence of explosive"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Affix a security sticker or seal and bag can be send for check-in"
  },
  {
    "question": "Following action will be taken for the Suspect bag at X-ray machine",
    "options": [
      "a. Affix a security sticker or seal and bag can be send for check-in",
      "b. Inform passenger to take it as hand bag",
      "c. Send for physical search",
      "d. Affix security strapping and send for check-in"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Send for physical search"
  },
  {
    "question": "Following action will be taken for the unsafe bag at X-ray machine",
    "options": [
      "a. Affix a security sticker or seal and bag can be send for check-in",
      "b. Send for physical search",
      "c. Inform supervisor and take action as per SOP",
      "d. Keep bag on your custody and let pax board the aircraft"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Inform supervisor and take action as per SOP"
  },
  {
    "question": "How to check bottles containing liquid",
    "options": [
      "a. Unscrew bottle and smell contents",
      "b. Test spray",
      "c. Offload liquid",
      "d. Pass it separately through X-BIS"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Unscrew bottle and smell contents"
  },
  {
    "question": "What immediate action you will take on the discovery of IED in the bag while screening",
    "options": [
      "a. Immediately remove bag from the tunnel",
      "b. Stop conveyor belt",
      "c. Take bag for physical inspection",
      "d. Physically restrain the owner"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Stop conveyor belt"
  },
  {
    "question": "What immediate action you will take on the discovery of gun in the bag while screening",
    "options": [
      "a. Take bag in your custody",
      "b. Press emergency stop button",
      "c. Take bag for physical inspection",
      "d. Use EVD/ETD"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Take bag in your custody"
  },
  {
    "question": "Passengers shall be escorted from the Terminal building to the aircraft by concerned airlines to",
    "options": [
      "a. To prevent contamination of security cleared person",
      "b. It is service which airlines should provide",
      "c. To keep a check on the driver",
      "d. To ensure passengers are comfortable"
    ],
    "answer": "a. To prevent contamination of security cleared person"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a security measure for registered bag after it is screened ?",
    "options": [
      "a. Use Explosive detector",
      "b. Compulsory physical identification of bag by passenger",
      "c. Bag should be kept for 24 hours cooling",
      "d. Reconciliation at BMA"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Reconciliation at BMA"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a security measure for registered bag after it is screened ?",
    "options": [
      "a. Bag is kept on conveyor belt and sent to BBA",
      "b. Compulsory physical identification of bag by passenger",
      "c. Bag should be kept for 24 hours cooling",
      "d. Escorting bag from BMA to aircraft"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Escorting bag from BMA to aircraft"
  }
]
    },
     {
        set: 13,
        questions: [
  {
    "question": "Procedure for hand search of baggage",
    "options": [
      "a. Baggage should be opened in such a way that passenger and searcher both can see the contents but other passengers can not see the",
      "b. Baggage should not be opened and examined to ensure that there is no false bottom.",
      "c. Try to search the bag if possible without removing contents. Use systematic method i.e. top to down and left to center and center to right.",
      "d. Both 'a' & 'c'"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Both 'a' & 'c'"
  },
  {
    "question": "While screening passenger registered bag you discovered some suspicious skin, bones and horn inside the bag. What action you will take.",
    "options": [
      "a. As it is not prohibited we can allow.",
      "b. As it also contains horn so it must of any animal, hence can be allowed.",
      "c. You will keep bag in custody and by silent alarm call supervisor and local police.",
      "d. You will inform passenger to take it as hand bag"
    ],
    "answer": "c. You will keep bag in custody and by silent alarm call supervisor and local police."
  },
  {
    "question": "In what sequence would the you carry out checks on a registered bag that is suspicious ?",
    "options": [
      "a. i, ii, iii",
      "b. iii, ii, i",
      "c. ii, i, iii",
      "d. iii, i, ii"
    ],
    "answer": "c. ii, i, iii"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which agency is responsible for Searching and securing SHA",
    "options": [
      "a. Airline",
      "b. ASG",
      "c. Airport Operator",
      "d. BCAS"
    ],
    "answer": "b. ASG"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the method to secure SHA",
    "options": [
      "a. Keeping all entry points open",
      "b. Effective screening of passenger and not hand baggage",
      "c. Screening of passenger and not staff",
      "d. Observing operational holding area and keeping surveillance"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Observing operational holding area and keeping surveillance"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the method to secure SHA",
    "options": [
      "a. Keeping all entry points open",
      "b. Effective screening of passenger and not hand baggage",
      "c. Screening of passenger and not staff",
      "d. Search of sterile holding area using different levels of search"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Search of sterile holding area using different levels of search"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the method to secure SHA",
    "options": [
      "a. Keeping all entry points open",
      "b. Effective screening of passenger and not hand baggage",
      "c. Screening of passenger and not staff",
      "d. Effective screening of passenger and baggage"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Effective screening of passenger and baggage"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the method to secure SHA",
    "options": [
      "a. Keeping all entry points open",
      "b. Effective screening of passenger and not hand baggage",
      "c. Screening of authorized personnel such as airport and airline personnel",
      "d. Effective screening of passenger and not hand baggage"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Screening of authorized personnel such as airport and airline personnel"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the method to secure SHA",
    "options": [
      "a. Keeping all entry points open",
      "b. Effective screening of passenger and not hand baggage",
      "c. Inspection / screening of goods and supplies taken into the holding areas",
      "d. Screening of passenger and not staff"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Inspection / screening of goods and supplies taken into the holding areas"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the screening plan",
    "options": [
      "a. Concourse plan",
      "b. Course plan",
      "c. Concussion plan",
      "d. Pier plan"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Concourse plan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the screening plan",
    "options": [
      "a. Holding area plan",
      "b. Multi holding plan",
      "c. Pier plan",
      "d. Concussion plan"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Holding area plan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the screening plan",
    "options": [
      "a. Boarding gate plan",
      "b. Multi holding plan",
      "c. Pier plan",
      "d. Concussion plan"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Boarding gate plan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is not the screening plan",
    "options": [
      "a. Concourse plan",
      "b. Holding area plan",
      "c. Boarding gate plan",
      "d. Bomb Threat Contingency Plan"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Bomb Threat Contingency Plan"
  },
  {
    "question": "When conducting search of the SHA more attention to be paid to toilets because",
    "options": [
      "a. It dirty",
      "b. Passenger is unsupervised",
      "c. Very few passengers use it",
      "d. House keeping staff are available at all times"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Passenger is unsupervised"
  },
  {
    "question": "More the facilities in the SHA greater the problem because",
    "options": [
      "a. Cost involved",
      "b. Passengers make SHA dirty",
      "c. More checks to be conducted of facilities",
      "d. More revenue is generated"
    ],
    "answer": "c. More checks to be conducted of facilities"
  },
  {
    "question": "If weapon discovered while conducting search of SHA searcher should immediately",
    "options": [
      "a. Trace passenger",
      "b. Check all hand bags of passenger in SHA",
      "c. Immediately safeguard the weapon",
      "d. Announce it on PA System"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Immediately safeguard the weapon"
  },
  {
    "question": "If IED IS discovered while conducting search of SHA searcher should immediately",
    "options": [
      "a. Trace passenger",
      "b. Check all hand bags of passenger in SHA",
      "c. Notify supervisor",
      "d. Announce it on PA System"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Notify supervisor"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the advantage of concourse plan",
    "options": [
      "a. Less man power required",
      "b. Segregation of passenger",
      "c. Less facilities",
      "d. More equipments required"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Less man power required"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the advantage of concourse plan",
    "options": [
      "a. Less equipments",
      "b. Segregation of passenger",
      "c. Less facilities",
      "d. More manpower required"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Less equipments"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the advantage of concourse plan",
    "options": [
      "a. Passengers have no direct access to aircraft",
      "b. Segregation of passenger",
      "c. Less facilities",
      "d. More equipments required"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Passengers have no direct access to aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the advantage of concourse plan",
    "options": [
      "a. Lot of time available for staff to carry out checks",
      "b. Segregation of passenger",
      "c. Less facilities",
      "d. More manpower required"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Lot of time available for staff to carry out checks"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the disadvantage of concourse plan.",
    "options": [
      "a. More man power required",
      "b. More equipment required",
      "c. Passenger have direct access to aircraft",
      "d. Mixing of passengers of various flight"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Mixing of passengers of various flight"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the disadvantage of concourse plan",
    "options": [
      "a. More man power required",
      "b. More equipment required",
      "c. Passenger have direct access to aircraft",
      "d. Passenger have to report well in advance for the checks"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Passenger have to report well in advance for the checks"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the disadvantage of concourse plan",
    "options": [
      "a. More man power required",
      "b. More equipment required",
      "c. Passenger have direct access to aircraft",
      "d. More facilities"
    ],
    "answer": "d. More facilities"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the advantage of holding area plan",
    "options": [
      "a. Direct access to aircraft",
      "b. Less time to check passenger",
      "c. Segregation of passenger of different flights",
      "d. Holding area must be secured when not in use."
    ],
    "answer": "c. Segregation of passenger of different flights"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the advantage of holding area plan",
    "options": [
      "a. Passenger have no direct access to aircraft",
      "b. Less time to check passenger",
      "c. No segregation of passenger of different flights",
      "d. Holding area must be secured when not in use."
    ],
    "answer": "a. Passenger have no direct access to aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the advantage of holding area plan",
    "options": [
      "a. Direct access to aircraft",
      "b. Less time to check passenger",
      "c. Segregation of passenger of different flights",
      "d. Holding area must be secured when not in use"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Segregation of passenger of different flights"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the advantage of holding area plan",
    "options": [
      "a. No direct access to aircraft",
      "b. Less time to check passenger",
      "c. Mixing of passenger of different flights",
      "d. Holding area must be secured when not in use."
    ],
    "answer": "a. No direct access to aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the advantage of holding area plan",
    "options": [
      "a. Passengers have direct access to aircraft",
      "b. Lot of time to check passenger",
      "c. Mixing of passenger of different flights",
      "d. Holding area must be secured when not in use."
    ],
    "answer": "b. Lot of time to check passenger"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the advantage of holding area plan",
    "options": [
      "a. Passengers have direct access to aircraft",
      "b. Less staff",
      "c. Mixing of passenger of different flights",
      "d. Holding area must be secured when not in use"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Less staff"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the advantage of holding area plan",
    "options": [
      "a. Passengers have direct access to aircraft",
      "b. Less equipments",
      "c. Mixing of passenger of different flights",
      "d. Holding area must be secured when not in use."
    ],
    "answer": "b. Less equipments"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the disadvantage of holding area plan",
    "options": [
      "a. Segregation of passengers",
      "b. Passengers have no direct access to aircraft",
      "c. Lot of time available for staff to carry out checks",
      "d. Holding area must be secured when not in use"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Holding area must be secured when not in use"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the advantage of boarding gate plan",
    "options": [
      "a. Passengers can have access to aircraft",
      "b. More manpower",
      "c. More equipments",
      "d. Segregation of passengers of different flights"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Segregation of passengers of different flights"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the disadvantage of boarding gate plan",
    "options": [
      "a. Mixing of passenger",
      "b. No direct access to aircraft",
      "c. Less manpower",
      "d. More equipments"
    ],
    "answer": "d. More equipments"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the disadvantage of boarding gate plan",
    "options": [
      "a. Mixing of passenger",
      "b. No direct access to aircraft",
      "c. More manpower",
      "d. Less equipments"
    ],
    "answer": "c. More manpower"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the disadvantage of boarding gate plan",
    "options": [
      "a. Mixing of passenger",
      "b. No direct access to aircraft",
      "c. Less time available to check passengers",
      "d. Less equipments"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Less time available to check passengers"
  },
  {
    "question": "Permission for the carriage of prisoner by air is given by:",
    "options": [
      "a. BCAS",
      "b. DGCA",
      "c. Local police",
      "d. CID"
    ],
    "answer": "a. BCAS"
  },
  {
    "question": "A prisoner should be accompanied by minimum",
    "options": [
      "a. One escort",
      "b. Two escorts",
      "c. Three escorts",
      "d. No escort require"
    ],
    "answer": "a. One escort"
  },
  {
    "question": "A prisoner should be boarded on aircraft",
    "options": [
      "a. A prisoner should be boarded on aircraft",
      "b. Before all passengers have boarded",
      "c. Within last 10 minutes of departure time",
      "d. At any time once boarding is announced"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Before all passengers have boarded"
  },
  {
    "question": "A prisoner should be seated",
    "options": [
      "a. On the first row of aircraft",
      "b. On the row with emergency exit",
      "c. As far as possible to the rear",
      "d. As far as possible to the rear"
    ],
    "answer": "d. As far as possible to the rear"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is a prisoner ?",
    "options": [
      "a. Any person who has committed crime",
      "b. A person who is arrested under any law",
      "c. A terrorist",
      "d. A criminal"
    ],
    "answer": "b. A person who is arrested under any law"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a part of procedure to carry prisoner?",
    "options": [
      "a. Permission to be obtained from BCAS",
      "b. Inform Sky Marshal about presence of prisoner",
      "c. Inform Sky Marshal about presence of prisoner",
      "d. Prisoner should only be seated on aisle seat"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Prisoner should only be seated on aisle seat"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a part of procedure to carry prisoner?",
    "options": [
      "a. Permission to be obtained from BCAS",
      "b. Inform Sky Marshal about presence of prisoner",
      "c. Prisoner should only be seated in the front rows of aircraft only so that it is easy to disembark him",
      "d. Give plastic cutlery to prisoner and escort"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Prisoner should only be seated in the front rows of aircraft only so that it is easy to disembark him"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a part of procedure to carry prisoner?",
    "options": [
      "a. Permission to be obtained from BCAS",
      "b. Inform Sky Marshal about presence of prisoner",
      "c. Prisoner should only be seated in the front rows of aircraft only so that it is easy to disembark him",
      "d. Give plastic cutlery to prisoner and escort"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Prisoner should only be seated in the front rows of aircraft only so that it is easy to disembark him"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is incorrect measure applied for carriage of prisoner?",
    "options": [
      "a. Permission to be obtained from BCAS",
      "b. Inform Sky Marshal about presence of prisoner",
      "c. Prisoner should not be under surveillance when using lavatory as he should get privacy while using the lavatory",
      "d. Give plastic cutlery to prisoner and escort"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Prisoner should not be under surveillance when using lavatory as he should get privacy while using the lavatory"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a part of procedure to carry prisoner?",
    "options": [
      "a. Permission to be obtained from DGCA",
      "b. Inform Sky Marshal about presence of prisoner",
      "c. Inform Sky Marshal about presence of prisoner",
      "d. Prisoner should only be seated as far as possible to the rear of aircraft"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Permission to be obtained from DGCA"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a part of procedure to carry prisoner?",
    "options": [
      "a. Inform Sky Marshal about presence of prisoner",
      "b. Give plastic cutlery to prisoner and escort",
      "c. Prisoner should only be seated as far as possible to the rear of aircraft",
      "d. Escorting officers can carry a weapon on board to deal with prisoner in case of emergency"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Escorting officers can carry a weapon on board to deal with prisoner in case of emergency"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a part of procedure to carry prisoner?",
    "options": [
      "a. Permission to be obtained from BCAS",
      "b. Inform Sky Marshal about presence of prisoner",
      "c. Prisoner should only be seated as far as possible to the rear of aircraft",
      "d. Prisoner and escort to be boarded in the end and disembarked before all other passengers"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Prisoner and escort to be boarded in the end and disembarked before all other passengers"
  },
  {
    "question": "A husband and wife are travelling on BOM-DEL sector. The husband has a licensed weapon on his name. The wife comes earlier with three checked in bags, one of it containing a pistol. She has all relevant documents of her husband related to the weapon. Which of the following is the appropriate procedure in this case",
    "options": [
      "a. All bags will be security cleared but request the lady to check-in only after her husband arrives",
      "b. All bags will be security cleared and check-in process is completed",
      "c. Bags will not be security cleared till the time the owner of the weapon arrives, lady cannot check in",
      "d. Weapon bag will be kept in your custody, rest of the bags are security cleared and the lady is checked in"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Bags will not be security cleared till the time the owner of the weapon arrives, lady cannot check in"
  },
  {
    "question": "You have identified undeclared weapon in passenger registered bag, but on questioning guest shows his valid license, what action you will take",
    "options": [
      "a. Detain passenger and complaint should be made to the local police station for necessary action at their end",
      "b. No need to detain passenger however complain should be made to the local police station for necessary action at their end.",
      "c. No need to detain as well as no need to complain about him in local police station",
      "d. Offload the passenger"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Detain passenger and complaint should be made to the local police station for necessary action at their end"
  }
]
    },
     {
        set: 14,
        questions: [
  {
    "question": "You have identified undeclared weapon in passenger registered bag, but on questioning guest claims to have valid arms license at home and can produce it later on, in that case,",
    "options": [
      "a. You will accept weapon and request passenger to fax license later on",
      "b. You will keep bag in your custody and tell passenger to go home and bring the license",
      "c. You will keep bag in your custody and inform local police for necessary legal action",
      "d. You will return the bag to the passenger and ask him to come back with license"
    ],
    "answer": "c. You will keep bag in your custody and inform local police for necessary legal action"
  },
  {
    "question": "Undeclared weapons carried by passenger discovered at pre-embarkation checks, on questioning guest shows his valid license, what action you will take",
    "options": [
      "a. Arms and ammunition to be shifted to registered baggage. Complaint lodged with local police",
      "b. Passenger is offloaded from the flight",
      "c. Arms and ammunition to be shifted to registered baggage",
      "d. Passenger allowed to board and briefed to be careful next time"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Arms and ammunition to be shifted to registered baggage. Complaint lodged with local police"
  },
  {
    "question": "Undeclared weapons carried by passenger discovered at pre-embarkation checks, on questioning guest, claims to have valid arms license at home and can produce it later on, in that case,",
    "options": [
      "a. Keep weapon in your custody and tell passenger to bring valid license",
      "b. Keep weapon in your custody and allow guest to travel. On returning back to station he can collect the same",
      "c. Passenger should be handed over to police",
      "d. Inform passenger to carry weapons in registered baggage"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Passenger should be handed over to police"
  },
  {
    "question": "What action you will take on the discovery of ammunition only in hand baggage of the passenger",
    "options": [
      "a. APSU/ASG or Airlines staff should question him why he is carrying arms and ammunition and he can be allowed to board",
      "b. If there is no doubt about his identity as well as about his genuineness dispose the ammunition and allow him to board the flight",
      "c. Ammunition to be send in checked in luggage, however complaint should be made in local police station.",
      "d. If there is no doubt about his identity as well as about his genuineness dispose the ammunition and allow him to board the flight"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Ammunition to be send in checked in luggage, however complaint should be made in local police station."
  },
  {
    "question": "Flight routed as DEL-BOM-PNQ. During transit checks crew informed security staff that there is one prisoner and three escorts travelling in the aircraft, but security staff/security incharge has no information about it, on inquiry it discovered that they are not carrying written permission from BCAS. What action you will take.",
    "options": [
      "a. As they have already traveled on DEL-BOM sector you will allow them to travel.",
      "b. Take written apology from escorts and allow them to travel",
      "c. Escort and prisoner will be offloaded and will be informed to get written approval from BCAS, at the same time complaint lodged to the agency carrying prisoner",
      "d. Allow passengers to travel and inform BCAS"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Escort and prisoner will be offloaded and will be informed to get written approval from BCAS, at the same time complaint lodged to the agency carrying prisoner"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the ring of protection",
    "options": [
      "a. Outer ring",
      "b. Middle ring",
      "c. In house ring",
      "d. Both 'a' & 'b'"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Both 'a' & 'b'"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a ring of protection",
    "options": [
      "a. Outer ring",
      "b. Internal ring",
      "c. Middle ring",
      "d. Inner ring"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Internal ring"
  },
  {
    "question": "One of the three rings of protection is",
    "options": [
      "a. Interior ring",
      "b. In house ring",
      "c. Inner ring",
      "d. In house ring"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Inner ring"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the procedure for guarding the aircraft normal condition?",
    "options": [
      "a. Guarding of aircraft is not required",
      "b. SLPC",
      "c. Intercept unauthorized people attempting to board aircraft or in a vicinity",
      "d. Provision of Sky Marshalls"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Intercept unauthorized people attempting to board aircraft or in a vicinity"
  },
  {
    "question": "Toilets of an aircraft is the most vulnerable area, where suspicious items could be placed by terrorists because",
    "options": [
      "a. They are dirty",
      "b. The terrorist has complete privacy",
      "c. There are smoke detectors in toilets",
      "d. They are not cleaned while aircraft is in flight"
    ],
    "answer": "b. The terrorist has complete privacy"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following areas of the aircraft is most vulnerable where the terrorist can easily place an IED",
    "options": [
      "a. Under the seat",
      "b. Over head bin",
      "c. In the cockpit",
      "d. In the toilet"
    ],
    "answer": "d. In the toilet"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the airline procedure for unattended aircraft",
    "options": [
      "a. Aircraft are parked in a well-lit area",
      "b. Only 1 external door should be opened",
      "c. Stairs and loading bridges are removed",
      "d. Both 'a' & 'c'"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Both 'a' & 'c'"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a procedure for unattended aircraft?",
    "options": [
      "a. Aircraft are parked in a well-lit area",
      "b. Aircraft will be guarded by security staff",
      "c. Stairs and loading bridges are removed and immobilized",
      "d. All external doors are closed and locked"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Aircraft will be guarded by security staff"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the correct action to handle a suspect bag found at airport",
    "options": [
      "a. Handover the bag to Airport operator",
      "b. Handover the bag to Airport operator",
      "c. Do not touch the bag",
      "d. Check the bag to find out any details of passengers on it"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Do not touch the bag"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is applicable for originating flight ?",
    "options": [
      "a. Aircraft search not required for originating flight",
      "b. A thorough anti-sabotage check is carried out",
      "c. Transit passengers and their baggage are examined",
      "d. Identification of checked in baggage by pax done for this flight"
    ],
    "answer": "b. A thorough anti-sabotage check is carried out"
  },
  {
    "question": "Identification of checked in baggage by pax done for this flight",
    "options": [
      "a. After all the passengers have disembarked/ deplaned",
      "b. Aircraft search not required in turn around flight",
      "c. With Transit passenger still on board",
      "d. When the boarding process is completed"
    ],
    "answer": "a. After all the passengers have disembarked/ deplaned"
  },
  {
    "question": "When the boarding process is completed",
    "options": [
      "a. ASG/APSU",
      "b. Trained airline ground staff & engineering staff",
      "c. Cabin crew",
      "d. Cockpit crew"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Trained airline ground staff & engineering staff"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which document to be referred while conducting search of aircraft ?",
    "options": [
      "a. Aircraft search check-list",
      "b. Aircraft equipment check-list",
      "c. Aircraft entry list",
      "d. Aircraft entry register"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Aircraft search check-list"
  },
  {
    "question": "Flight is routed from DEL-AMD-BOM which of the following security check will be done at AMD during the transit stop?",
    "options": [
      "a. Make sure nothing is left in over head bin",
      "b. Re-identification of hand baggage",
      "c. Anti sabotage check is done after disembarkation of all the passengers and crew",
      "d. Re-identification of Registered baggage"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Re-identification of hand baggage"
  },
  {
    "question": "In what sequence would the pre flight anti sabotage search of a turnaround aircraft be carried out ?",
    "options": [
      "a. i, ii, iii",
      "b. iii, ii, i",
      "c. ii, i, iii",
      "d. iii, i, ii"
    ],
    "answer": "b. iii, ii, i"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the procedure for a Gate no show passenger",
    "options": [
      "a. Once aircraft is departed he should be traced and booked for next available flight",
      "b. Check the system to find out whether passenger has check in bag. His check-in bag should be offloaded then flight can be released",
      "c. Inform the destination station to trace and return the passengers registered bag by first available flight",
      "d. Such a passenger is black listed by the airline and not allowed to travel on the airlines flight"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Check the system to find out whether passenger has check in bag. His check-in bag should be offloaded then flight can be released"
  },
  {
    "question": "Boarding for the departure aircraft is in process. Crew has found an un-identified bag in the toilet which does not have any hand baggage tag or identification. What action will be taken ?",
    "options": [
      "a. Immediately offload the bag from the aircraft and take it 100 m away from aircraft",
      "b. All passengers would be asked to come one by one to see the bag and identify if it belongs to them, else it offloaded and handed over to airport operator",
      "c. Crew will make announcement in aircraft and try to identify owner. If no one claims bag, aircraft evacuated, BDDS informed, bag should not be touched",
      "d. If owner cannot be traced, security staff should open and check the bag first. If threat item is seen the aircraft is evacuated, BDDS informed else bag is offloaded."
    ],
    "answer": "c. Crew will make announcement in aircraft and try to identify owner. If no one claims bag, aircraft evacuated, BDDS informed, bag should not be touched"
  },
  {
    "question": "Boarding for the departure aircraft is in process. Crew has found an un-identified bag in the toilet which does not have any hand baggage tag or identification. What should be the first action taken by crew ?",
    "options": [
      "a. Offload bag and hand over to security",
      "b. Inform pilot to take aircraft to isolated bay",
      "c. Make announcement and try to find the owner of the bag",
      "d. Announce about the threat bag and ask passengers to evacuate"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Make announcement and try to find the owner of the bag"
  },
  {
    "question": "You are allocated at remote bay to guard aircraft, at the distance of approximately 50mtrs you observed boy loitering around who is not wearing any uniform , from far you could not see his AEP. What action you will take.",
    "options": [
      "a. You will call boy at your aircraft and ask him what he is doing there",
      "b. You will leave aircraft and run towards him and ask what he is doing there",
      "c. You will not pay any attention to him as you are allocated for aircraft guarding",
      "d. You will call up supervisor and inform about the location of strange person"
    ],
    "answer": "d. You will call up supervisor and inform about the location of strange person"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the duty of airlines in catering security",
    "options": [
      "a. Access control of catering premises",
      "b. Security of chilling room and refrigerators",
      "c. Delivery of raw material",
      "d. Supervise the pre-setting of the catering uplift"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Supervise the pre-setting of the catering uplift"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the duty of airlines in catering security",
    "options": [
      "a. Access control of catering premises",
      "b. Security of chilling room and refrigerators",
      "c. Delivery of raw material",
      "d. Systematic search of food trolley"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Systematic search of food trolley"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the duty of airlines in catering security",
    "options": [
      "a. Access control of catering premises",
      "b. Security of chilling room and refrigerators",
      "c. Delivery of raw material",
      "d. Search under the food trolley"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Search under the food trolley"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the duty of airlines in catering security",
    "options": [
      "a. Access control of catering premises",
      "b. Security of chilling room and refrigerators",
      "c. Delivery of raw material",
      "d. Check the trays for unusual weight"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Check the trays for unusual weight"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the duty of airlines in catering security",
    "options": [
      "a. Access control of catering premises",
      "b. Security of chilling room and refrigerators",
      "c. Delivery of raw material",
      "d. Search of dry ice tray"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Search of dry ice tray"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the duty of airlines in catering security",
    "options": [
      "a. Access control of catering premises",
      "b. Security of chilling room and refrigerators",
      "c. Delivery of raw material",
      "d. Items that are not containerized shall be physically searched"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Items that are not containerized shall be physically searched"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is responsibility of airline staff in catering premises",
    "options": [
      "a. Access control of catering premises",
      "b. Security of chilling room and refrigerators",
      "c. Checks of the high lift vehicle",
      "d. Delivery of raw material"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Checks of the high lift vehicle"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the responsibility of caterer?",
    "options": [
      "a. Sealing of carts",
      "b. Access control of catering premises",
      "c. Preparation of dispatch slip for HLV",
      "d. Checking food trays"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Access control of catering premises"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which is not a role of airline security in catering",
    "options": [
      "a. Search under the food trolley and check locks",
      "b. Access control of catering premises",
      "c. Check the trays for unusual weight",
      "d. Search the top part of the trolley namely the ice tray"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Access control of catering premises"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the responsibility of caterer?",
    "options": [
      "a. Sealing of carts",
      "b. Security checks of raw material brought into premises",
      "c. Preparation of dispatch slip",
      "d. Checking trays"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Security checks of raw material brought into premises"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the responsibility of caterer?",
    "options": [
      "a. Sealing of carts",
      "b. Chilling rooms and refrigerators under strict security control",
      "c. Preparation of dispatch slip",
      "d. Checking trays"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Chilling rooms and refrigerators under strict security control"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the responsibility of caterer?",
    "options": [
      "a. Sealing of carts",
      "b. Providing proper locking system for meal carts",
      "c. Preparation of dispatch slip",
      "d. Checking trays"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Providing proper locking system for meal carts"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the responsibility of caterer?",
    "options": [
      "a. Sealing of carts",
      "b. Access control of catering premises",
      "c. Escorting of catering vehicles",
      "d. Preparation of dispatch slip"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Access control of catering premises"
  },
  {
    "question": "On board courier will be accepted minimum",
    "options": [
      "a. One day prior",
      "b. 5hrs prior",
      "c. 2hrs prior",
      "d. 1 hr prior"
    ],
    "answer": "c. 2hrs prior"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why cargo is vulnerable",
    "options": [
      "a. High volume carried",
      "b. Easy to screen",
      "c. Low risk to terrorist",
      "d. Both 'a' & 'c'"
    ],
    "answer":"d. Both 'a' & 'c'"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the method of screening cargo",
    "options": [
      "a. Frisking",
      "b. Pat down search",
      "c. X-ray screening",
      "d. Check with metal detectors"
    ],
    "answer": "c. X-ray screening"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the method of screening cargo",
    "options": [
      "a. Frisking",
      "b. Physical check",
      "c. Pat down search",
      "d. HHMD"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Physical check"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the method of screening cargo",
    "options": [
      "a. Frisking",
      "b. Explosive detector",
      "c. Pat down search",
      "d. CCTV"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Explosive detector"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the method of screening cargo",
    "options": [
      "a. Frisking",
      "b. X Ray",
      "c. Pat down search",
      "d. HHMD"
    ],
    "answer": "b. X Ray"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the method of screening cargo",
    "options": [
      "a. Frisking",
      "b. Simulation chamber",
      "c. Pat down search",
      "d. DFMD"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Simulation chamber"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the method of screening cargo",
    "options": [
      "a. Frisking",
      "b. Physical check",
      "c. Dog squad",
      "d. Both 'b' & 'c'"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Both 'b' & 'c'"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following shipment is exempted from x-ray screening",
    "options": [
      "a. Documents",
      "b. Food items",
      "c. HUM",
      "d. Medicines"
    ],
    "answer": "c. HUM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following shipment is exempted from x-ray screening",
    "options": [
      "a. Documents",
      "b. Food items",
      "c. AVI",
      "d. Flower"
    ],
    "answer": "c. AVI"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following shipment is exempted from x-ray screening",
    "options": [
      "a. Documents",
      "b. Life saving material",
      "c. Food items",
      "d. Vegetables"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Life saving material"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following shipment is exempted from x-ray screening",
    "options": [
      "a. Food items",
      "b. Live human organs",
      "c. Documents",
      "d. Fruits"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Live human organs"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following shipment is exempted from x-ray screening",
    "options": [
      "a. Food items",
      "b. Diplomatic mail",
      "c. Documents",
      "d. Clothes"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Diplomatic mail"
  }
]
    },
     {
        set: 15,
        questions:[
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following shipment is exempted from x-ray screening",
    "options": [
      "a. Food items",
      "b. Special nuclear material",
      "c. Diplomatic mail",
      "d. Both 'b' & 'c'"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Both 'b' & 'c'"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following document is required in case of acceptance of HUM",
    "options": [
      "a. Letter from embassy",
      "b. Embalming certificate",
      "c. Approval from BCAS",
      "d. Approval from DGCA"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Embalming certificate"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following document is required in case of acceptance of HUM",
    "options": [
      "a. Letter from embassy",
      "b. Approval from BCAS",
      "c. Police clearance certificate",
      "d. Approval from DGCA"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Police clearance certificate"
  },
  {
    "question": "Accompanied diplomatic mail bag can be",
    "options": [
      "a. Screened",
      "b. Not to be screened",
      "c. Can be physically searched",
      "d. Can be searched by HHMD"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Not to be screened"
  },
  {
    "question": "Unaccompanied diplomatic mail bag can be",
    "options": [
      "a. Screened",
      "b. Not be screened",
      "c. Can be physically searched",
      "d. Can be kept for Cooling off period"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Screened"
  },
  {
    "question": "While screening postal mail you discovered weapon in one of the mail bag, what action you will take",
    "options": [
      "a. Postal authorities must have checked the license for the weapon so you will accept it",
      "b. You will conduct physical search of mail bag",
      "c. You will immediately inform to your supervisor, local police as well to postal authorities",
      "d. You will inform to postal authorities to come and collect the bag"
    ],
    "answer": "c. You will immediately inform to your supervisor, local police as well to postal authorities"
  },
  {
    "question": "While monitoring loading of cargo at aircraft you saw one carton with all marking of Dangerous goods but documentation says general goods, what action you will take at aircraft.",
    "options": [
      "a. As declared general good you will load it",
      "b. Documentation says general goods but marking says DG you will offload it and send it in warehouse to re-verify the contents",
      "c. You will open carton at aircraft hold to check the contents",
      "d. You will offload it and load it in cabin and inform crew to take care."
    ],
    "answer": "c. You will open carton at aircraft hold to check the contents"
  },
  {
    "question": "You have received consignment of HUM through cargo but no consignee has reverted to collect the same even after 5hrs after arrival. What action you will take.",
    "options": [
      "a. Send HUM back to originating station",
      "b. Send HUM to mortuary and wait for consignee",
      "c. Check from the arrival station about the contact details consignor and consignee, if unable to contact them inform local police",
      "d. You can wait and keep body in your warehouse till consignee comes to collect"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Check from the arrival station about the contact details consignor and consignee, if unable to contact them inform local police"
  },
  {
    "question": "The following personnel’s is exempted from pre-embarkation security checks at all civil airports even when he/she is not accompanying the president.",
    "options": [
      "a. Spouse of the president of India",
      "b. Former President",
      "c. Shri Robert Vadra, while traveling with SPG protectees",
      "d. His Holiness the Dalai Lama"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Spouse of the president of India"
  },
  {
    "question": "On the grounds of protocol which one of the following persons is allowed access to aircraft in their own vehicles with an escort",
    "options": [
      "a. President",
      "b. Former President of India",
      "c. Chief Justice of India",
      "d. Chief Ministers"
    ],
    "answer": "a. President"
  },
  {
    "question": "On the grounds of protocol the following is allowed in their own vehicles with an escort",
    "options": [
      "a. Lt Governors of Union Territories",
      "b. Vice President",
      "c. Speaker of Lok Sabha",
      "d. Foreign Ambassadors/High Commissioners on their first arrival and final departure"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Vice President"
  },
  {
    "question": "On the grounds of protocol which one of the following persons is allowed access to aircraft in their own vehicles with an escort",
    "options": [
      "a. Prime Minister",
      "b. Governors",
      "c. First Lady (Wife of President of India)",
      "d. Chief Ministers"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Prime Minister"
  },
  {
    "question": "On the grounds of protocol which one of the following persons is allowed access to aircraft in their own vehicles with an escort",
    "options": [
      "a. Wife of Vice President of India",
      "b. Former Prime Minister",
      "c. Visiting Heads of State",
      "d. Speaker of Lok Sabha"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Visiting Heads of State"
  },
  {
    "question": "On the grounds of protocol which one of the following persons is allowed access to aircraft in their own vehicles with an escort",
    "options": [
      "a. Visiting Heads of Govt",
      "b. Chief Justice of India",
      "c. Foreign Ambassadors/High Commissioners on their first arrival and final departure",
      "d. Former President of India"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Visiting Heads of Govt"
  },
  {
    "question": "On the grounds of protocol which one of the following persons is allowed access to aircraft in their own vehicles without an escort",
    "options": [
      "a. Former President of India",
      "b. Visiting Heads of State",
      "c. Visiting Heads of Govt",
      "d. Lt Governors of Union Territories"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Former President of India"
  },
  {
    "question": "On the grounds of protocol which one of the following persons is allowed access to aircraft in their own vehicles without an escort",
    "options": [
      "a. Former Prime Minister",
      "b. Prime Minister",
      "c. President",
      "d. Governors"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Former Prime Minister"
  },
  {
    "question": "On the grounds of protocol which one of the following persons is allowed access to aircraft in their own vehicles without an escort",
    "options": [
      "a. Visiting Heads of States",
      "b. Chief Justice of India",
      "c. Prime Minister",
      "d. Lt Governors of Union Territories"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Chief Justice of India"
  },
  {
    "question": "On the grounds of protocol which one of the following persons is allowed access to aircraft in their own vehicles without an escort",
    "options": [
      "a. On the grounds of protocol which one of the following persons is allowed access to aircraft in their own vehicles without an escort",
      "b. Speaker of Lok Sabha",
      "c. Governors",
      "d. Lt Governors of Union Territories"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Speaker of Lok Sabha"
  },
  {
    "question": "On the grounds of protocol which one of the following persons is allowed access to aircraft in their own vehicles without an escort",
    "options": [
      "a. First Lady (Wife of President of India)",
      "b. Chief Ministers",
      "c. Visiting Heads of States",
      "d. Visiting Heads of States"
    ],
    "answer": "a. First Lady (Wife of President of India)"
  },
  {
    "question": "On the grounds of protocol which one of the following persons is allowed access to aircraft in their own vehicles without an escort",
    "options": [
      "a. Wife of Vice President of India",
      "b. Visiting Heads of Govt",
      "c. Prime Minister",
      "d. President"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Wife of Vice President of India"
  },
  {
    "question": "On the grounds of protocol which one of the following persons is allowed access to aircraft in their own vehicles without an escort",
    "options": [
      "a. Prime Minister",
      "b. Wife of Vice President of India",
      "c. Visiting Heads of Govt",
      "d. Chief Ministers"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Wife of Vice President of India"
  },
  {
    "question": "On the grounds of protocol which one of the following persons is allowed access to aircraft in their own vehicles without an escort",
    "options": [
      "a. Foreign Ambassadors/High Commissioners on their first arrival and final departure",
      "b. Lt Governors of Union Territories",
      "c. President",
      "d. Governors"
    ],
    "answer":"a. Foreign Ambassadors/High Commissioners on their first arrival and final departure"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following persons is allowed access to aircraft in their own vehicles without escort up to tarmac area within their states/union territories the following is allowed.",
    "options": [
      "a. Prime Minister",
      "b. Vice President",
      "c. Governors",
      "d. Visiting Heads of states"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Governors"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following persons is allowed access to aircraft in their own vehicles without escort up to tarmac area within their states/union territories the following is allowed",
    "options": [
      "a. Chief Ministers",
      "b. Visiting heads of Govt",
      "c. Wife of Vice President of India",
      "d. President"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Chief Ministers"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following persons is allowed access to aircraft in their own vehicles without escort up to tarmac area within their states/union territories the following is allowed",
    "options": [
      "a. Prime Minister",
      "b. Former President of India",
      "c. Speaker of Lok Sabha",
      "d. Lt Governors of Union Territories"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Lt Governors of Union Territories"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is exempted from the pre-embarkation security check?",
    "options": [
      "a. Member of Parliament",
      "b. Member of Legislative Assembly",
      "c. Judges of High Court",
      "d. Chief Election Commissioner"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Chief Election Commissioner"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is exempted from the pre-embarkation security check?",
    "options": [
      "a. Former Prime Ministers",
      "b. Wife of Prime Ministers",
      "c. Cabinet Secretary",
      "d. Judges of High Court"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Cabinet Secretary"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is exempted from the pre-embarkation security check?",
    "options": [
      "a. Member of Legislative Assembly",
      "b. Judges of High Court",
      "c. Speaker of Lok Sabha",
      "d. Governors of Union Territories"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Speaker of Lok Sabha"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is exempted from the pre-embarkation security check?",
    "options": [
      "a. Chief of staff holding the rank of full Colonel or equivalent",
      "b. Chief Justices of the High Court",
      "c. Wife of Prime Ministers",
      "d. Judges of District Court"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Chief Justices of the High Court"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is exempted from the pre-embarkation security check?",
    "options": [
      "a. Governors of Union Territories",
      "b. Judges of High Court",
      "c. Union Ministers of Cabinet rank",
      "d. Member of Parliament"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Union Ministers of Cabinet rank"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is exempted from the pre-embarkation security check?",
    "options": [
      "a. Chief Election Minister",
      "b. Former Speakers of Lok Sabha",
      "c. Comptroller and Auditor General of India",
      "d. Governors of Union Territories"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Comptroller and Auditor General of India"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is exempted from the pre-embarkation security check?",
    "options": [
      "a. Cabinet Secretary",
      "b. Speaker of Lok Sabha",
      "c. Chief Justices of the High Court",
      "d. Wife of Prime Ministers"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Wife of Prime Ministers"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is exempted from the pre-embarkation security check?",
    "options": [
      "a. Speaker of Lok Sabha",
      "b. Comptroller and Auditor General of India",
      "c. Cabinet Ministers",
      "d. Governors of Union Territories"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Comptroller and Auditor General of India"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is exempted from the pre-embarkation security check?",
    "options": [
      "a. President",
      "b. Chief Justice of India",
      "c. Speaker of Lok Sabha",
      "d. Member of Legislative Assembly"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Member of Legislative Assembly"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is exempted from the pre-embarkation security check?",
    "options": [
      "a. His Holiness the Dalai Lama",
      "b. Governors of Union Territories",
      "c. Wife of Prime Ministers",
      "d. Cabinet Ministers"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Wife of Prime Ministers"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is exempted from the pre-embarkation security check?",
    "options": [
      "a. Shri Robert Vadra, While Traveling with SPG protectees",
      "b. Former Prime Ministers",
      "c. Deputy Chief Ministers of Union Territories",
      "d. Chief Ministers of States"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Former Prime Ministers"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is exempted from the pre-embarkation security check?",
    "options": [
      "a. Former President",
      "b. Union Ministers of Cabinet Rank",
      "c. Deputy Chief Ministers of States",
      "d. Chief of staff holding the rank of full Colonel or equivalent"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Chief of staff holding the rank of full Colonel or equivalent"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is exempted from the pre-embarkation security check?",
    "options": [
      "a. Member of Legislative Assembly",
      "b. Chief Justices of the High Court",
      "c. Comptroller and Auditor General of India",
      "d. Cabinet Secretary"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Member of Legislative Assembly"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is exempted from the pre-embarkation security check?",
    "options": [
      "a. Governors of States",
      "b. Chief Ministers of States",
      "c. Cabinet Ministers",
      "d. SPG protectees"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Cabinet Ministers"
  },
  {
    "question": "While monitoring loading of cargo at aircraft you saw one carton with all marking of Dangerous goods but documentation says general goods, what action you will take at aircraft",
    "options": [
      "a. Load it on aircraft as document says it is general goods",
      "b. Offload it and send it in warehouse to re-verify the contents",
      "c. Open carton at aircraft hold to check the contents",
      "d. Offload it and load it in cabin and inform crew to take care"
    ],
    "answer":"c. Open carton at aircraft hold to check the contents"
  },
  {
    "question": "The abbreviation VDU stands for ?",
    "options": [
      "a. Vision Display Unit",
      "b. Visual Density Unit",
      "c. Visual Display Unit",
      "d. Visual Direction Unit"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Visual Display Unit"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the duty of airlines in catering security",
    "options": [
      "a. Access control of catering premises",
      "b. Security of chilling room and refrigerators",
      "c. Delivery of raw material",
      "d. Search of dry ice tray"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Search of dry ice tray"
  },
  {
    "question": "Diplomatic Mail bags carried as hold baggage",
    "options": [
      "a. Requires to be escorted by airport security",
      "b. Requires to be physically inspected by airline security",
      "c. Requires to be x-ray screened by airline security",
      "d. Requires physical check"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Requires to be x-ray screened by airline security"
  },
  {
    "question": "High value shipments will be required to be",
    "options": [
      "a. Documented",
      "b. Exempted from screening",
      "c. Escorted by security",
      "d. Both 'a' & 'c'"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Both 'a' & 'c'"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following document is required in case of acceptance of HUM",
    "options": [
      "a. Letter from embassy",
      "b. Approval from BCAS",
      "c. Death certificate",
      "d. DGCA Approval"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Death certificate"
  },
  {
    "question": "Unaccompanied diplomatic mail bag can be",
    "options": [
      "a. Screened",
      "b. Not be screened",
      "c. Can be physically searched",
      "d. Kept for Cooling off period"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Screened"
  },
  {
    "question": "On board courier will be accepted minimum",
    "options": [
      "a. One day prior",
      "b. 5 hrs prior",
      "c. 2 hrs prior",
      "d. 4 hrs prior"
    ],
    "answer": "c. 2 hrs prior"
  },
  {
    "question": "The under mentioned personnel are authorized to carry loaded weapons on board an aircraft",
    "options": [
      "a. Chairman of the Aircraft Operator",
      "b. Security In-charge",
      "c. Sky Marshal",
      "d. PSO’s of President"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Sky Marshal"
  },
  {
    "question": "First recorded hijacking of aircraft in the history of civil aviation took place in the year",
    "options": [
      "a. 1931",
      "b. 1933",
      "c. 1934",
      "d. 1935"
    ],
    "answer": "a. 1931"
  },
  {
    "question": "BMA is located in which part of the airport",
    "options": [
      "a. Landside",
      "b. Airside",
      "c. Departure side of T.B",
      "d. Arrival side"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Airside"
  }
]
    },
     {
        set: 16,
        questions: [
  {
    "question": "In case of unlawful seizure of aircraft, which committee meets at the airport",
    "options": [
      "a. Central Committee",
      "b. Airport Security Committee",
      "c. Aerodrome Committee",
      "d. COSAH"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Aerodrome Committee"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IED can be concealed",
    "options": [
      "a. In hand baggage",
      "b. Only in registered baggage",
      "c. On person",
      "d. Both 'a' & 'c'"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Both 'a' & 'c'"
  },
  {
    "question": "The X-BIS should meet the specification of",
    "options": [
      "a. BCAS",
      "b. DGCA",
      "c. Manufacturer of X-BIS",
      "d. Air operator"
    ],
    "answer": "a. BCAS"
  },
  {
    "question": "All acids fall under which category of prohibited item",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapon",
      "b. Explosive",
      "c. Dangerous Article",
      "d. Dangerous substances"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Dangerous substances"
  },
  {
    "question": "NCASTP deals with which of the following",
    "options": [
      "a. Training of personnel in Security",
      "b. Safety Inspection of Audit",
      "c. DGR",
      "d. N/A"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Training of personnel in Security"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many prisoners of dangerous category can be allowed on board in one flight",
    "options": [
      "a. 1",
      "b. 2",
      "c. 3",
      "d. any number"
    ],
    "answer": "a. 1"
  },
  {
    "question": "Feedback of missed TIP object appears in which colour",
    "options": [
      "a. Red colour",
      "b. Green colour",
      "c. Yellow colour",
      "d. Blue colour"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Red colour"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the meanining of the phrase WILCO in RT communication",
    "options": [
      "a. I understand your message and will comply with it",
      "b. Permission for the proposed action granted",
      "c. YES",
      "d. Negative"
    ],
    "answer": "a. I understand your message and will comply with it"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one is not a primary effect of an high explosive explosion",
    "options": [
      "a. Blast effect",
      "b. Fragmentation",
      "c. Translation",
      "d. Water soak"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Water soak"
  },
  {
    "question": "The distance between 2 DFMD while installation should be ___ to get maximum efficiency of DFMD",
    "options": [
      "a. 35 cm",
      "b. 35 inches",
      "c. 45 cm",
      "d. 20 cm"
    ],
    "answer": "a. 35 cm"
  },
  {
    "question": "Load officer of the X-BIS is also known as ___",
    "options": [
      "a. Senior",
      "b. Profiler",
      "c. Pilot",
      "d. Loader"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Profiler"
  },
  {
    "question": "Head Quarters of ICAO is located at",
    "options": [
      "a. Geneva, Switzerland",
      "b. New Delhi, India",
      "c. Montreal, Canada",
      "d. Chicago, USA"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Montreal, Canada"
  },
  {
    "question": "The passenger who is verbally, potentially violent and not cooperating with security procedures is known as",
    "options": [
      "a. Criminal",
      "b. Person in intoxication mode",
      "c. Disruptive passenger",
      "d. Mentally ill"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Disruptive passenger"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which is not the characteristic of profiler",
    "options": [
      "a. Quick decision maker",
      "b. Intelligent",
      "c. Rigid",
      "d. Endurance"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Rigid"
  },
  {
    "question": "Bomb threat comes under",
    "options": [
      "a. Hijacking",
      "b. Sabotage",
      "c. Pilferage",
      "d. Petty crime"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Sabotage"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is an example of explosive",
    "options": [
      "a. Detonator",
      "b. Tear Gas",
      "c. Rifles",
      "d. Acids"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Detonator"
  },
  {
    "question": "Types of switches/ mechanism that can be used to blast an IED",
    "options": [
      "a. One",
      "b. Two",
      "c. Three",
      "d. Four"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Four"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which department can go for inspection in an aircraft other than the concerned airlines",
    "options": [
      "a. CISF",
      "b. Immigration",
      "c. BCAS & DGCA",
      "d. AAI"
    ],
    "answer": "c. BCAS & DGCA"
  },
  {
    "question": "The transponder code for Hijacking",
    "options": [
      "a. 7500",
      "b. 7000",
      "c. 1500",
      "d. 2000"
    ],
    "answer": "a. 7500"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which equipment gives 3 degree angle for landing of flight",
    "options": [
      "a. ILS",
      "b. Localizer",
      "c. Glide Path",
      "d. Outer marker"
    ],
    "answer": "a. ILS"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following lights is used for safe landing of the aircraft",
    "options": [
      "a. PAPI",
      "b. PAPA",
      "c. AGNIS",
      "d. PRAN"
    ],
    "answer": "a. PAPI"
  },
  {
    "question": "Boeing belongs to which country",
    "options": [
      "a. America",
      "b. Britain",
      "c. Germany",
      "d. Russia"
    ],
    "answer": "a. America"
  },
  {
    "question": "UVSS is used to",
    "options": [
      "a. Search a vehicle",
      "b. Assist Pilot in landing as part of ILS",
      "c. Both 'a' & 'b'",
      "d. Screen Cargo"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Search a vehicle"
  },
  {
    "question": "Typical location of crash gate at airport is",
    "options": [
      "a. Near the Terminal building",
      "b. Anywhere at an airport",
      "c. Access control point",
      "d. Near to runway"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Near to runway"
  },
  {
    "question": "Dangerous Goods are classified in",
    "options": [
      "a. 04 class",
      "b. 05 class",
      "c. 07 class",
      "d. 09 class"
    ],
    "answer": "d. 09 class"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many cartridges a pax with valid license can carry in registered baggage",
    "options": [
      "a. 30 cartridges",
      "b. 50 cartridges",
      "c. 60 cartridges",
      "d. No limit"
    ],
    "answer": "b. 50 cartridges"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Chicago convention is only applicable for",
    "options": [
      "a. Civil Aviation",
      "b. Military Aviation",
      "c. General Aviation",
      "d. India"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Civil Aviation"
  },
  {
    "question": "When did India become a contracting state of ICAO",
    "options": [
      "a. 1st March 1947",
      "b. 4th April 1947",
      "c. 7th Dec 1944",
      "d. 10th May 1984"
    ],
    "answer": "a. 1st March 1947"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is UM?",
    "options": [
      "a. Unaccompanied Minors",
      "b. United Members",
      "c. Useful Machines",
      "d. Useful Management"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Unaccompanied Minors"
  },
  {
    "question": "Glide Path is a part of",
    "options": [
      "a. Security Control",
      "b. ILS",
      "c. GPS",
      "d. LLZ"
    ],
    "answer": "b. ILS"
  },
  {
    "question": "ACI was formed in the year",
    "options": [
      "a. 1990",
      "b. 1989",
      "c. 1944",
      "d. 1991"
    ],
    "answer": "d. 1991"
  },
  {
    "question": "FM Transmission & Radio Control mechanism are ___ type of Switch",
    "options": [
      "a. Remote Control",
      "b. Delayed",
      "c. Anti-handling",
      "d. Ambient Condition"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Remote Control"
  },
  {
    "question": "The X-Ray machine should be able to produce clear images on the monitors with minimum ____ pixels",
    "options": [
      "a. 1024 x 768",
      "b. 1200 x 600",
      "c. 864 x 226",
      "d. 100 x 100"
    ],
    "answer": "a. 1024 x 768"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft may be termed as an aircraft not in service, if it is not under surveillance sufficient to detect unauthorized access or if it is parked for a period of more than the ___ hrs",
    "options": [
      "a. 12 hrs",
      "b. 18 hrs",
      "c. 24 hrs",
      "d. one week"
    ],
    "answer": "a. 12 hrs"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is/ are Aircraft Operator's Documents",
    "options": [
      "a. Airway bills/ Consignment notes",
      "b. Passenger Tickets & Boarding passes",
      "c. Airport Security programme",
      "d. Both 'a' & 'b'"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Both 'a' & 'b'"
  },
  {
    "question": "The abbreviation of aircraft operator company mail, shipped within the company's network of stations is",
    "options": [
      "a. AM (Airline Mail)",
      "b. CO-Mail",
      "c. Op-Mail",
      "d. CO-MAT"
    ],
    "answer": "b. CO-Mail"
  },
  {
    "question": "A shipping container having diplomatic immunity from search or seizure",
    "options": [
      "a. Diplomatic Container",
      "b. Embassy Mail Bag",
      "c. Diplomatic Bag/ Pouch",
      "d. Diplomatic Courier"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Diplomatic Bag/ Pouch"
  },
  {
    "question": "The pilot responsible for the operation and safety of the aircraft during flight time is known as __",
    "options": [
      "a. Pilot-in Command",
      "b. Pilot -in Flight",
      "c. Flight Commander",
      "d. Co-Pilot"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Pilot-in Command"
  },
  {
    "question": "The airports are categorized into Normal, Sensitive and Hyper sensitive on the basis of ____",
    "options": [
      "a. Threat Perception in consultation with intelligence agencies",
      "b. No. of flights",
      "c. No. of passengers departing",
      "d. No. of terminals"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Threat Perception in consultation with intelligence agencies"
  },
  {
    "question": "An examination of Implementation of relevant national civil aviation security programme requirement by an airline, airport or other entity involved in security is known as",
    "options": [
      "a. Security Test",
      "b. Security Inspection",
      "c. Security Audit",
      "d. Security Survey"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Security Inspection"
  },
  {
    "question": "A covert or overt trial of an aviation security measure which simulates an attempt to commit an unlawful act is known as",
    "options": [
      "a. Dummy check",
      "b. Security test",
      "c. Security check",
      "d. Decoy check"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Security test"
  },
  {
    "question": "Terminal means the main building or group of buildings where the processing of",
    "options": [
      "a. commercial passengers occurs",
      "b. Parking is done",
      "c. the boarding of aircraft occurs",
      "d. Both 'a' & 'b'"
    ],
    "answer": "a. commercial passengers occurs"
  },
  {
    "question": "___ PSI of pressure can be tolerated by the eardrum",
    "options": [
      "a. 50 PSI",
      "b. 40 PSI",
      "c. 30 PSI",
      "d. 7 PSI"
    ],
    "answer": "d. 7 PSI"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the total no. of ICAO Annexes",
    "options": [
      "a. 15",
      "b. 16",
      "c. 17",
      "d. 18"
    ],
    "answer": "d. 18"
  },
  {
    "question": "LTPE stands for",
    "options": [
      "a. Low Temperature Plastic Explosive",
      "b. Linear Type Plastic Explosive",
      "c. Long Term Plastic Explosive",
      "d. Less Time for Passenger Entry"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Low Temperature Plastic Explosive"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which of the following year Colombo Airport was attacked",
    "options": [
      "a. 2001",
      "b. 2003",
      "c. 1999",
      "d. 2000"
    ],
    "answer": "a. 2001"
  },
  {
    "question": "For a prisoner to be carried on board aircraft, prior permission is required from",
    "options": [
      "a. Prisons",
      "b. BCAS",
      "c. DGCA",
      "d. Concerned Airlines"
    ],
    "answer": "b. BCAS"
  },
  {
    "question": "MLAs of state legislature have free access up to which area of airport",
    "options": [
      "a. Aircraft's",
      "b. Up to Terminal Building",
      "c. All areas",
      "d. Not permitted in the airport without valid AEP"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Not permitted in the airport without valid AEP"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which among the following, is the sensitivity of the EVD",
    "options": [
      "a. Min 5 gm",
      "b. Min 10 gm",
      "c. Min 15 gm",
      "d. Min 2.5 gm"
    ],
    "answer":  "a. Min 5 gm"
  },
  {
    "question": "As per BCAS specification weight of HHMD should not exceed",
    "options": [
      "a. 250 gm",
      "b. 100 gm",
      "c. 200 gm",
      "d. 500 gm"
    ],
    "answer": "a. 250 gm"
  }
]
    },
     {
        set: 17,
        questions:[
  {
    "question": "Chief Justice of India will be checked by using",
    "options": [
      "a. HHMD",
      "b. DFMD",
      "c. Physical check",
      "d. Exempted from Security check"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Exempted from Security check"
  },
  {
    "question": "The ability of X-Ray machine to image thin metal is tested by",
    "options": [
      "a. Single wire resolution test of CTP",
      "b. Thin metal imaging test of CTP",
      "c. OTP",
      "d. Spatial resolution test of CTP"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Thin metal imaging test of CTP"
  },
  {
    "question": "Brass knuckles come under ___ category of prohibited items",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapon",
      "b. Dangerous Article",
      "c. Dangerous Substance",
      "d. Explosive"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Weapon"
  },
  {
    "question": "Screeners may not faced difficulties in screening of",
    "options": [
      "a. Wrapped items",
      "b. Children's toys",
      "c. Canes & Crutches",
      "d. Clothes"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Clothes"
  },
  {
    "question": "X-BIS should be switched on after ensuring ___",
    "options": [
      "a. Bag inside the tunnel",
      "b. obstructed conveyor belt",
      "c. Electric Supply",
      "d. Missed lead curtains"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Electric Supply"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who among the following discovered a new kind of radiation which is called X-Rays, in the year 1885",
    "options": [
      "a. Wilson C Roentgen",
      "b. Robert C Roentgen",
      "c. William C Roentgen",
      "d. George C Roentgen"
    ],
    "answer": "c. William C Roentgen"
  },
  {
    "question": "Runways & Aprons are protected by",
    "options": [
      "a. Not Patrolling",
      "b. Guarding",
      "c. Surveillance",
      "d. Both 'b' & 'c'"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Both 'b' & 'c'"
  },
  {
    "question": "The full form of DFMD is",
    "options": [
      "a. Door Frame Metal Detector",
      "b. Door Form Metal Detector",
      "c. Detect Frame Metal Detector",
      "d. Detect & Frame Metal Detector"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Door Frame Metal Detector"
  },
  {
    "question": "Acceptable height of DFMD as per BCAS specification is",
    "options": [
      "a. 2m",
      "b. 4m",
      "c. 5m",
      "d. 6m"
    ],
    "answer": "a. 2m"
  },
  {
    "question": "The airport security committee should meet every",
    "options": [
      "a. Month",
      "b. Two months",
      "c. Three months",
      "d. Whenever required"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Month"
  },
  {
    "question": "The abbreviation POD stands for",
    "options": [
      "a. Proof of departure",
      "b. Point of detonation",
      "c. Power of detonator",
      "d. Postal order"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Point of detonation"
  },
  {
    "question": "Local rules & regulation of the Airport should be known to",
    "options": [
      "a. All employees working at Airport",
      "b. Those staff having Airside Driving Permit",
      "c. Those having permanent Airport Entry Pass",
      "d. Those having Bonafied ticket"
    ],
    "answer": "a. All employees working at Airport"
  },
  {
    "question": "What pattern should be used for performing bag searches",
    "options": [
      "a. Side to side pattern",
      "b. Clockwise pattern",
      "c. Random pattern",
      "d. Top to bottom pattern"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Top to bottom pattern"
  },
  {
    "question": "What will be the course of action when you notice suspicious sign on a passenger during profiling",
    "options": [
      "a. Notify supervisor",
      "b. Thorough observation",
      "c. Both 'a' & 'b'",
      "d. Arrest passenger"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Both 'a' & 'b'"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which committee recommended for separate organization for security",
    "options": [
      "a. Ramamitran committee",
      "b. B N Kirpal Committee",
      "c. Pandey Committee",
      "d. Cabinet Committee"
    ],
    "answer": "b. B N Kirpal Committee"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a responsibility of CASO",
    "options": [
      "a. Deployment of security staff",
      "b. Convening APSC",
      "c. Conducting mock exercises",
      "d. Chair the BTAC"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Convening APSC"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Annexure contains the SARP on Aviation Security",
    "options": [
      "a. Annex",
      "b. Annex 16",
      "c. Annex 17",
      "d. Annex 18"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Annex 17"
  },
  {
    "question": "Activity where systematic observation is done for categorization of passenger into threatening and non-threatening category is",
    "options": [
      "a. Personating",
      "b. Profiling",
      "c. Counseling",
      "d. Training"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Profiling"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is ARP",
    "options": [
      "a. Reference point of Aerodrome",
      "b. It is brand",
      "c. Both 'a' & 'b'",
      "d. Aircraft Reaching Path"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Reference point of Aerodrome"
  },
  {
    "question": "At screening points how radios and electrical items will be checked",
    "options": [
      "a. Do not ask passenger to operate the item",
      "b. Ask passenger to open the battery compartment",
      "c. Check tightness of seal to see if any screws are removed or paint chipped off",
      "d. Both 'b' & 'c'"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Both 'b' & 'c'"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which is one of the specification of XBIS",
    "options": [
      "a. Speed of the conveyor belt should be 0.18 to 0.3 mtr/sec",
      "b. Convenience to pax",
      "c. Safe for film food and drugs",
      "d. Convenience for staff to check bag"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Speed of the conveyor belt should be 0.18 to 0.3 mtr/sec"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which is the equipment used for screening for Bags?",
    "options": [
      "a. DFMD",
      "b. HHMD",
      "c. XBIS",
      "d. CTP"
    ],
    "answer": "c. XBIS"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the radiation distance from the tunnel",
    "options": [
      "a. 1cm",
      "b. 5 cm",
      "c. 15 cm",
      "d. 25 cm"
    ],
    "answer": "b. 5 cm"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is common for every duty post",
    "options": [
      "a. Barrier",
      "b. DFMD",
      "c. Standing order/SOP",
      "d. HHMD"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Standing order/SOP"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many types of detonators are available",
    "options": [
      "a. 1",
      "b. 2",
      "c. 3",
      "d. 4"
    ],
    "answer": "b. 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many gates are required for better access control",
    "options": [
      "a. As less as possible",
      "b. More gates are required",
      "c. 10",
      "d. 8"
    ],
    "answer": "a. As less as possible"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which year was the first International Convention on aviation held",
    "options": [
      "a. 1937",
      "b. 1944",
      "c. 1947",
      "d. 1934"
    ],
    "answer": "b. 1944"
  },
  {
    "question": "The duty of QRT is ?",
    "options": [
      "a. Anti sabotage check of aircraft",
      "b. To cordon hijacked aircraft",
      "c. Quick response at the time of crisis",
      "d. Both 'b' & 'c'"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Both 'b' & 'c'"
  },
  {
    "question": "When was CISF first inducted at airports?",
    "options": [
      "a. 3rd Feb 2000",
      "b. 31st Dec 2000",
      "c. 10th Mar 2000",
      "d. 3rd Feb 2001"
    ],
    "answer": "a. 3rd Feb 2000"
  },
  {
    "question": "The emergency which is not related to aircraft",
    "options": [
      "a. New born",
      "b. Sabotage",
      "c. Fire in Terminal building",
      "d. Hijacking"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Fire in Terminal building"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which is not the duty of Airlines Security",
    "options": [
      "a. Hand baggage screening",
      "b. Registered baggage screening",
      "c. Surveillance in BMA",
      "d. Reconciliation of baggage"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Hand baggage screening"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which is not used in Security",
    "options": [
      "a. HHMD",
      "b. RT SET",
      "c. CCTV",
      "d. Laptop"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Laptop"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Ambulift",
    "options": [
      "a. A vehicle/ machine to lift pax with reduced mobility into aircraft",
      "b. Machine used to wrap machine",
      "c. Lift for 100 people",
      "d. Machine used to lift cargo"
    ],
    "answer": "a. A vehicle/ machine to lift pax with reduced mobility into aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "Security of Parked Aircraft is done by",
    "options": [
      "a. CISF",
      "b. AIRLINES",
      "c. BCAS",
      "d. AAI"
    ],
    "answer": "a. CISF"
  },
  {
    "question": "There are ___ components of ASG",
    "options": [
      "a. One",
      "b. Three",
      "c. Four",
      "d. Seven"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Three"
  },
  {
    "question": "The authority responsible for regulating Safety aspects of aircrafts in India",
    "options": [
      "a. ICAO",
      "b. Commander of concerned airports",
      "c. BCAS",
      "d. DGCA"
    ],
    "answer": "d. DGCA"
  },
  {
    "question": "As per approved technical specifications, the approx weight of ETD should be",
    "options": [
      "a. 30 kg",
      "b. 25 Kg",
      "c. 40 Kg",
      "d. 20 Kg"
    ],
    "answer": "c. 40 Kg"
  },
  {
    "question": "PTI in aviation security stands for",
    "options": [
      "a. Positive Target Identification",
      "b. Positive Trainee Identification",
      "c. Press Trust of India",
      "d. Passport Tally I-card"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Positive Target Identification"
  },
  {
    "question": "As per approved technical specifications, the approx weight of EVD should be",
    "options": [
      "a. 3 Kg",
      "b. 2Kgs",
      "c. 5 Kg",
      "d. 4 Kg"
    ],
    "answer": "b. 2Kgs"
  },
  {
    "question": "If hijacking takes place in Chennai this will be treated as",
    "options": [
      "a. National Contingency",
      "b. Contingency of local area only",
      "c. It is not a contingency",
      "d. Chennai Airport Contingency only"
    ],
    "answer": "a. National Contingency"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the prescribed position of lights used at perimeter",
    "options": [
      "a. Focusing out",
      "b. Focused at duty points",
      "c. Very dim",
      "d. Focused at gates only"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Focusing out"
  },
  {
    "question": "DFMD works on the principle ___",
    "options": [
      "a. Electro- magnetic Pulse field technology",
      "b. Electric Pulse field technology",
      "c. Magnetic Pulse field technology",
      "d. Infrared Rays"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Electro- magnetic Pulse field technology"
  },
  {
    "question": "Simulation Chamber operates on the principle of activating the explosive device in the suspect object by simulating the",
    "options": [
      "a. Physical Conditions",
      "b. Gaseous conditions",
      "c. Liquid conditions",
      "d. Delayed conditions"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Physical Conditions"
  },
  {
    "question": "Clock is used as switch in which type of mechanism",
    "options": [
      "a. Anti handling",
      "b. Remote Control",
      "c. Ambient",
      "d. Delay mechanism"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Remote Control"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Anti Hijacking Act came into existence in the year",
    "options": [
      "a. 1982",
      "b. 1987",
      "c. 1944",
      "d. 1999"
    ],
    "answer": "a. 1982"
  },
  {
    "question": "Significance of 23.02.1931",
    "options": [
      "a. First hijacking in the history of civil aviation",
      "b. First Sabotage in the history of civil aviation",
      "c. First terrorist attack in the history of civil aviation",
      "d. ICAO came into existence"
    ],
    "answer": "a. First hijacking in the history of civil aviation"
  },
  {
    "question": "ETD works on which principle",
    "options": [
      "a. Ion mobility spectrometry",
      "b. Ion stability spectrometry",
      "c. Gas Chromatography",
      "d. Gas spectrometry"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Ion mobility spectrometry"
  },
  {
    "question": "In an airport Apron area is within",
    "options": [
      "a. T.B",
      "b. Airside",
      "c. ATS",
      "d. Fuel Storage"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Airside"
  },
  {
    "question": "The department who can go for inspection in an aircraft except concern airline",
    "options": [
      "a. CISF",
      "b. Immigration",
      "c. BCAS & DGCA",
      "d. AAI"
    ],
    "answer": "c. BCAS & DGCA"
  },
  {
    "question": "Head of ASG at a particular Airport",
    "options": [
      "a. CASO",
      "b. BCAS",
      "c. COSCA",
      "d. APD"
    ],
    "answer": "a. CASO"
  }
]
    },
     {
        set: 18,
        questions: [
  {
    "question": "Difference between Appropriate authority for aviation security and COSCA is",
    "options": [
      "a. one related to ICAO and another is with MCA",
      "b. Both are same",
      "c. One related to aviation security and another with the aviation safety",
      "d. Totally different"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Both are same"
  },
  {
    "question": "A parked aircraft which is under ____ sufficient to detect unauthorized access",
    "options": [
      "a. observation",
      "b. surveillance",
      "c. recommendation",
      "d. notice"
    ],
    "answer": "b. surveillance"
  },
  {
    "question": "ASG Personnel are authorized to check / frisk",
    "options": [
      "a. Employees who are not entering the operational area",
      "b. Airport employees while leaving the Tarmac area",
      "c. Exempted Category",
      "d. Employees who are approaching towards airport"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Airport employees while leaving the Tarmac area"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ultimate authority for airport entry passes are",
    "options": [
      "a. APSU/ASG",
      "b. BCAS",
      "c. DGCA",
      "d. Airport Operator"
    ],
    "answer": "b. BCAS"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is BWAF required",
    "options": [
      "a. To assess specific and non-specific calls",
      "b. To assess the Caller",
      "c. To maintain perfect data about the caller",
      "d. Formality"
    ],
    "answer": "a. To assess specific and non-specific calls"
  },
  {
    "question": "If a pistol is detected during screening of hand baggage",
    "options": [
      "a. Take action as per local SOP",
      "b. Inform BDDS",
      "c. Inform BCAS",
      "d. Inform Police"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Take action as per local SOP"
  },
  {
    "question": "What will be the course of action when X-BIS does not pass one of the CTP tests",
    "options": [
      "a. Stop the machine",
      "b. Avoid it & work",
      "c. Stop the machine & notify supervisor",
      "d. Notify Supervisor and continue screening"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Stop the machine & notify supervisor"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which is not a duty of BCAS",
    "options": [
      "a. Planning",
      "b. Monitoring",
      "c. Guiding",
      "d. Training"
    ],
    "answer":  "c. Guiding"
  },
  {
    "question": "If a person is denying to be frisked, what is the course of action",
    "options": [
      "a. Allow him to board",
      "b. Apply -No search No fly",
      "c. Use force to search him",
      "d. Frisk as a formality"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Apply -No search No fly"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many International Conventions have been held",
    "options": [
      "a. One",
      "b. Four",
      "c. Five",
      "d. Eight"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Five"
  },
  {
    "question": "Blue color pass holder can enter",
    "options": [
      "a. All areas except SHA",
      "b. All areas",
      "c. Only in operational area",
      "d. Only till check-in area"
    ],
    "answer": "a. All areas except SHA"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is your action if you find Explosive inside the bag while screening",
    "options": [
      "a. Ask the passenger, why is he carrying it",
      "b. Allow the passenger to board",
      "c. Stop the conveyor & inform supervisor",
      "d. Remove the article and leave the passenger"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Stop the conveyor & inform supervisor"
  },
  {
    "question": "Tokyo Convention was held in the year",
    "options": [
      "a. 12.Sep.63",
      "b. 14.Sep.63",
      "c. 23.Sep.71",
      "d. 01.Mär.91"
    ],
    "answer": "b. 14.Sep.63"
  },
  {
    "question": "MEX Convention was held in the year",
    "options": [
      "a. 12.Sep.63",
      "b. 14.Sep.63",
      "c. 23.Sep.71",
      "d. 01.Mär.91"
    ],
    "answer": "d. 01.Mär.91"
  },
  {
    "question": "Hague Convention",
    "options": [
      "a. 12.Sep.63",
      "b. 14.Sep.63",
      "c. 23.Sep.71",
      "d. 16.Dez.70"
    ],
    "answer": "d. 16.Dez.70"
  },
  {
    "question": "There are ____ Annexes to Chicago Convention on International Civil Aviation",
    "options": [
      "a. 17",
      "b. 18",
      "c. 20",
      "d. 25"
    ],
    "answer": "b. 18"
  },
  {
    "question": "The specification for physical characteristics, configuration, material performance, personnel or procedure, the uniform application of which is recognized as desirable for the safety or regularity of international air navigation and to which Contracting states will conform in accordance with the convention are",
    "options": [
      "a. SARP",
      "b. Recommended Practices",
      "c. Standard Practices",
      "d. Mandatory Practices"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Recommended Practices"
  },
  {
    "question": "Standard Practices are the specification for physical characteristics, configuration, material performance, personnel or procedure, the uniform application of which is recognized as ___ for the safety or regularity of international air navigation and to which Contracting States will conform in accordance with the Convention",
    "options": [
      "a. Desirable",
      "b. Mandatory",
      "c. Necessary",
      "d. Not required"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Necessary"
  },
  {
    "question": "European Civil Aviation Conference (ECAC) was founded in the year",
    "options": [
      "a. 1944",
      "b. 1955",
      "c. 1963",
      "d. 1970"
    ],
    "answer": "b. 1955"
  },
  {
    "question": "IATA is the association of",
    "options": [
      "a. Airport Operators",
      "b. Airlines",
      "c. An agency of ICAO",
      "d. Part of DGCA"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Airlines"
  },
  {
    "question": "Airport Council International (ACI) is the association of",
    "options": [
      "a. Airports",
      "b. Airlines",
      "c. An agency of ICAO",
      "d. Part of DGCA"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Airports"
  },
  {
    "question": "Measures adopted by a State to safeguard international civil aviation against Acts of Unlawful Interference are",
    "options": [
      "a. National Civil Aviation Security programme",
      "b. Standard Operating Procedures (SOP)",
      "c. Airport Security programme",
      "d. Contingency Plan"
    ],
    "answer": "a. National Civil Aviation Security programme"
  },
  {
    "question": "Individual post orders that state exactly how security measures should be implemented",
    "options": [
      "a. National Civil Aviation Security programme",
      "b. Standard Operating Procedures (SOP)",
      "c. Airport Security programme",
      "d. Contingency Plan"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Standard Operating Procedures (SOP)"
  },
  {
    "question": "To ensure that aviation security measures and responsibilities are clearly defined and understood by those who need to implement them. It should clarify and detail all measures that are required to be implemented at the airport to meet the requirements of the National Civil Aviation Security Programme is the Primary Objective of",
    "options": [
      "a. National Civil Aviation Security programme",
      "b. Standard Operating Procedures (SOP)",
      "c. Airport Security programme",
      "d. Contingency Plan"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Airport Security programme"
  },
  {
    "question": "Basic Concept of Security is deter, delay, detect, respond",
    "options": [
      "a. deter, delay, detect, attack",
      "b. differ, delay, detect, respond",
      "c. deter, delay, detect, respond",
      "d. deter, speed, detect, respond"
    ],
    "answer": "c. deter, delay, detect, respond"
  },
  {
    "question": "Passenger Screening is mainly needed :",
    "options": [
      "a. to ensure that no unauthorized person passes the land side/ airside barrier",
      "b. to ensure that no restricted articles are carried past the search point",
      "c. to ensure that passengers are not allowed on the aircraft unless their baggage has been checked",
      "d. to ensure that passenger have valid ticket"
    ],
    "answer": "b. to ensure that no restricted articles are carried past the search point"
  },
  {
    "question": "Passengers who refused to be physically searched are",
    "options": [
      "a. within their rights but must not be allowed to pass the search point",
      "b. must be physically restrained by the searcher until the police arrive",
      "c. must be searched very carefully with the hand held metal detector",
      "d. It depend on you to search or not"
    ],
    "answer": "a. within their rights but must not be allowed to pass the search point"
  },
  {
    "question": "A passenger is found to have a 1 litre bottle of soda. The bottle is half full. Do you:",
    "options": [
      "a. Take no special action",
      "b. Allow the passenger tp proceed after you see them tasting the liquid",
      "c. Confiscate the item or instruct the passengers that the bottle must be placed in hold baggage due to restrictions on the amount of liquids and gels that passengers can carry onto the aircraft.",
      "d. Handover him to police immediately"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Confiscate the item or instruct the passengers that the bottle must be placed in hold baggage due to restrictions on the amount of liquids and gels that passengers can carry onto the aircraft."
  },
  {
    "question": "Airport staff members who can show that they need to pass through the passenger screening point in performance of their duties",
    "options": [
      "a. Do not need to submit to a physical search",
      "b. Do not need to pass through the walk through metal detector",
      "c. Have to submit to the same procedure as passengers",
      "d. Not necessary to display AEP"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Have to submit to the same procedure as passengers"
  },
  {
    "question": "What level of search will you normally be carrying out in the passenger search area",
    "options": [
      "a. Levels 1, 2 & 3",
      "b. Level 1 only",
      "c. Level 1 & 2",
      "d. No level"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Levels 1, 2 & 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Diplomatic pouches are exempted from manual search according to ___ Paragraph 3 of the Vienna Convention on Diplomatic Relations (18 Apr 1961)",
    "options": [
      "a. Article 17",
      "b. Article 18",
      "c. Article 27",
      "d. Article 11"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Article 27"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is NOT TRUE when conducting search of the baggage",
    "options": [
      "a. Start the search with the bag in front of you",
      "b. During the search the bag must remain in the view of the passenger",
      "c. Do not ask the passenger for permission to search the bag",
      "d. Check the outside appearance and construction of the bag for signs of interference or tampering that might indicate the presence of an IED"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Do not ask the passenger for permission to search the bag"
  },
  {
    "question": "There are ___ sweeps while searching a room for suspicious devices",
    "options": [
      "a. 2",
      "b. 3",
      "c. 4",
      "d. 5"
    ],
    "answer": "b. 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "There are ___ levels of search while conducting search of people",
    "options": [
      "a. 1",
      "b. No level",
      "c. 3",
      "d. 4"
    ],
    "answer": "c. 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Baggage which is accepted for carriage in the hold of an aircraft and which is checked in by the passenger who is on board",
    "options": [
      "a. Accompanied hold baggage",
      "b. Hold baggage",
      "c. Registered baggage",
      "d. Cabin baggage"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Registered baggage"
  },
  {
    "question": "An inspection of the interior of an aircraft to which passengers may have had access and an inspection of the hold for the purposes of discovering suspicious objects, weapons, explosives or other dangerous devices, articles and substances",
    "options": [
      "a. Aircraft security search",
      "b. Aircraft security check",
      "c. Aircraft anti-sabotage check",
      "d. Aircraft stand"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Aircraft anti-sabotage check"
  },
  {
    "question": "Any area in a Contracting state which is open for commercial aircraft operations",
    "options": [
      "a. Airport",
      "b. Aircraft stand",
      "c. Airside",
      "d. Movement area"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Airport"
  },
  {
    "question": "A building through which cargo passes between air and ground transport and in which processing facilities are located, or in which cargo is stored pending transfer to air or ground transport",
    "options": [
      "a. Cargo building",
      "b. Catering stores",
      "c. Catering supplies",
      "d. Catering building"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Cargo building"
  },
  {
    "question": "Permissible size of hand baggage is",
    "options": [
      "a. 120 cm",
      "b. 115 cm",
      "c. 200 cm",
      "d. 250 cm"
    ],
    "answer": "b. 115 cm"
  },
  {
    "question": "Guarding of deportee/ inadmissible pax in refusal room is the responsibilty of",
    "options": [
      "a. ASG",
      "b. Airlines",
      "c. Airport Operator",
      "d. Local Police"
    ],
    "answer": "a. ASG"
  },
  {
    "question": "A communicated threat, ____ or otherwise, which suggests, or infers, whether true or false that the safety of an aircraft in flight or on ground, or any person may be in danger from any explosive or other otem or device",
    "options": [
      "a. Enormous",
      "b. Synonymous",
      "c. Anonymous",
      "d. Hoax"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Anonymous"
  },
  {
    "question": "The relevant document to be checked at the time of accepting a weapon in X-BIS from a bonafied staff on duty is",
    "options": [
      "a. Duty Slip",
      "b. Gate Pass",
      "c. Travel Document",
      "d. Driving license"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Duty Slip"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is your main responsibility as an X-Ray Officer/ Screener",
    "options": [
      "a. To count the no. of person going through the check point",
      "b. To prevent explosives of dangerous weapons from onto an aircraft",
      "c. To guess the contents of carry on bags",
      "d. To check pax ticket"
    ],
    "answer": "b. To prevent explosives of dangerous weapons from onto an aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "Uranium is a ___ as per catergorization of prohibited items",
    "options": [
      "a. Dangerous Substance",
      "b. Dangerous Article",
      "c. Explosive",
      "d. Weapon"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Dangerous Substance"
  },
  {
    "question": "Security of Cargo is related to",
    "options": [
      "a. Regulated agent",
      "b. Airlines & Airport Operator",
      "c. APSU",
      "d. Both a & b"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Both a & b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a weapon",
    "options": [
      "a. Grenade",
      "b. Mace",
      "c. TNT",
      "d. Hammer"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Mace"
  },
  {
    "question": "Maximum speed of driving vehicle in airport premises is",
    "options": [
      "a. 30 KMPH",
      "b. 25 KMPH",
      "c. 50 KMPH",
      "d. 15 KMPH"
    ],
    "answer": "b. 25 KMPH"
  },
  {
    "question": "____ is not a method of Screening a passenger's bag",
    "options": [
      "a. X-Ray",
      "b. Physical Check",
      "c. Explosive Detector",
      "d. Simulation Chamber"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Simulation Chamber"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following should be practiced by a security person",
    "options": [
      "a. Being too familiar with staff",
      "b. Effective permit control",
      "c. Both a & c",
      "d. To let by pass Access Control"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Effective permit control"
  },
  {
    "question": "Aircraft search at Transit station should be carried out",
    "options": [
      "a. Before Identification of cabin baggage",
      "b. Before passenger disembark",
      "c. After identification of cabin baggage",
      "d. After passenger embark"
    ],
    "answer": "c. After identification of cabin baggage"
  }
]
    },
     {
        set: 19,
        questions: [
  {
    "question": "Responsibility of searching the interior of the aircraft is of",
    "options": [
      "a. Airport Security",
      "b. Customer Service staff",
      "c. Trained Airline Security & Engineering staff",
      "d. ASG"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Trained Airline Security & Engineering staff"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one is not a method of concealment of an explosive",
    "options": [
      "a. Trafficking",
      "b. Disguised",
      "c. Dismantled",
      "d. Camouflaged"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Trafficking"
  },
  {
    "question": "Starter sockets, refuelling wells and battery access hatches of an aircraft shall be opened and searched as part of",
    "options": [
      "a. Anti hijacking checks of aircraft",
      "b. Anti Sabotage checks of aircraft",
      "c. Anti terrorist checks of aircraft",
      "d. Anti theft measures"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Anti Sabotage checks of aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "In an emergency situation the right way to pass the runway is",
    "options": [
      "a. Look right and left see everything is clear and then cross",
      "b. Use a vehicle hazard warning light to inform captain while crossing",
      "c. Obtain clearance from ATC before crossing",
      "d. Obtain permission from ASG"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Obtain clearance from ATC before crossing"
  },
  {
    "question": "In case of Non Specific call",
    "options": [
      "a. Aircraft to be checked by BDDS",
      "b. Aircraft to be checked by dog squad",
      "c. Aircraft to be checked by airlines security, airlines engineer",
      "d. Aircraft to be checked by CISF, BDDS and airline security"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Aircraft to be checked by airlines security, airlines engineer"
  },
  {
    "question": "PLX is a _____",
    "options": [
      "a. Explosive Detector",
      "b. Explosive",
      "c. IED",
      "d. Dangerous Article"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Explosive"
  },
  {
    "question": "VDU is a component of ____",
    "options": [
      "a. HHMD",
      "b. DFMD",
      "c. X-BIS",
      "d. ETD"
    ],
    "answer":  "b. DFMD"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are MRTDs",
    "options": [
      "a. Machine Readable Travel Documents",
      "b. Memory Readable Text Documents",
      "c. Memory Reset Text Device",
      "d. Machine Reset Text Device"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Machine Readable Travel Documents"
  },
  {
    "question": "The baggage are categorized in which category during screening",
    "options": [
      "a. Safe",
      "b. Doubtful",
      "c. Threat",
      "d. Any of these"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Any of these"
  },
  {
    "question": "STPs are prepared by",
    "options": [
      "a. ICAO",
      "b. IATA",
      "c. ACI",
      "d. BCAS"
    ],
    "answer": "a. ICAO"
  },
  {
    "question": "The magnification of X-BIS is comparatively high if the generator is located at ___ in X-BIS",
    "options": [
      "a. Top",
      "b. Bottom",
      "c. Side",
      "d. Diagonal"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Bottom"
  },
  {
    "question": "___ type of IED is initiated by the victim",
    "options": [
      "a. IED with ambient mechanism",
      "b. IED with anti handling mechanism",
      "c. IED with Remote Controller mechanism",
      "d. IED with delay mechanism"
    ],
    "answer":  "c. IED with Remote Controller mechanism"
  },
  {
    "question": "Nationality Registration of Indian Aircrafts are",
    "options": [
      "a. VT",
      "b. AP",
      "c. VJ",
      "d. VK"
    ],
    "answer": "a. VT"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is PPP model of Airport Development",
    "options": [
      "a. Public Private Partnership",
      "b. Public Private Policy",
      "c. Public Private Procedure",
      "d. Private Procedure for Public"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Public Private Partnership"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a Civil Enclave in India",
    "options": [
      "a. Goa",
      "b. Bhuj",
      "c. Pune",
      "d. Delhi"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Delhi"
  },
  {
    "question": "To whom does the Pilot gives first information about any crisis",
    "options": [
      "a. AC",
      "b. ATC",
      "c. CC",
      "d. CCS"
    ],
    "answer": "c. CC"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is an example of explosive",
    "options": [
      "a. Detonator",
      "b. Tear Gas",
      "c. Rifles",
      "d. Acids"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Detonator"
  },
  {
    "question": "Nun-chucks falls under which category",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapon",
      "b. Dangerous Substances",
      "c. Dangerous Article",
      "d. Explosives"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Weapon"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which among the following Airports is a Greenfield Airport",
    "options": [
      "a. Hyderabad",
      "b. Mumbai",
      "c. Bengaluru",
      "d. Both 'a' & 'c'"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Both 'a' & 'c'"
  },
  {
    "question": "The primary responsibility for movement of patient on a wheel chair is with",
    "options": [
      "a. ASG",
      "b. Airline Operator",
      "c. Airport Operator",
      "d. Relatives or Dependents of the passenger"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Airline Operator"
  },
  {
    "question": "A copy of cancelled ____ of deceased person is required in case of carriage of dead body by air if it comes from abroad",
    "options": [
      "a. Ticket",
      "b. VISA",
      "c. Passport",
      "d. Boarding pass"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Passport"
  },
  {
    "question": "Actual flight condition are made in",
    "options": [
      "a. Cooling pit",
      "b. Simulation chamber",
      "c. ETD",
      "d. Bomb blanket"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Simulation chamber"
  },
  {
    "question": "Security Control of carriage of dead bodies into aircraft is the responsibilty of",
    "options": [
      "a. ASG",
      "b. Airlines Security",
      "c. Airport Operator",
      "d. BCAS"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Airlines Security"
  },
  {
    "question": "Standalone XBIS commonly used at airports for screeening of hand baggage works on the principle of",
    "options": [
      "a. Ion mobility spectrometry",
      "b. Gas Chromatography",
      "c. Multi Energy Technology",
      "d. Back scatter technology"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Multi Energy Technology"
  },
  {
    "question": "Bomb threat comes under",
    "options": [
      "a. Hijacking",
      "b. Sabotage",
      "c. Pilferage",
      "d. Petty crime"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Sabotage"
  },
  {
    "question": "In line X-RAY Baggage System has a facility to _____",
    "options": [
      "a. Automatically screen and segregate hold baggage at different levels",
      "b. Automatically screen but cannot segregate hold baggage",
      "c. Cannot Automatically screen or segregate",
      "d. Automatically segregate but cannot screen hold baggage"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Automatically screen and segregate hold baggage at different levels"
  },
  {
    "question": "Air India (AI 182) Kanishka tragedy happened over ______ ocean",
    "options": [
      "a. Indian Ocean",
      "b. Pacific Ocean",
      "c. Atlantic Ocean",
      "d. Artic Ocean"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Atlantic Ocean"
  },
  {
    "question": "A pax permitted to carry more than prescribed number of ammunition in the hold baggage with the permission of",
    "options": [
      "a. Airline Operator",
      "b. COSCA",
      "c. DGCA",
      "d. CASO"
    ],
    "answer": "c. DGCA"
  },
  {
    "question": "TATP is an example of",
    "options": [
      "a. Weapon",
      "b. Dangerous Article",
      "c. Liquid explosives",
      "d. Dangerous substances"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Liquid explosives"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pyrotechnique material and Propellants are also often known as ________",
    "options": [
      "a. High Explosive",
      "b. Low Explosive",
      "c. Medium Explosive",
      "d. Incendiary Device"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Low Explosive"
  },
  {
    "question": "An operation whereby shipments tendered by one or more shippers are transported as the baggage of the courier passenger on board a scheduled airline service under normal passenger hold baggage documentation.",
    "options": [
      "a. General Cargo",
      "b. Courier Service",
      "c. Mail",
      "d. Company stores"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Courier Service"
  },
  {
    "question": "The efficient management of a necessary control process, with the objective to expedite clearance of persons or goods and prevent unnecessary operational delays",
    "options": [
      "a. Facilitation",
      "b. Security check",
      "c. Passenger reconciliation",
      "d. Check in"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Facilitation"
  },
  {
    "question": "Measures to control the illicit movement of narcotics and psychotropic substances by air are known as ___________",
    "options": [
      "a. Narcotics Control",
      "b. Pre embarkation checks",
      "c. Anti sabotage check",
      "d. Security checks"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Narcotics Control"
  },
  {
    "question": "A passenger or cargo transport link terminal at an urban population centre at which processing facilities are provided",
    "options": [
      "a. Terminal building",
      "b. Post office",
      "c. Off Airport Processing Facilities",
      "d. Cargo Warehouse"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Off Airport Processing Facilities"
  },
  {
    "question": "A general description applied to all hand held fire arms.",
    "options": [
      "a. Small Arm",
      "b. Weapon",
      "c. Pistol",
      "d. Dangerous substances"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Small Arm"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following battery can be used for letter bomb",
    "options": [
      "a. 6V",
      "b. 9V",
      "c. Polaroid battery",
      "d. Pencil cells"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Polaroid battery"
  },
  {
    "question": "Escorting VVIP at airport is the responsibility of",
    "options": [
      "a. ASG",
      "b. Airlines",
      "c. Airport Operator",
      "d. Local Police"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Airlines"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the response time of fire fighting services in case of any fire emergency of the aircraft",
    "options": [
      "a. 2-3 minutes",
      "b. 10 minutes",
      "c. Can take their own time",
      "d. 5 minutes"
    ],
    "answer": "a. 2-3 minutes"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the identification no. of electric detonator",
    "options": [
      "a. No. 28",
      "b. No.30",
      "c. No.32",
      "d. No. 33"
    ],
    "answer": "d. No. 33"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sensitivity & Specificity is the term associated with",
    "options": [
      "a. XBIS",
      "b. HHMD",
      "c. DFMD",
      "d. ETD/EVD"
    ],
    "answer": "d. ETD/EVD"
  },
  {
    "question": "International Explosives Technical Commission (IETC) is the outcome of",
    "options": [
      "a. Montreal Convention 1988",
      "b. Montreal Protocol 1991",
      "c. Hague Convention 1970",
      "d. Tokyo Convention 1963"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Montreal Protocol 1991"
  },
  {
    "question": "DMNB is a compound used for",
    "options": [
      "a. Marking and detection of explosives",
      "b. Add smell to an explosive",
      "c. Add color to the explosive",
      "d. Giving high effect for explosion"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Marking and detection of explosives"
  },
  {
    "question": "De icing is a responsibility of",
    "options": [
      "a. Airport Operator",
      "b. Airlines Operator",
      "c. Airport Security Group",
      "d. Local Police"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Airport Operator"
  },
  {
    "question": "A formal evaluation and confirmation by or on behalf of the appropriate authority for aviation security that a person possesses the necessary competencies to perform assigned functions to an acceptable level as defined by the appropriate authority, is termed as:",
    "options": [
      "a. Certification",
      "b. Vetting",
      "c. Assessment",
      "d. Examination"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Certification"
  },
  {
    "question": "Co-mat, is a term which stands for:-",
    "options": [
      "a. aircraft operator company materials, shipped within the company's network of stations",
      "b. aircraft operator company mail, shipped within the company's network of stations",
      "c. Meteorological information input for an aircraft",
      "d. None"
    ],
    "answer": "a. aircraft operator company materials, shipped within the company's network of stations"
  },
  {
    "question": "At an airport, Airside vehicle access control point are manned by",
    "options": [
      "a. Airport Operator",
      "b. ASG/APSU",
      "c. Immigration/ Custom",
      "d. Local Police"
    ],
    "answer": "b. ASG/APSU"
  },
  {
    "question": "Orange(C ) passes are issued to the",
    "options": [
      "a. Concessionaires",
      "b. Crew members",
      "c. Courier Service",
      "d. Customs staff"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Crew members"
  },
  {
    "question": "Security procedure of Diplomatic bags doesn't include",
    "options": [
      "a. Prior permission from BCAS",
      "b. Diplomatic bag will not be opened in any circumstances",
      "c. In case of doubt protocol division of MEA to be contacted",
      "d. Will not be screened if going as hand bag"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Prior permission from BCAS"
  },
  {
    "question": "Regulated Agent is involved in the following function",
    "options": [
      "a. Ticketing of the passengers",
      "b. Provides security control for Cargo which is accepted and required by appropriate authority",
      "c. Conducts business with the aircraft operator for freight forwarding",
      "d. Both 'b' & 'c'"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Both 'b' & 'c'"
  },
  {
    "question": "Carriage of persons suffering from mental disorders comes under which rule",
    "options": [
      "a. 24A",
      "b. 25",
      "c. 19",
      "d. 78"
    ],
    "answer": "a. 24A"
  }
]
    },
     {
        set: 20,
        questions:[
  {
    "question": "PEK stands for",
    "options": [
      "a. Plastic Explosive Kirkee",
      "b. Power Electrode Kirkee",
      "c. Both a & b",
      "d. Plastic Explosive Ketone"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Plastic Explosive Kirkee"
  },
  {
    "question": "Nitroglycerine is ____ explosive",
    "options": [
      "a. Liquid",
      "b. Plastic",
      "c. Solid",
      "d. Not an explosive"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Liquid"
  },
  {
    "question": "The plan adopted at Srinagar airport is",
    "options": [
      "a. Boarding gate plan",
      "b. Concourse plan",
      "c. Holding area plan",
      "d. Holding and Concourse plan"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Holding and Concourse plan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Maximum two searchers per room of ____ size should be deployed for search of a building",
    "options": [
      "a. up to 350 square feet",
      "b. up to 150 square feet",
      "c. up to 550 square feet",
      "d. up to 250 square feet"
    ],
    "answer": "d. up to 250 square feet"
  },
  {
    "question": "The plan setting forth the procedures for coordinating the response of different aerodrome agencies (or services) and of hose agencies in the surrounding commuinity that could be of assistace in responding to the emergency, is called as",
    "options": [
      "a. Contingency Plan",
      "b. Emergency Plan",
      "c. SOP",
      "d. Crisis Management Plan"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Emergency Plan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Direct transit area is a specila area approved by the public authorities concerned and under their direct supervision or control, where passengers can stay during transit or transfer without applying for entry to the state. It is established in:",
    "options": [
      "a. An international airport",
      "b. A domestic Airport",
      "c. A big Airport",
      "d. Joint Venture Airport"
    ],
    "answer": "a. An international airport"
  },
  {
    "question": "Control Panel and cross piece are found in",
    "options": [
      "a. DFMD",
      "b. HHMD",
      "c. X-BIS",
      "d. ETD/EVD"
    ],
    "answer": "a. DFMD"
  },
  {
    "question": "Dangerous Goods register at X-BIS will contain",
    "options": [
      "a. Dangerous goods detected",
      "b. Make of machine",
      "c. Date of installation",
      "d. Visit by supervisor"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Dangerous goods detected"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which is the example of medical emergency",
    "options": [
      "a. Sudden death",
      "b. Natural disaster",
      "c. Bomb threat",
      "d. Hijacking"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Sudden death"
  },
  {
    "question": "NCASQCP deals with",
    "options": [
      "a. Security",
      "b. Training",
      "c. Safety",
      "d. Passengers"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Security"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the X-Ray machine ' Lead' is primarily used to",
    "options": [
      "a. Absorb radiation",
      "b. Detect arms and ammunition",
      "c. Detect explosives",
      "d. Increase the 'Through Put'"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Absorb radiation"
  },
  {
    "question": "Profiling can be done on ____ things",
    "options": [
      "a. One",
      "b. Three",
      "c. Six",
      "d. Seven"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Three"
  },
  {
    "question": "Checked in passenger not reported to board would be",
    "options": [
      "a. Canceled passenger",
      "b. Deportee",
      "c. Gate No Show",
      "d. Transit Passenger"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Gate No Show"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one is a standard Practice",
    "options": [
      "a. PEC",
      "b. SLPC",
      "c. ABC",
      "d. SSLC"
    ],
    "answer": "a. PEC"
  },
  {
    "question": "All service panels of the X-Ray BIS machines are to be opened before switching on for air circulation of machine",
    "options": [
      "a. WAHR",
      "b. FALSCH",
      "c. Can't Say",
      "d. None"
    ],
    "answer": "b. FALSCH"
  },
  {
    "question": "Multi energy test discriminates the material as per their",
    "options": [
      "a. Atomic number",
      "b. Atomic weight",
      "c. Molecular weight",
      "d. Density"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Atomic number"
  },
  {
    "question": "In thin metal imaging test ___ mm strip should be seen",
    "options": [
      "a. 0.1",
      "b. 0.05",
      "c. 0.01",
      "d. 1"
    ],
    "answer": "a. 0.1"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one is not a radio discipline",
    "options": [
      "a. Think before you speak",
      "b. Listen before you transmit",
      "c. Using slang",
      "d. Keep it short and concise"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Using slang"
  },
  {
    "question": "Provision and maintainance of Perimeter road and fencing is the responsibility of",
    "options": [
      "a. Aircraft Operator",
      "b. Aviation Security Group",
      "c. Airport Operator",
      "d. ATC"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Airport Operator"
  },
  {
    "question": "In US Attack two aircraft crashed over the twin towers, one in Pennsylvania where did the fourth aircraft crashed?",
    "options": [
      "a. Into the White House",
      "b. Into the Pentagon",
      "c. Into the Statue of Liberty",
      "d. Into the World Trade Center"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Into the Pentagon"
  },
  {
    "question": "Most of the hijackings in India were",
    "options": [
      "a. For Political reasons",
      "b. For Ransom",
      "c. Done by Mentally deranged person",
      "d. Done to seek refugee in India"
    ],
    "answer": "a. For Political reasons"
  },
  {
    "question": "In inline X-ray machine Level 2 comprises of",
    "options": [
      "a. Screenwriters",
      "b. Standalone X-ray machine",
      "c. High speed Multi view X-ray machine",
      "d. Explosive detectors"
    ],
    "answer":"a. Screenwriters"
  },
  {
    "question": "The aim of segregating 10% of screened baggage should be at randomly marked for physical search",
    "options": [
      "a. To keep physical searcher alert",
      "b. It acts as deterrent",
      "c. Because BCAS circular says so",
      "d. Searcher gets some practice"
    ],
    "answer": "b. It acts as deterrent"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is exempted from Pre-embarkation security check",
    "options": [
      "a. Former Prime Ministers",
      "b. Wife of Prime Ministers",
      "c. Cabinet Secretary",
      "d. Judges of High Court"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Cabinet Secretary"
  },
  {
    "question": "Any vehicle used to convey passengers between aircraft and passengers terminal buiding",
    "options": [
      "a. Push back trolley",
      "b. High lift vehicle",
      "c. Apron passenger vehicle",
      "d. Baggage container"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Push back trolley"
  },
  {
    "question": "A receptacle in which baggage is loaded in for conveyance in aircraft",
    "options": [
      "a. Cargo hold",
      "b. Simulation Chamber",
      "c. Aircraft",
      "d. Baggage Container"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Baggage Container"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the hand bag passenger can carry any liquid item in volume not more than",
    "options": [
      "a. 10 ml",
      "b. 100 ml",
      "c. 1000 ml",
      "d. 10000 ml"
    ],
    "answer": "b. 100 ml"
  },
  {
    "question": "For searches to be effective they should be conducted",
    "options": [
      "a. Systematically",
      "b. Regularly",
      "c. Frequently",
      "d. Daily"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Systematically"
  },
  {
    "question": "For effective search of an area to be conducted by",
    "options": [
      "a. Staff unfamiliar to area",
      "b. Police",
      "c. ASG",
      "d. Staff familiar to area"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Staff familiar to area"
  },
  {
    "question": "Area search plan to be prpared",
    "options": [
      "a. On the spot",
      "b. In Advance",
      "c. Upon receipt of threat",
      "d. Before area being searched"
    ],
    "answer": "b. In Advance"
  },
  {
    "question": "Search plans to be used by",
    "options": [
      "a. Any Staff",
      "b. Airport Security Staff",
      "c. Staff trained to use",
      "d. Ground Staff"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Staff trained to use"
  },
  {
    "question": "Use of_______ communication is useful during search for co-ordination",
    "options": [
      "a. Mobile",
      "b. Landside Telephone",
      "c. Email",
      "d. Hand Held(RT)"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Hand Held(RT)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Radios should not be used to transmit within _____ of suspect device",
    "options": [
      "a. 25 Meters",
      "b. 15 Meters",
      "c. 15 Feet",
      "d. 25 Feet"
    ],
    "answer": "a. 25 Meters"
  },
  {
    "question": "Before starting the search of an area",
    "options": [
      "a. Strict access control to be maintained",
      "b. Guarding",
      "c. Access control require after search",
      "d. Access control not required before"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Strict access control to be maintained"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the warning received indicated a possible detonation time then best and safest option would be",
    "options": [
      "a. Use more person to search area",
      "b. Take help form trained Airline Security",
      "c. Evacuate all personnel to safe area",
      "d. Lock the area after search"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Evacuate all personnel to safe area"
  },
  {
    "question": "Decentralization of pax usually takes place in",
    "options": [
      "a. Holding Area",
      "b. Pier",
      "c. Departures Gates",
      "d. Boarding Gates"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Boarding Gates"
  },
  {
    "question": "Semi- Centralization of pax usually takes place in",
    "options": [
      "a. At Boarding Gate",
      "b. After duty free Area",
      "c. At PEC",
      "d. Before Duty free area"
    ],
    "answer": "b. After duty free Area"
  },
  {
    "question": "Centralization of pax usually takes place in",
    "options": [
      "a. Before Duty free area",
      "b. At Pier",
      "c. At Boarding Gate",
      "d. Before PEC"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Before Duty free area"
  },
  {
    "question": "Screening of pax is carried out immediately before boarding in",
    "options": [
      "a. Holding Area Plan",
      "b. Boarding Gate Plan",
      "c. Concourse Plan",
      "d. SHA Plan"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Boarding Gate Plan"
  },
  {
    "question": "At boarding gate plan screening points are located at",
    "options": [
      "a. Before entry in to SHA",
      "b. At Jet Way",
      "c. At Aircraft stepladder",
      "d. Before entry in terminal building"
    ],
    "answer": "b. At Jet Way"
  },
  {
    "question": "Screening of pax is carried out at the entrance in which of the following Sterile Holding Area concept",
    "options": [
      "a. Concourse concept",
      "b. Holding Area concept",
      "c. Centralized Plan",
      "d. Boarding Gate concept"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Holding Area concept"
  },
  {
    "question": "Searcher shoud be brief to",
    "options": [
      "a. Handle suspicious object",
      "b. If suspicious object found discontinue the search",
      "c. Look for out of place objects",
      "d. Use RT to communicate from less than 25 meters distance from object"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Look for out of place objects"
  },
  {
    "question": "Search plan should be readily available at",
    "options": [
      "a. At the time of search",
      "b. Only in case of search during threat",
      "c. At all times",
      "d. With In-Charge"
    ],
    "answer": "c. At all times"
  },
  {
    "question": "How mant types of search procedures have been identified for Area Search",
    "options": [
      "a. 4",
      "b. 2",
      "c. 5",
      "d. 3"
    ],
    "answer": "d. 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Dividing terminal building into different sectors is first step for",
    "options": [
      "a. Segregating Pax",
      "b. Avoiding mixture of screened and unscreened pax",
      "c. Preparing Search Plan",
      "d. It is easy for housekeeping"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Preparing Search Plan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Search team for 250 sq feet area should not consist more than",
    "options": [
      "a. Three- man",
      "b. Five-man",
      "c. Two-man",
      "d. One-man"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Two-man"
  },
  {
    "question": "Areas to which access is normally controlled may be search",
    "options": [
      "a. On priority basis",
      "b. Last",
      "c. Immediately after search begins",
      "d. First"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Last"
  },
  {
    "question": "While screening an Area. If the item detected is weapon",
    "options": [
      "a. Mark the location and continue search",
      "b. Do not Touch",
      "c. Inform BDDS",
      "d. Immediately safeguard the weapon"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Immediately safeguard the weapon"
  },
  {
    "question": "While screening an Area. If the item detected is an Explosive Device",
    "options": [
      "a. Immediately safeguard the device",
      "b. Mark the location and notify search co-ordinator",
      "c. Take the device at safe place",
      "d. Throw water to defuse the device"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Mark the location and notify search co-ordinator"
  },
  {
    "question": "Deployment of security personnel to static posts may contribute to the",
    "options": [
      "a. Detection process",
      "b. Security Control",
      "c. Respond to attack",
      "d. Prevent Theft"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Detection process"
  }
]
    },
  
];